Chapter 1: Solo Adventures

Disclaimers: This story is a Dungeons and Dragons/Harry Potter crossover, and primarily aimed at readers who are fans of both. That said, people only vaguely familiar with either Harry Potter or D&D will still likely get most of the enjoyment this story has to offer. For those who don't know much about either, reading a quick plot summary of Harry Potter and the Philospher's Stone (say, on Wikipedia) and skimming the article on D&D will likely suffice. Anyone still confused can search d20srd (.org), a wonderful website with the entirety of the D&D 3.5 rules available for free. Players of AD&D, D&D 3.0, 4th edition, Pathfinder, and probably other RPGs will probably be just fine. You can check my Author's Page for a link to Milo's character sheet, more details, and a link to Semiautomagic, an RPG I'm working on, currently available as a free beta.

For D&D buffs: this fic uses a few minor house rules which I've played with so long I didn't even realize they weren't canon. We're using 3.0's XP system instead of 3.5's (XP divides a little differently) and Wizards are able to swap out their Scribe Scroll bonus feat at 1st level for alternate class features (in this case, Spontaneous Divination) as if they were the 5th, 10th, 15th, or 20th-level bonus feats. Also, magic items like Bags of Holding track only weight for carrying capacity, not volume. I rolled Milo's stats using the usual system (4d6, drop the lowest) and roll his hit dice every level, as well as most of the other dice in combats and things.

Anyways, on with the story! If you like it, review it!

o—o—o—o

—Thud—

Milo hit the ground—hard. There was a brief moment of silence before he heard the sound of chairs being slid back on a stone floor and people rising to their feet.

He wasn't alone.

Milo quickly glanced around, taking in the unfamiliar surroundings. He was in some sort of dining room, lying face-up on a hardwood table. The room was richly appointed, and Milo was keenly aware of their solid brass candlesticks, as one was currently poking him most uncomfortably in the lower back. Most notable, however, were the half-dozen figures sitting around him. They were evil—like, really, obviously evil. Black robes. Masks. Hells, there was even a chandelier.

It didn't take Milo long to realize he should be putting his Improved Initiative to good use. As the cultist—these guys had to be in some sort of cult—who was sitting at the head of the table reached up the sleeve of his robe for a wand, Milo unleashed sparkly arcane fury.

"Avada Kedavr—Aaaah!" the cultist was cut off.

"Glitterdust!" A cloud of blindingly bright, glowing golden particles exploded out of Milo's outspread hands, covering the cultists and their furniture. The cultists clutched at their masks, temporarily blinded by the spell. Milo paused, briefly stunned. He'd gotten all of them? Surely, as primary casters, they'd have a higher Will save than that... oh well, think later, escape first.

Taking advantage of their condition, Milo rolled off the table and made a dash for the window. Standard action to stand up, move action to hustle and jump... he figured he'd make it just in time. There was a surprisingly painful crash (note to self: never jump through glass again) and Milo found himself in freefall. The window, it seemed, was roughly seven storeys aboveground.

"Feather Fall," Milo muttered, slowing his descent. As his feet gently touched the ground, he took stock of his surroundings. He was standing in the grounds of a rural manor, in the middle of some carefully kept gardens. The only thing between him and freedom was a clear shot over flat ground with the occasional shrub and a low fence. As he began to run, the cultists, judging by the hail of magic, recovered from their temporary blindness. An unfamiliar sparkling green bolt of light struck a shrub next to Milo, causing it to rapidly turn brown and wither.

Gulp.

"Mirror Image," Milo cast, summoning a trio of identical illusory copies of himself. The four Milos bolted in different directions, splitting the cultist's fire between them. As Milo approached the edge of the manor grounds, he noticed some distinctly unfamiliar mountains in the distance. The sky, he noticed, was missing a pair of moons.

"Crap," Milo muttered. He must have gotten hit with a Plane Shift or Greater Teleport, which was improbable, because both of those were well beyond even the supremely dark power of the Fell Lord, Thamior the Thaumaturge...

One of the illusory Milo's was hit with one of those weird green spells, vanishing instantly. As another of his doubles went down, Milo hopped the fence and ducked behind it briefly. His next spell took a little longer to cast than the others had, but Milo hoped it would pay off.

"Mount," he said quietly after concentrating for a few seconds. Next to him appeared a grey pony, which, except for its eyes—which were glassy and lifeless—appeared all but indistinguishable from a natural one. Unlike the mirror images, the mount was real—depending on your definition of real, of course. It was real enough to get him the Hells out of here.

Milo awkwardly pulled himself into the saddle (he never was much of an equestrian, as Skill Points were few and far between for a Wizard) and kicked the summoned pony's rump with his heels. As he was catching his breath, thinking of how close his run-in was (if that spell could just kill a plant like that, imagine what it could do to him? Milo's Fortitude save was lower than a serf's daily wage) he heard a loud crack from his left. One of the cultists suddenly appeared, wand brandished threateningly.

"Glitterdust!" Milo cast again, burning his last 2nd-level spell. As before, the burst of golden light blinded the dark wizard. If another one shows up, I'll have to resort to harsh language...

"They can teleport?" Milo shrieked. "That's a 5th-level spell! This is way beyond my ECL! I call shenanigans. Shenanigans!" But nobody responded. Who he was even talking to was unclear, as there wasn't another soul—except for the blinded Death Eater—in sight. After several minutes of galloping, Milo decided to rein his pony in for a short break while he considered his options.

Now you may be wondering, "what the heck is going on?" And that's a perfectly valid question, but unfortunately, Milo is as confused as you are. Perhaps a brief description of our perplexed hero is in order. As far as Milo is concerned, the information written on his character sheet sufficed as description: True Neutral, Wizard 3, Human, Male, Age: 11, Weight: 71 lbs (his world runs on the imperial system, the poor barbarians), Height: 4'9'', Hair: brown, Eyes: brown. And you may be thinking, "eleven years old? That seems a little young to be a Wizard." And you're right. Most Wizards, from where Milo comes from (more on that later) are at least seventeen before they become even a level one Wizard. Milo, however, managed to pull a fast one involving starting life as a Rogue and doing some retraining. "But wait," you protest. "That jargon doesn't mean anything to me at all. And even if it did, the minimum starting age for a human Rogue is still 16." But unfortunately, you don't have time to worry about problems like that, because Milo is, in fact, being attacked by a Death Eater on a broomstick. See what happens when you nitpick?

"Avada Kedavra!" the evil flying cultist shouted, making weird gestures with his wand. Milo felt his pony suddenly go limp beneath him as its heart stopped. Milo collided with the ground for most of his remaining Hit Points (Milo dumped Constitution during character creation, which seemed like a really good idea at the time). Weakly, he staggered to his feet as the cultist came around for another pass.

"You know, there's a reason most Wizards prefer to use a Phantom Steed to a Broom of Flying," Milo muttered. "That reason is Grease!" he said, with a complicated hand gesture to accompany the last word. He cast the spell, not targeting the cultist but his broomstick, which became nearly frictionless. Without any sort of safety strap or foot petals, the broomstick continued accelerating while the cultist, unfortunately, did not. Before meeting the ground, the cultist vanished with another distinctive popping sound. Milo frowned. What kind of cultist can cast save-or-die spells multiple times, teleport, afford a Broom of Flying, and yet not manage a simple Feather Fall? Maybe they're some obscure non-core class? Milo thought. Well, time to loot the corpse. A Broom of Flying would make an excellent replacement for his ex-pony, which was already starting to fade out of existence now that the magic keeping its form together was gone.

As Milo searched for the broomstick, he let his mind wander again. The last thing he'd done before slamming into that table in the manor house was confront the Supremely Evil Fell Lord Thamior the Thaumaturge (try putting that on a business card) with his companions. Everything was going according to plan, then suddenly... table. Milo was sure Thamior hadn't had a chance to get a spell off, especially not one of this magnitude. Maybe something over here pulled him across? Why in the Prime Material would anyone want to summon Milo, of all things? Milo shuddered to think of what Thamior was doing to his party without his arcane support. It was probably going to be his job upon returning to raise funds for three Raise Deads, because a thief, a meatshield, and a glorified box of band-aids against Thamior's power spelled T-P-K.

Milo stumbled across the broomstick, which had flown into the ground, point-first. He confidently pulled the stick out of the dirt, straddled it, and leapt into the air. Nothing happened except that Milo looked rather foolish.

"Hmm, must be command-word activated, I suppose? Swordfish!" Nothing happened. "Melon! Rise! Up! Activate! Flight! Abra Kadabra!" Ten minutes later, with all the usual suspects attempted to no avail, Milo gave up.

"Detect Magic." Nothing. The broomstick, as far as Milo could determine, didn't have enough magic to power a Bard's cantrip. It was an ordinary, mundane broom. For sweeping things.

"Wha... what? Then how... Agh, my poor head." Nothing happening was making any sense here. Maybe if he found some non-cultist residents of this strange world, they'd be able to explain things to him. Shouldering the broom, he chose a direction completely at random and started walking.

o—o—o—o

Some time after 3 AM, the villagers of Hogsmeade were surprised to find a dirty, bloodied, half-dead (or rather, five-sixths, to be precise, since you asked) young boy stumble into their village before collapsing of exhaustion. He was clutching in his hands a Nimbus Two Thousand.

"Who is he?"

"Is he a Muggle? How did he get through the wards?"

"Is he a student?"

"Blimey! Is that a Nimbus?"

"If he had a broomstick, why was he walking?"

"Someone send for Dumbledore, this kid needs help."

"I'm right here in front of you."

"No, not you, the other Dumbledore."

"Oh," said Aberforth, slightly disappointed. "Nobody ever wants to send for me."

As the nearest medical facility was the hospital wing of Hogwarts, and, as the villagers reasoned, this boy was more likely than not some student from the castle caught up in one of their fool adventures, he was rushed with all possible haste to the care of Madam Pomfrey, and, more than likely, detention. It was a very surprised, and somewhat sleepy, Professor McGonagall who answered the door. She immediately sent a Patronus to wake the school's Headmaster before carrying the boy to the hospital wing.

"Minerva! What's happening?" Dumbledore (the right one, this time) said as he entered the wing. The Deputy Headmistress quickly filled him in about what the villagers at Hogsmeade had discovered.

Dumbledore frowned. "I don't recognize him, do you?" McGonagall shook her head.

"This is most unusual. He's clearly of an age that he should be just starting in Hogwarts, so if he's a wizard of magical Britain..." McGonagall said, trailing off in thought.

"Why don't we wake him and ask?" Dumbledore suggested.

"Poppy believes it best that we let him recover. He's suffered some fairly serious injuries—it looks like a particularly nasty fall, perhaps."

"Could he be a student of Beauxbatons—or Durmstrang? I'll owl Madame Maxime and Professor Karkaroff. In the meantime, keep me updated."

McGonagall sighed. She wouldn't give up being Deputy Headmistress for all the gold in Gringotts, but it did involve rather a lot more sleepless nights than she would have preferred.

o—o—o—o

Milo awoke to the sound of people talking quietly. The odd thing about whispers, Milo had discovered, is that they tend to catch the ear even faster than ordinary talking. There were curtains around his bed, so he couldn't place a face to the speakers.

"Minerva! I—I noticed something… well, something most unusual," the first voice (female, human) said.

"What's the matter?" inquired a second (also female, human).

"The patient, he… well, he recovered," the first voice said hesitantly.

"Surely, that's good news?"

"Well, yes, normally very good news, this being an infirmary, recovery is most appreciated. But… not normally with quite the alacrity demonstrated."

"Explain."

"After precisely eight hours of bed rest, the majority of his wounds simply vanished before my eyes," the first voice said.

There was a brief silence.

"Well, I daresay I'm impressed. How did you do it?" the second voice—Minerva—asked.

"I didn't do it!" the first voice said, her voice rising. "I hadn't actually done much of anything beyond cleaning and bandaging his wounds!"

"Then… perhaps he had some Charm cast on him when he entered? Or one of the villagers did something?"

"That was the first thing I checked! I think… I think the possibility should be considered that he isn't entirely human," the first voice said cautiously.

"Poppy, get professors Dumbledore, Snape, Flitwick, and Sprout—in that order," Minerva commanded. "I'll watch him until then, whoever he is."

Milo frowned. Why were they so confused? A night's rest resulted in healing a hit point per level. Everyone knows that. Had they never slept? Were they Constructs—or even Undead? Milo reached for his Belt of Hidden Pouches, where he kept (among rather a lot of other, useful things) his spellbook. He needed an hour to prepare new spells (which he doubted he'd get, but it was worth trying.)

His Belt was gone.

Milo sat straight upright and checked his other pockets. Nothing. He broke out into a cold sweat. Without his spellbook, he couldn't memorize spells. If he couldn't memorize spells, he had a mere four 0th-level spells and then nothing. He was a Commoner for the rest of time, or at least until he could make a new one.

Almost as importantly, Mordy was still in the belt. Milo concentrated on the empathic bond, to see if Mordy was all right. Hunger, Fear, Confusion.

Milo licked his lips nervously. He'd just begun searching for something he could use as an improvised club (not his preferred way of doing things) when the curtains were drawn aside.

"Who are you, where am I, and what have you done with my Magic Items?" Milo demanded, before they were even pulled all the way aside. In walked an odd duo. A pair of aging humans in robes (Venerable meant +3 Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma, so Milo made a mental note not to underestimate these two) who were obviously spellcasters of some sort. Great big white beard, half-moon glasses, wands… What is it with the casters here and wands? Milo wondered.

"If you are talking about your broomstick, young man, its right beside the bed. And I would suggest you mind your manners," said the lady, who was sporting a rather severe bun of hair.

"Peace, Minerva," said the man in the purple robes. "He's clearly been through some sort of ordeal." The old man turned his pleasant, grandfatherly face to Milo. "Now, if you would be so good as to tell us who you are…?"

"I am Milo Amastacia-Liadon," said Milo proudly. For those of you keeping score at home, Milo's parents, being cosmopolitan humans, decided to give him a Halfling first name and both of their (Elven) last names.

"And I," said the grandfatherly man, "am Professor Albus Percival Dumbledore." He said it like Milo was supposed to know who he was. Maybe he really was famous; it was Zook who had all the Ranks in Knowledge (Nobility and Royalty) in their party. "This, of course, is Professor Minerva McGonagall. You are in Hogwarts, school of Witchcraft and Wizardry."

"Wizardry? Oh, thank Boccob. You're Wizards, then?" Milo asked, feeling profoundly relieved.

Dumbledore looked slightly taken aback.

"Well, naturally we're wizards—Except for Minerva, of course, who is, in fact, a witch. You didn't take us for Muggles, did you?"

"What? Mug—look, I think we're getting slightly afield. Was I wearing a belt when I came in here?"

"I'd have to ask Madam Pomfrey to say for certain, but there is a belt on your bedstand," the old wizard said.

"Oh, thank the gods. Don't you know that it's terribly rude, not to mention a sign of hostile intent, to part a person from his Magic Items?" Milo grabbed the belt, which was covered in tiny pockets (and had many more besides, which were invisible) and quickly opened the snap on one of the hidden ones. Out crawled a very distressed-looking brown-and-white rat. "Not to mention a Wizard from his familiar."

"Best not let Poppy see that," Dumbledore suggested. "She would not, I believe, take kindly to seeing a rat in her hospital wing. Now, could you please tell me, of what school—if, indeed, any—are you a student?"

"Conjuration," Milo said proudly, "though I've always had something of a knack for Divinations as well."

"The School of Conjuration?" Albus frowned. "Unless I'm mistaken, they were shut down, oh, sometime in 1869, after the Spoons Incident." Nearby, McGonagall shuddered. "Would you take it amiss if I asked to see your wand?"

"My wand? I don't have one. Never saw the point, really, and even if I wanted one I couldn't afford it."

"No wand?" McGonagall gasped. But Dumbledore frowned.

"Now, I'm not one to pay close attention to the ins-and-outs and developments of sporting equipment, but how is it that you managed to come by what I believe to be a most expensive racing broom if you can't afford even a simple wand?" Dumbledore asked.

"Oh, that thing? I took it off a cultist," Milo said blandly. "Seems pretty useless to me. If there's any magic in it, I have no idea how to make it work, and its shape is hardly optimal for sweeping."

McGonagall's mind recoiled from the notion of using a Nimbus Two Thousand to clean a house. Thinking the very thought was unthinkably unthinkable.

"I think the more questions he answers, the less sense this makes," Dumbledore said. "Start with the cultists, then how you came to be in Hogsmeade so late at night, then we'll discuss your school and the broomstick."

Milo shrugged.

"My party and I were storming the tower of the Most Maliciously Malevolent Magus, Thamior the Thaumaturge. After fighting our way past all the usual defenses—you know, skeletons, goblins," McGonagall choked slightly on hearing that, "that sort of thing, pretty routine, when we confronted the dark Wizard. Our Rogue crept into a flanking position while I distracted him with taunts, interrupting his monologue. The Cleric and I were about to unleash magical fury when suddenly, I was somewhere else entirely. The next thing I know, I hit a table in a room surrounded by cultists," Milo said. "They had dark robes and masks and everything; you should have seen them. So, one of them started casting some spell, it went like, 'Avada Keda—'" Milo was interrupted as McGonagall desperately clamped a hand over Milo's mouth.

"There's no need to worry, Minerva. He doesn't have a wand," Dumbledore said gently.

"Right. Er. Continue your story, then, Mister Amastacia-Liadon," said the old witch, slightly embarrassed. "But you must never say those words again. They are the incantation for the worst of the Unforgivable Curses."

"Please call me Milo; elf names tend to be on the long side," Milo said.

"Elf names?" McGonagall asked incredulously. "Albus, add that to the list of questions."

"Right, so I blinded the cultists with a Glitterdust, jumped out the window, provided false targets with illusions, summoned a pony, and rode off as fast as I could, but one of them chased me on that broomstick. One casting of Grease on the stick and the cultist fell — but he teleported to safety somehow. Not before he killed my mount, though. So I started walking, and I think I'd just found some village or another when I passed out. Pretty lucky, really, all things considered."

"Albus," McGonagall said quietly. "These… cultists… he speaks of. They sound an awful lot like—"

"I'd noticed, Minerva. It appears they were not quite so disbanded as we had once believed." Dumbledore said ominously. Milo grinned. That sounded like a plot hook if he'd ever heard one.

"Now, young wizard, if you could tell me what school you attend so I can see you home safely?" Dumbledore asked.

"Oh, that kind of school? Nah, never bothered," Milo said. "You gain experience way faster hunting dark Wizards and goblins and things, let me tell you."

"No school?!" McGonagall gasped again, this time even more offended than when she'd heard of his lack of wand. "That's criminal! Your parents should be arrested!" The professor paused, looking concerned. "You—you do have parents, don't you, Mister Ama—er, Milo?" she asked gently.

"Parents? Most likely. They're…" he paused. Something was wrong. He reached out for his memories of his parents, but came back with nothing. He started to panic. "I don't understand. My parents, they're… they're… what's happening?"

"Are you… quite alright, young man?" McGonagall asked, her voice full of concern.

"I… this has never happened before," Milo confessed. His backstory generally wrote itself on an as-needed basis. "Obviously I had parents, but I… I just, I can't remember them."

"Oh, I am so, so sorry." McGonagall said seriously. It broke her heart how many orphans came through Hogwarts, especially in the time after the war.

"Minerva, if you would please come with me for a moment, I think we need to discuss this with the other heads of houses," Dumbledore said. "We'll be back shortly, Milo, in the mean time I'll let Poppy take care of you."

o—o—o—o

"I think it's obvious that we're dealing with a very confused individual," Sprout said sadly after McGonagall had explained the situation. "He seems to have been orphaned at a young age and fended for himself since then, and is quite delusional."

"Sadly, I must agree," Dumbledore said. "I think we can assume that very little of his story is true, although he did describe the Death Eaters and the Killing Curse with an alarming level of accuracy. I think it likely, unfortunately, that his parents were killed by them at a young age."

"The broomstick," Flitwick said suddenly. "It's our only clue. We know that the Nimbus is a brand-new model of Quidditch broom, so he must have come across it recently. Judging by his vagabond nature and lack of wand, he didn't obtain it through legitimate channels. If we can find any of the broomsticks reported stolen, it might be able to discern the veracity of his story."

"Clever as always, Filius," Dumbledore congratulated him.

"Headmaster, what if his story is true?" McGonagall asked. "There could very well be active Death Eaters out there, looking for revenge." And, she thought quietly, the Malfoy Summer Manor is at about one night's walking distance from Hogsmeade… "Investigating the Nimbus will only draw attention to him."

"Well, it would appear we have but one option," Dumbledore said. "And the law is quite clear. Regardless of all else, the boy is clearly magical—otherwise, Hogsmeade's wards would have driven him off well before he made it within sight of the village. Term starts in only three days, and I believe this young man, both for his safety and for that of those around him, should be among the first years to be sorted."

"Headmaster, with respect," sneered Snape, who in fact meant none, "we can't just offer every street urchin and vagrant who wanders to our door a spot in this school. We're the best school in magical Britain, not the only one."

"I'm afraid I'll have to insist," Dumbledore said gently, but firmly. "Minerva, if you could take the young Mr. Amastacia-Liadon to Diagon Alley to get his school supplies and robes tomorrow, it would be much appreciated. Filius, would you please anonymously return the Nimbus to the Department of Magical Law Enforcement and quietly keep an eye on who picks it up? Pomona, would you be so good as to take over preparations for the sorting ceremony for us? As for myself, I will make inquiries at the Ministry of Magic, to see if any underage magic has been detected."

"And myself, headmaster?" asked Snape.

"Ah, Severus, I have a special task for you. I'm afraid you'll have to visit certain old… acquaintances again."

"I understand," said Snape with a sigh. He'd hoped it wouldn't come to this.

"Well then, I believe we all have our tasks. We'd best get to them."

o—o—o—o

On the one hand, Milo was not particularly enthusiastic about attending school. But on the other hand, it was pretty clear that this was what the plot demanded of him. Besides, this was his best shot at getting at those cultists, and everything about them said "we have loads and loads of Magic Items and gold." And it wasn't like he had anything else to do. Besides, he was only 300 XP away from a new level, and with it, one step closer to the untold arcane power of 3rd-level spells.

"I suppose I might be interested in attending your school, Deputy Headmistress," Milo said respectfully. Never hurts to flatter powerful NPCs on occasion.

"Excellent. We only have three days until term starts, so tomorrow we'll go out and purchase you your school supplies," McGonagall said.

"Oh, er. I haven't got any money, per se." Milo had spent the last of his loot buying that Belt of Hidden Pouches.

"None at all? Well, Hogwarts does have a small fund for… unfortunate… students such as yourself," McGonagall said thoughtfully, "but I'm afraid you'll likely have to make do with second- or third-hand materials."

"No complaints here. So what are we talking, like, quills and parchment and things?"

"That, of course, and also, oh where did I put that list…? Here we are. Wand, robes, pointed hat, dragonhide gloves," Milo choked slightly in surprise at that, "telescope, a cauldron, scales, and various text and spellbooks, wand..." McGonagall frowned as she read through the list. "It seems wand was listed twice. I'll be having a word with someone about that, I should think. It also says that you can have an owl, cat, or toad, though we generally make allowances for rats as well."

"A wand? What kind? Probably no higher than first level, but seriously, that's on your mandatory list? And, wait… spellbooks?" Milo asked incredulously. "You're going to buy me spellbooks?" Milo felt faint. There had to be some kind of catch. Telescopes clocked in at 1,000 gp alone, and if they had the capability to slaughter enough dragons to make gloves for the entire student body, the faculty here were not to be trifled with. This little shopping list was way beyond the average Wealth By Level of a 1st-Level Wizard, and Milo's rapid addition placed it at almost half of his current total value.

"I—I think I need to sit down for a moment," Milo said. "I appear to have been Dazed—or possibly even Stunned."

"Yes, well, I suppose it can be a bit overwhelming at first," McGonagall frowned at him. She couldn't imagine how someone could be so poor that a second-hand old textbook seemed extravagant. "In the meantime, I suppose, just stay here and focus on feeling better."

"Oh, I was going to ask about that. Don't you have any Clerics on staff?" Milo asked. His injuries weren't anything that a Cure Light Wounds wouldn't solve; it really was faster than bed rest.

"Oh, er, no. Not many in the magical world feel a, um, religious calling of that nature." McGonagall said carefully. Most wizards and witches felt a little awkward around matters of religion, what with all the suffer-not-the-witch-to-live's and inquisitions and all that.

"Hmm, that would explain that, then." Wizards heal injuries in a manner resembling how pigs fly—they generally tried to keep such a situation from occurring in the first place.

"In the mean time, I suggest you try to relax as much as possible, and I will be here early tomorrow morning to take you to London," McGonagall said before leaving.

Milo sat back, trying to contain his excitement for tomorrow. This time in two days, he thought, I'm going to be absolutely rolling in new spells and items… he was practically salivating at the thought. In fact, he realized, he was salivating at the thought.

Chapter 7: The Potions Master

"I'm just sad I didn't get to see his face when he read the Daily Prophet," Malfoy sniggered. Several Slytherins laughed as well. "I'll bet he was like, 'BWAH,'" he said, making a face that would match 'BWAH' rather well, in fact.

"Teach him to mess with Slytherin in our own dungeon," Crabbe (or Goyle) said.

"Yeah, shows him to mess with us in our own classroom," said Goyle (or Crabbe).

"And for that time on the train," Crabbe (probably) added.

"Yeah, that time on the Hogwarts express," said Goyle.

"Yeah, and for when Potter got the Remembrall from you," Crabbed continued.

"Yeah, for that time he showed you up in flying in front of everyone and got Longbottom's Remembrall," Goyle clarified.

"And then when he got put on the Quidditch team even though first years aren't allowed."

"Yeah, for when the teachers were so impressed at how great his flying was that he became the youngest Seeker in a century," said Goyle.

"In future," Malfoy said coldly, "could you two not list out every time they've shown us up whenever I have a victory?"

"Sorry boss," said Crabbe. "It's just that they have so, you know, many of them."

"Yeah boss," said Goyle. "They have so many, and they're real easy to remember, because everyone always talks about them."

Malfoy sighed. He wondered if the warranty had expired, or if he couldn't just send these two back for a pair of shiny, new goons.

o—o—o—o

"I can't help but feel like there was something I was supposed to do this morning," Milo said as he walked back to the castle from the forest, "but I just can't remember what it was. Can't have been very important."

o—o—o—o

Hermione was forced to admit to herself, however reluctantly, that she was dead bored. The three boys were total morons, but they did make things interesting. She wondered if there was some way she could work her way back into their preposterous plan without looking exceedingly foolish. She applied her towering intellect to the problem, hypothesized various scenarios and predicted their likely outcomes, and thirty seconds later said:

"Nope."

Hermione sighed. It wasn't even that their points were even slightly convincing, it was just that it was sort of fun, in a dark way, to imagine that You-Know-Who really was returning and that he was after the Stone and Snape was a dark wizard...

"But I can't go back on my position," she reminded herself. "Or I'll look like an idiot."

"Yes, but just think," she countered, "what if it is true? What if Snape is trying to get the Stone for You-Know-Who? Shouldn't I be helping put a stop to this?"

"If it is, Dumbledore would know, and he would do something. He's the only one You-Know-Who was ever afraid of, after all."

"But Dumbledore is just one person," the other side of her argued, "he could get caught by surprise, or called away, or be sleeping, or distracted, or anything."

"But if Dumbledore isn't enough, how could I possibly help? I'm barely twelve."

"Is that what everyone said in the last war?" she questioned herself. "Did they just say, 'I'm only a dressmaker, Dumbledore will take care of it, and in any case my marks in Defence Against the Dark Arts were rubbish,' and nobody did anything?"

"Doing the opposite and going on a witch hunt now will only make things worse," she protested. "There's no knowing where it will end."

"Without a witch hunt, you'll never catch witches."

"I am a witch!"

"You—er, I—know what I mean."

"So I'll just wait until there's proof," she said, "and then I'll help in any way that I can. How is that not reasonable?"

"Just think, Hermione, think. You—er, I—know what the problem is."

She sighed.

"It's that it's Harry and Ron that I'm depending on to find conclusive proof," she said defeatedly.

o—o—o—o

"Professor," Harry asked the ghost of Professor Binns politely, "Ron and I were wondering if you could help us on a little independent research?"

"Research—my help—independent—why, I'd be delighted!" the ghost said. "Would you believe that in all my years of teaching, no student has ever asked me that? What is it you need to know?"

"Nicolas Flamel," Ron said. "He just seemed like such a... a... uh, a dynamic and interesting—"

"—historically significant—" Harry added.

"—yeah, historically significant, dynamic, interesting, historical, erm a, figure." Ron finished lamely.

"And we'd love to hear everything you know about him," Harry said. For some unimaginable reason, most of the library seemed to be checked out already (maybe they were doing some re-organizing?) so they'd resorted to actually asking a professor for help. It seemed to rub Harry the wrong way, somehow, going to an adult, but it was all they could come up with.

Harry diligently tried, he really did, to listen to everything Binns said about Flamel and to stay awake while doing so, but the stone's texture in the floor was just so much more interesting. Ron's eyes developed a glassy look in under five minutes (glassier than usual, that is), and by the third hour Harry wasn't quite sure that he didn't look the at least as bad.

"Well," he said after they'd (finally) left Binns' office, "that was, uh, interesting."

"Was it?" Ron asked. "Glad to hear it."

"I think," Harry said, "that we might need Hermione."

"I was hoping you wouldn't say that, mate," Ron said with a sigh. "Did we learn anything important, though?"

Harry shrugged.

"Flamel's a big, powerful wizard and master alchemist who found out how to create a Philosopher's Stone—turns out, it's not necessarily a unique object, but he only ever made the one, anyway—which can turn lead into gold and create the Elixir of Life. He used to fight Dark Wizards, but decided to retire with his wife way back, and he's been sort of neutral since then. Keeps to himself, mostly."

"So, nothing we didn't already know," Ron said. "Great, just great. Well, there went our Saturday, eh?"

"Yeah," Harry said. "I hope Milo found something more useful in the Forbidden Forest."

"And that he didn't get eaten by werewolves," Ron added.

o—o—o—o

Milo, in a rare moment of luck, made a Listen check successfully. He almost wished he hadn't. He'd hoped to get out of the woods without the mandatory random encounter.

"Invisibility," he said as he faded from sight. Hope it's not a false alarm, he thought. That was my last 2nd-level spell.

All he'd heard was movement in the shrubs, and it could have been caused by anything. Really, when it came down to it, Milo not only didn't know what kind of creatures lived in this forest, but this world. Bugbears? Owlbears? Dire bears? Giant bears? Shapeshifted druids in the form of bears? Gods help him, grizzly bears?

As it turned out, it was far, far worse than any form of bear or bear-like monstrosity.

It was Professor Snape.

Is he here looking for me? Or is he the one killing unicorns, and he's going for another one? I could follow him, Milo thought, but Invisibility only lasts four minutes. And if I run into trouble, I'm already out of spells. Milo bit his lip. I feel like Harry Potter would for sure, but... well... this is a job for a Rogue. I've got no business sneaking around in a forest, tailing people. I'm a Wizard, I should have people for this. He frowned.

"Hey, Mordy," he whispered, "time to put that +10 bonus to Move Silently to use." Mordenkainen, who had been sitting on his shoulder, nodded gravely (although Milo couldn't see, because the familiar was as invisible as he was) and scampered noiselessly after the Potions Master.

o—o—o—o

"You're late," Lucius hissed. "You were supposed to be here forty-seven seconds ago."

Snape said nothing.

"I need a favour," Lucius said. "It would do well for you to comply."

"Go on," Snape shrugged.

"There is a certain individual who, I understand, is a first-year student attending Hogwarts," Lucius said. "He has no business here. Have him expelled."

"The Potter boy?" Snape grinned. He'd wondered when Lucius was going to make his move against the Dark Lord's mortal enemy. Fortunately, he and Dumbledore had prepared for this.

"No, we can deal with Potter later; I speak of one Mr. ... Amastacia-Liadon," Lucius said. He... no, it knows too much, whatever it is that we summoned, Lucius thought. "Whatever you have to do, get him out of that school."

"It shall be as you say," Snape said. Now, this is good news, Snape thought. Time to get back at that boy for insulting my house and attacking my students. And unlike Potter, I'm under no obligation to protect him. Snape smiled briefly before masking it. No sense letting Lucius know I'd do this one for free.

"It shouldn't be too hard for you," Lucius said. "He's not a wizard." I doubt he's even human. We may have accidentally created some sort of ... Homunculus. An artificial human. There's no telling what it might do.

o—o—o—o

When Milo returned to the castle, it was late afternoon. He was glad to make it to safety—not because he thought he was really in any mortal danger, after what he'd discovered in the forest, but because without any powerful spells he was as good as useless if another plot hook appeared.

What he had to do was find Harry. He had a right to know about Milo's discovery—it directly affected the Boy-Who-Lived, after all.

"M-M-Milo," Milo heard a familiar voice from behind him. "M-m-m-ight I have a w-w-w-word with you?"

"Sure," Milo said. "What's up, Professor?"

"E-enjoying the sun, I s-s-see?" Quirrell asked.

"It was sunny?" Milo asked. Nobody ever paid much attention to weather where he was from, unless it was an ominous thunderstorm. "Well, then I guess I was. And I went to check out that spider thingy I killed the other day."

"Oh, did you?" Quirrell asked. "Whatever for?"

"It's just that something seemed wrong about the whole thing. The tree really shouldn't have killed it," he said.

"It looked like a pretty heavy tree to me," Quirrell said. "Maybe it was an extraordinarily lucky hit?"

"Falling objects can't critical hit, because they don't make attack rolls," Milo said. "It would be different if I threw it."

Quirrell paused.

"I'm sorry, what did you just say?"

"Ah, nevermind. I'll figure it out eventually. I don't suppose you noticed anything?"

"No," said Quirrell. "I did not—although just a moment ago, I did see the Potions Master heading into the forest." Quirrell looked Milo directly in the eye when he did, as if expecting something.

"Oh, did you?" Milo said. "Wonder what he was doing. Gathering rare potions ingredients or something. Probably. Yeah, totally that." Natural 1 on Bluff. Great. Just great.

"Of course. Well, I'll be seeing you in class Monday," Quirrell said.

o—o—o—o

Not a Wizard? Snape mused. What could that possibly mean? How could he be in Hogwarts and not be a Wizard? I'll have to keep a closer eye on him in class...

Snape's breath caught. The only reason Lucius would have an interest in him is if the boy's tale were true, he thought. So, impossible as it seems, he really is from another world.

Snape was caught in a dilemma. If he refused to do as Lucius asked, it would blow his cover with the Death Eaters, and his position there would be necessary in the next war. And, though he tried to keep it from influencing his decision, he did want to get his revenge with Milo for 'accidentally' blinding his students. But... Snape was under no illusions about what Lucius would do to Milo once the boy was outside of the wards and away from Dumbledore's protection.

The Snape that everyone knew, the pawn of Lucius, would comply. If he didn't, it would confirm any suspicions Lucius had about him being a double agent. And besides, if Milo really wasn't a wizard, then it would be Snape's duty as professor to make sure he was expelled. Besides, Milo wasn't anyone important. It was unfortunate, perhaps, but the boy had become a pawn that needed to be sacrificed to protect the king.

Snape was broken out of his reverie when he bumped into the Defence Professor.

"S-s-s-sorry, S-S-Severus," Quirrell stammered and scurried away. Snape shook his head. It should have been me with that position, Snape thought. Quirrell is much more suited to his old job as Professor of Muggle Studies.

Hang on, Snape thought. He could practically hear the wheels clicking in his brain. What was it Quirrell said about Milo? That he was impressed with his magical abilities? From what Snape had heard, Milo was one of the least gifted students that Hogwarts had seen, apart from his occasional demonstration of wandless magic. And after that acromantula attack, Quirrell had tried pretty desperately to save the boy... most unusual. The Quirrell that Snape knew fainted whenever he saw a spider.

Most unusual, indeed. With everything going on involving Milo, nothing, Snape decided, should be treated as coincidence. Snape resolved to keep a closer eye on the Defence Professor, and watch for an opportunity to prove Milo's lack of magic. Shouldn't be too hard, he thought. I'll just have to wait for the other students to progress somewhat. When he fails to do so as well, that will be evidence enough.

o—o—o—o

Sometimes I'm so clever I outsmart myself, Milo thought bitterly. This is one of those times.

"Squeak squeak squeak squeak," Mordy said excitedly. "Squeak squeak SQUEAK."

"Mordenkainen: I don't speak Rat," Milo said, his voice tinged with an edge of frustration. Though they shared an empathic link, which let each know the other's general mood and condition, they couldn't actually speak until Milo hit level five.

"What's up, mate?" Ron asked him. Milo was sitting in Gryffindor Common Room, trying to figure out what Mordy had seen Snape do. From what he could tell, there was a great deal of squeaking involved. Ron and Harry had just walked through the portal, looking despondent.

"I found Snape sneaking about in the forest and had Mordy tail him, but I evidently didn't think very far ahead when I did. You ever hear of a spell that lets you talk to animals?"

"Nope," Ron said. "Except for Parselmouths, of course."

"Parcel mouths?" Milo asked. "What are those, aside from the worst thing to get in the mail imaginable?"

"Blimey!" Ron exclaimed. "Everyone knows about Parselmouths."

Harry sighed.

"Ron, I thought I asked you to stop doing that?" Potter said. "I was raised by Muggles, and Milo's from another planet or something."

"Oh, right. Sorry."

"We know as much about Parselmouths as we did about Quidditch," Harry continued.

"Sorry."

"Which is to say absolutely nothing."

"Sorry."

"Because we, unlike you, were not raised in Magical Britain."

"Sorry."

"Just saying."

"Right."

Milo coughed.

"Parselmouths?" he asked.

"Oh, right," Ron said. "Well, it's this really rare ability some people have that lets them talk to snakes," Ron said. "It's said Slytherin was one—Salazar Slytherin, that is—and You-Know-Who. It's a sign of Dark Wizards, for sure. I've never heard of any after You-Know-Who, and it's just snakes, anyway."

"Oh," Milo said. "Well, that's pretty useless." Harry, however, had gone completely white.

"I have to—that is, I should probably—I'll just go. Er. Bye." Harry said, and fled the Common Room.

"Well, that was weird," Ron said. "Wonder what that was all about?"

"Something significant, probably," Milo said. "But I don't think it has anything to do with us, yet. We can always ask him later, but right now, I have to figure out how to speak with this rat."

"So you can find out what evil things Snape was up to in the forest?" Ron asked.

"Yeah," Milo said. "then you can use it to get Hermione to help you figure out what's going on with the Philosopher's Stone."

"How do you know we need help?" Ron asked defensively. "For all you know, we learned everything we needed today."

"Oh? Did you?"

"Maybe. I wasn't really listening, to be honest," Ron admitted.

"Which is why we need Hermione."

"Which is why you need to make your rat speak."

"Yeah."

"Bollocks," Ron said. "Best of luck."

There was a spell Milo knew of that would help, called Speak With Animals. Unfortunately, it was only available to Rangers, Druids, and Bards—and Milo would sooner die than become any of those. If he could get his hands on a gnome—a proper gnome, not one of those garden gnomes that Ron kept complaining about—then they could maybe help, because they could speak with animals a few times a day. Only burrowing animals, though. Milo wondered if rats counted as burrowing animals or, if not, merely digging a hole once would count. He would, technically be "burrowing."

Milo sighed. He didn't have a gnome, he didn't have a Ranger, he didn't have a Druid, and he neither had nor particularly wanted a Bard.

"Squeak, squeak squeak," Mordy continued without pause.

There were only two options, as Milo saw it. He could attempt to push the rules past breaking point and test if his Spontaneous Divination ability could mimic Druid spells, or he could wait until levelling up to find out. The first option risked calling righteous fury upon himself from above, while the second took time and monster slaying. Unfortunately, patience was a virtue, and Milo was True Neutral.

"Speak with Animals," Milo tried to cast, attempting to swap out Protection from Evil. Other than losing the spell from his memorized list, nothing happened—but Milo felt a distinct sense of wrongness. It was as if the universe recoiled from him slightly, pondered for a moment, then...

"Excuse me," Lavender Brown said to him, "Professor McGonagall told me to tell you that Professor Snape wants to talk to you, like, right this second."

"I'm sure it's totally a coincidence," Milo said nervously as he started to sweat. "Heh, heh. Hah. Coincidence. OhmygodsI'mgoingtodie." Lavender gave him a sympathetic look, but said nothing.

Milo supposed he would just have to wait until he gained another level before finding out what Snape was up to in the Forbidden Forest. And this, he thought as he walked towards Snape's dungeon, is why you don't try to stretch the Rules as Written to allow more than 150% as much as the Rules as Intended, er, intended.

I just hope I'll have the opportunity to live long enough to learn from my mistake.

Milo knocked on the heavy wooden door to Snape's office, which created a surprisingly loud echo.

"Enter," a voice said sternly from the other side of the door. Milo quickly ran through his assets before opening the door: a pair of Prestidigitations and Dancing Lights, an Acid Splash, a Protection from Evil, a Silent Image, anda Feather Fall, as well as the contents of his Belt of Hidden Pouches.

So, not much.

Milo cautiously opened the door and walked in. Snape's office was... uniquely atmospheric. There was an eyeball floating in a jar, and it was probably the least creepy thing there.

"Ah, mister Amastacia-Liadon," Snape said. "I've been expecting you."

Milo whimpered quietly. Sitting on Snape's desk was a lustrous black flask inlaid with a silver skull pattern. There was a skull-shaped stopper with reflective red eyes. To complete the image, the eyes glowed slightly.

"Madam Pomfrey has instructed me to give you this," he said, gesturing at the very, very evil flask. "It contains a week's worth of antidote for acromantula venom," Snape continued. "You are to drink one teaspoon every night, ideally within a minute or two of midnight for full effect."

"W-why midnight?" Milo stammered.

"Oh, just so your body has time to process it before breakfast."

"W-why the sk-skulls?"

"It's the only flask I had in the correct size."

"Oh." That didn't, of course, answer the question of why he possessed such a flask in the first place. It looked more suited to holding the blood of sacrificial maidens than medicine. Well, no matter, Milo could just cast Detect Poison on it as soon as he left the office to see if it was dangerous.

"Oh, before you go, make sure you don't drink more than your prescribed amount," Snape warned. "That's a powerful poison in large quantities." Well, Milo thought, there goes that plan. It would just register as poisonous anyways. The safest option is to just toss a teaspoon of it down the drain every night and hope for the best.

"And make sure you don't miss a night, either," Snape said. "Or the venom could relapse, and you'll most likely die." Oh, come on.

"Oh. Um, thanks," Milo said. "I'll just, ah, go now. Bye, Professor." Milo fled the room, and didn't stop running until he was in front of the Fat Lady.

"Password?" she asked.

"Squeak," Milo said, and the painting swung open to reveal Gryffindor Tower.

Milo found Ron and Harry sitting at a table by themselves playing Wizard Chess. Harry had evidently returned from his weird flight earlier, but still looked a little shaken. Milo was no chess expert, but judging by the fact that Harry only had two pieces left, Ron was winning.

Milo collapsed into an overstuffed armchair and slammed the accursed flask on the table.

"Detect Poison, Detect Magic," he started casting rapidly.

"Bloody hell, mate," Ron said, staring at the skulled flask. "What's in there, You-Know-Who's tears?"

"Identify, Ancient Knowledge, Appraising Touch," Milo continued casting uninterrupted.

"What's that you're muttering?" Harry said. "Are you sweating? What happened?"

"It's poisonous and apparently nonmagical," Milo said to himself. "But that broomstick didn't appear to be magical, either. It could have a Magic Aura cast on it to conceal it from detection," Milo said, "or something more powerful. Otherwise I don't know at all what's in there... And it could really be poisonous, and Snape was just saying 'it's poisonous in large quantities' as an excuse to make me ignore the results of Detect Poison. Although Snape can't have known that I could do that, could he? Nobody here knows what my capabilities are, right? Unless he can read minds... Nah. Will is my highest save, that would never work. But Detect Poison only detects, like, actual, literal poison," he continued. "It wouldn't say anything was wrong if this were say, a Potion of Bestow Curse or Potion of Horrid Wilting... No, potions only go up to 3rd-level spells... so the worst it could be is, say, a Potion of Inflict Critical Wounds, maybe, which would still be more than enough to kill me. Or whatever the closest analogue is in this world."

"Sorry, what?" Ron asked.

"But if Snape is telling the truth and I don't drink tonight it I'll die." Milo ran his fingers through his hair. "Did Snape really give me an antidote that's technically poisonous just to fool my Detect Poison spell? And then make it into a lethal, but technically non-poisonous potion of some horrendous instant death spell once I'd concluded it wasn't really poisonous, at least in small doses, and therefore it's safe? Surely nobody's brain is that twisty..."

"Yours is, mate," Ron pointed out.

"But if this is going to kill me, why did he put it in such an over-the-top flask?" Milo asked.

"Uh," Harry said, "I'm not really sure what you're talking about, but maybe he gave you that flask of doom so you'd think 'surely no-one would put actual poison in something like this' and then you'd drink it."

"Ah!" Milo exclaimed. "You could be right! I'm going to die I never should have tried to speak to this useless rat!"

Over on the other side of the common room, Hermione rolled her eyes, put her book aside, and stood up exasperatedly.

"I couldn't help but overhear your anguished shrieks of, well, anguish," Hermione said walking over. "And why would Snape poison you with something everyone knows he gave you?"

"So you do think Snape's evil!" Ron said.

"No, dimwit," Hermione said, rolling her eyes again. "I said 'assuming your half-brained theory is correct and Snape is evil,' first. Remember?"

"You did?" Ron frowned. "I don't remember that, actually."

"Then try listening, next time, maybe?" Hermione asked testily. "Anyway," she continued as if Ron hadn't spoken, "if you drunk that and died, everyone would know Snape did it."

"I'd still be dead!" Milo protested.

"What I meant is, he wouldn't do it if it would reveal himself. Obviously."

"No, because he explicitly stated it would kill me if I either didn't drink it or if I drank too much," Milo countered, speaking rapidly. "So say I do drink it and I die, he could just say, 'oh, that poor stupid boy, he must have overdosed himself by accident, what a tragedy, oh, me, I'm so sorry, he showed so much promise, mwa ha ha, we're all worse off for his untimely death, oh, the humanity.'"

"So, ask Madam Pomfrey," Hermione said.

"Ask her what?" Milo asked, perplexed.

"If that's actually the antidote," she said.

Milo blinked.

"Why?"

"Because she'd tell you. She's a mediwitch; she knows what she's doing."

"I don't understand," Milo confessed. Asking adults for help was not something he, as an adventurer, had ever considered doing before.

"I'll use short, simple sentences so that even you can understand," Hermione said sharply. "Take this flask. Go to the hospital wing. Say, 'Madam Pomfrey, can you check that this is really acromantula antidote? I'm worried Snape gave me the wrong flask by accident.' She'll look at it and say, 'yes, this is the antidote, it's very dangerous so follow the directions precisely,' or, alternatively, say, 'no, that's distilled nightshade, among the deadlier poisons known to man.'"

"That's... a little unorthodox, but it just might work," Milo admitted. "But how do I know I can trust Madam Pomfrey? Actually, what if Snape assumed I would ask Pomfrey and deliberately made this here elixir of death to pass whatever test she would think of?" he asked. "Because he certainly outsmarted mine."

"No," Hermione said. "You outsmarted yourself. Just drink it."

"On the plus side," Ron said. "If you do drink it and die, that will prove you were right and Snape's evil and Hermione will help us stop him! It's a win-win."

"...but I'll be dead," Milo said.

"Can't have everything, mate," Ron shrugged.

"I've been outsmarted," Milo decided. "Whatever I decide, I'm probably falling for Snape's evil plan. I'll just... I'll flip a copper piece. Emperor, I drink it; Hydra, I don't."

He pulled out a copper from his Belt, and flipped it. It twirled four times in the air, and landed with a heavy thud on the table.

The four of them stared at it in disbelief.

"Blimey," said Ron. "I... I didn't think that was even possible."

"It is, without a doubt, highly improbable," Hermione conceded.

The coin was sitting on the heavy wooden table, balanced perfectly on its edge.

o—o—o—o

Snape leaned back in his leather chair, smiling. He knew he wasn't supposed to use Legilimency on students for his own amusement, but...

Even if I get sacked for this, he thought, it was, without a doubt, worth it. He could only imagine the agony and indecision going through Milo's head after he'd left.

Chapter 9: Hallowe'en

When Milo walked downstairs Hallowe'en morning, he was greeted by utter bedlam:

"I—I never thought this day would come," said Seamus. "Me mum always said it would, but... I guess I never really believed her."

"Well, I, mean, it's surprising, but really, we've been ready for it," said Ron.

"I say it's about time it happened," said Fred.

"Keeps us from having to live out the rest of our lives in suspense, just waiting for it to come," said George.

"I... I lost everything," said Lee Jordan soberly. "Everything."

"What happened?" asked Milo. "Did Vol—did You-Know-Who return?"

"What?" asked Fred. "You've lost it, mate, it's nothing like that—"

"—Although to some, like our dear Lee here, it's arguably worse—" continued George.

"—Teaches him to bet the farm on a sure thing—"

"—Don't be snide, you're only happy because it's your farm, now—"

"—Our farm, Fred, our farm—"

"Look, guys," Milo interrupted. "Can one of you just give me a straight answer?"

"I am led to believe," said Hermione Granger, sitting casually in an armchair, "that the Chudley Cannons went up against the Wigtown Wanderers this morning and actually won."

"Wait, and this is supposed to be important?" Milo asked.

"Blimey, important, mate!" said Ron, "That was the Northwestern Regional Semi-Finals!"

"So, to answer your question, apparently," said Hermione.

"The Cannons haven't won a match in decades!" Ron exclaimed. "Their fan club, back when they had a fan club that is, well, its motto was Let's all just keep our fingers crossed and hope for the best."

"Yawn," stated Milo. "Anyways, I have a sidequest to prepare for—and, for that matter, classes."

"Speaking of," Hermione said coyly, "what are you going to dress up as?"

"I don't actually have to do that, do I?" Milo asked.

"Oh, my, yes," said Hermione. "It's a prerequisite."

Well, that settled it. You can't ignore prerequisites. You can bend them, re-interpret them favourably, work around them, or barrel your way on through them, but you can't ignore them. Milo sighed.

"Okay," he said. "So I'll survive all my classes, stop a dark vampire wizard from returning from the dead, foil an evil professor's schemes, and make a Hallowe'en costume before the start of my sidequest, which is at five o'clock sharp."

"Oh, before you go," Hermione said, as if she'd only just remembered, "make sure you take this with you. Wouldn't want you to be late for your... sidequest... with Ms. Abbot." She held out a small, pink strap of some sort. There was a sort of a doodad in the middle, Milo wasn't sure how to describe it.

"Er," he said, "thanks, I think. What is it?"

"You don't even know what a watch – no. No, I'm not saying it. It's called a watch, Milo, it tells the time."

"Go figure. How's it work?"

"There's two hands, the short one points to the hour, the long one points to the minute... only, it's the hour times five. It's a bit complicated. Here..."

She spent the next ten minutes trying to explain how the watch worked, before giving up and bewitching it. She assured him that it would remind him when it was time to leave, and there would be no possible way for him to miss it. She then apologized, saying she had a bad case of hiccups coming on and fled the common room cackling. Milo had read that the Muggles here had a ridiculous stereotype of witches, flying around in broomsticks with mad hair cackling away under a full moon. Turns out all stereotypes really are grounded in fact somewhere down the line, he thought. Go figure.

Milo was particularly wary when he went down to get breakfast. The other Gryffindors seemed absorbed in their discussion of the Cannons' latest victory, so they lingered behind. At this rate, he thought, they'll miss their precious breakfast.

Milo was vaguely aware that the food was sort of holiday themed (there was much orange and black in attendance), but as usual, stuck to his Everlasting Rations. As long as he had 'about a pound of decent food' per day, he'd be fine, and this was really just more convenient than all this cutlery business.

"Oh, hey Milo," said a round-faced boy sitting next to him.

"Hey, Nev." Milo said. "What's new and relevant?"

"Well, I forgot where I left my Remembrall, I was wondering if you could do your trick...?"

"It's in your right pocket," Milo said.

"Wow! And I didn't even hear you cast it this time!" Neville said, grabbing the ball from his pocket. Like any other time it touched Neville's hands, it was glowing slightly red.

"I didn't. You always keep it in your right pocket."

"Oh, right—whoops!" the ball dropped out of his grasp, and fell towards the floor. The smoke in the glass ball turned black as soon it as left Neville's hands.

Milo reached to catch it, but with the distinct feeling of a failed Reflex Save, his fingers closed a second too late and he just wound up knocking it further away. It hit the cold stone floor and shattered all over the ground, but Milo was too distracted to care: in the instant that Milo's hands touched the ball, it glowed bright red. Brief as it was, there was no missing it. Before Milo could properly consider the problem, his thought process was interrupted.

"Had a little accident, have we?" Milo heard an all-too familiar voice.

"Mr. Malfoy, Mr. Coyle, Mr. Grabbe, pleased to see you," Milo said cheerfully.

"You know, after all that trouble Potter went through to get that ball back for you," Malfoy said to Neville with a sneer, "you'd think you'd take better care of it."

"Are you just here to exchange banter, or is this more than purely a social call?" Milo asked. "I'm on a schedule, you know."

"Are you, now?" Malfoy asked, his eyes suddenly alight. "The pressure starting to get to you? Distressed at seeing your plan fall all to pieces now, are we? I know what you're up to."

What in the Hells is he talking about? Milo wondered.

"You can't prove anything," Milo said, because it seemed appropriate. "And even if you could, you can never stop phase three," Milo said. He liked the sound of that phase three. It implied that there had already been not one, but two successful phases in whatever it was that Malfoy thought he was up to. Malfoy looked him up and down, closely.

"You're bluffing," Malfoy determined.

"Of course I am," Milo said. "Everything I said to you today was already a lie. Except this, of course." Milo leaned in close, and whispered, "or is it?"

Malfoy looked briefly perplexed, but recovered admirably.

"You act all tough," he said, "but I know where you really come from," he hissed. "And I know what you're trying to do. But it'll never work. My father's much too clever, and has too many friends, for it to work."

...What?

"Oh, we'll see about that," Milo said. If I keep him talking, maybe he'll let something else slip.

"Indeed we shall," said Malfoy. "Why don't you just ask your friends in the Wigtown Wanderers what they think, eh? See if they've still got your back now," Malfoy laughed and walked away, flanked by his goons.

"Well, that was weird," Milo said to Neville.

"I think it's really cool how you stand up to Malfoy," Neville said. "And, listen, are you going to eat your treacle tart? Can't remember where mine went."

"What? No, it's all yours," Milo said absently.

"Thanks," said Neville from around the tart.

"So, say Neville, any decent ideas for a Hallowe'en costume? Only apparently I need one for later this evening," Milo said. "It's got to look like a monster, but also allow enough movement that I can fight off actual monsters in it, if the need arises. Which it will, I'm sure of it. And I need easy access to my Belt of Hidden Pouches. No ideas, huh? That's cool, I'll think of something."

It occurred to Milo that Neville wasn't responding.

Milo glanced over at the boy, who was now slouched over the table, his face lying flat in a pumpkin pie.

"That's odd," Milo said as he looked around the Great Hall for help; but was surprised to find that, now that Malfoy had left, it was empty. What? He wondered. How is that even possible? This place is never empty... Frantically, Milo reached into his Belt of Hidden Pouches and grabbed his small vial of Antitoxin.

"Right, Nev, we got to get you to the Hospital Wing. Upsie-Daisy," he said, pouring the Antitoxin down Neville's throat. It wasn't an antidote by any means, but it should help somewhat. He attempted to lift the (fairly heavy) boy, but failed to have much success. "Agh! Curse this 8 Strength! There's no helping it, Levitate." I'd hoped to get to the evening with all of my 2nd-level spell slots intact. Never seems to work that way, does it?

Neville floated gently off the floor, and Milo gave him a solid push in the general direction of the door. He followed along, pushing Neville occasionally to keep him moving. Once he made it to the corridor, he broke into a run.

"Out of my way!" he shouted, scattering a bunch of students Milo didn't recognize. Probably Hufflepuffs, then. Neville was floating in front of him, looking decidedly unhealthy. The boy was shaking and growing increasingly pale as Milo pushed him along in front of him.

Why was the Great Hall empty? Milo wondered. How could that happen?

"Ickle wickle firsties," Milo heard an aggravating voice taunt from above. "Why is the ickle firstie floating? Are we using magic in the halls? Naughty, naughty firsties."

"I don't have time for this, Peeves!" Milo snarled, rounding a corner. "I think Neville could die, so don't try anything."

"Firsties always so dramatic," said the still-invisible poltergeist, "never see the joke, never see the laughs."

Milo decided to just ignore the taunting spectre. If he absolutely had to, he could use a Silent Image to chase him away with an image of the Baron again, but Milo really had to conserve his magic.

Milo, running at maximum speed and decidedly distracted (the most commonly forgotten -5 penalty to Spot checks known to man), never noticed the oil slick Peeves had placed in the corridor.

Milo slipped backwards, hitting his head on the floor. Neville, however, continued to float at Milo's running speed down the wrong corridor.

"PEEVES!" Milo shouted. "Come out and face me!"

"Face you?" Peeves asked. "But of course!"

A cream pie (nobody knew where Peeves got them from; the house-elves stopped making cream pies two hundred and thirty five years ago to try and discourage him. It didn't work.) materialized out of thin air and hit Milo in the face.

"You're a coward, you know that?" Milo asked. "You're even scared of a Silent Image of the Bloody Baron." Alright, it wasn't the smoothest sounding sentence ever, but Milo had to find some way to work Silent Image into conversation without making it obvious he was casting a spell. An image of the Baron drifted towards them from around the corner.

"Lies and Tricks!" Peeves shouted. "Lies and Tricks! Lies and Lies and Lies and Tricks! The Baron is in the Dungeons!"

Milo was already late for Potions, and hed'd lost sight of Neville. Milo stood up and wiped the cream out of his face.

"Very well, Peeves, you leave me no choice but to destroy you," Milo said, lying through his teeth. "I call upon the fell arcane might of Corellon Larethian!" Corellon was the god of elves, but there was no possible way that Peeves could know that. Milo, who still had an active and alterable Silent Image available, made the Baron vanish and redirected the spell at himself. His eyes started to glow white, and thirteen slender columns of white fire appeared about him in slowly rotating circle. Milo had once seen a Meteor Storm cast by an epic Sorcerer, and it hadn't looked half so impressive as this.

"Magic in the halls! Magic in the halls! Filch!" Peeves called from wherever he was hiding.

"In the name of Corellon Larethian, God of... of Doom, I abjure thee!" Milo shouted. He threw in some illusory mist for atmosphere and made it appear as though a pair of giant, purple eyes slowly opened from behind him. Milo was making this up entirely as he went by now, and wasn't really sure what he would do if Peeves didn't run away. Fortunately, bravery was not the poltergeist's strong suit.

"No! No! No doom, no doom!" Peeves wailed, and fled. Milo dismissed the spell and ran after Neville.

o—o—o—o

"What," Madam Pomfrey asked as the cream-covered Milo entered her domain at the speed of sound, pushing a floating Neville Longbottom in front of him. "is the meaning of this?"

"Shouldn't... have... dumped... Constitution..." Milo panted between breaths.

"I'm sorry, what about the Constitution?" Pomfrey asked.

"Poison," Milo managed.

"You've poisoned the Constitution?" Pomfrey asked. "Isn't it, you know, a sheet of parchment?"

"Neville!" Milo sputtered. He really needed to catch his breath; he felt like he was going to faint.

"You mean to suggest that Neville poisoned the Constitution?"

Milo groaned. Why did this keep happening to him?

"Neville's... been... poisoned!"

"Oh, my lord! Why didn't you say so at once? Quick, get him on the cot!" The stern mediwitch grabbed her wand immediately and started casting what Milo presumed where diagnostic divinations.

"We were just in the Great Hall," Milo said. "He was having breakfast, then I turned around and found him face down in some pie. So I rushed him here as fast as I could."

"And the food made him float, did it? Most unusual..." Pomfrey said.

"What? No, I Levitated him," Milo said.

"Oh? Impressive. Now get out, so I can try and save his life without distractions. He'll probably wind up in St. Mungo's again... poor boy."

"Right," Milo said, and bolted from the room. He had to make it to the Dungeons in... negative twelve minutes. Ah, Hells.

He eventually stumbled into the Potions class twenty minutes late, still covered in cream and bits of pie crust, drenched in sweat, and gasping for air.

"You're late," Snape said shortly, "by twenty-one minutes. Twenty-one points from Gryffindor, and detention this evening immediately after your Defence Class."

"But... Peeves..." Milo started to say, but immediately knew it was the wrong choice of words. Peeves hadn't been an acceptable excuse for tardiness for years. Snape just shook his head silently, then went back to berating Harry for his latest minor mistake.

Milo groaned. He hadn't been awake for an hour and he'd already lost twenty-one House Points and two of his very limited number of spells per day. And now he'd have to suffer the humiliation of utterly failing to make a potion again. Well, there's nothing else to do, he thought, than follow the directions on the chalk board and hope for the best. Sigh.

Malfoy gave him a smug look.

"Hey, Ron," Milo whispered, "where was everyone during breakfast?"

"Well, most of the Gryffindors were too busy caught up talking about the Cannons' latest victory to bother eating, and I imagine it was more-or-less the same with the other Houses."

"But Hermione loathes Quidditch, why didn't she come down?"

"I can't say for sure," Ron said slyly, "but I think she was enjoying making snide remarks too much to leave."

"And Neville? He was there."

"Dunno, mate," Ron admitted.

"Nev was rushed to St. Mungo's yesterday," Harry supplied, "after one of Fred and George's pranks got out of hand. I guess he only just got back. Where is he, anyway?"

"Poisoned," Milo said simply.

"No talking!" Snape snapped. "Five points from each of you."

Hermione groaned. Gryffindor was rapidly approaching zero points, and it was largely their fault.

The rest of Potions was uneventful, with the exception that Snape seemed incredibly pleased with himself. If he were a normal human, Milo thought, he'd probably be humming to himself. As it stood, he was simply sneering just a little less – not that this made him any more pleasant to be around.

Milo ran his fingers through his hair nervously as he left the Dungeons. Detention after Defence class... well, the class normally ran until three, but Quirrell had said he had something special planned for his Hallowe'en lesson. That should still leave me with plenty of time to make my costume for five, assuming Snape doesn't go overboard.

Milo paused.

My plan relies on Snape's mercy.

Crap.

"We've got half an hour before Transfiguration," Harry said from behind him. "Want to visit Nev?"

"What?" Milo asked distractedly. "Why?"

"Uhm," said Harry. "Because he's our friend? And he's sick?"

"Oh, right, yeah. Friendship. Let's go, then."

o—o—o—o

"Nah, really, it's fine," Neville said, lying on his hospital bed. "Actually, it's a shame it wasn't more severe."

"What? Why?" Harry asked.

"Well, it's just that if I go to St. Mungo's one more time, I get a free ice cream," Neville said. Harry chuckled.

"So, what happened, anyway?" Potter asked.

"Madam Pomfrey says I ingested lethal quantities of arsenic, deadly nightshade, cyanide, chlorine, and ricin this morning," the round-faced boy explained.

Harry gave a low whistle.

"I don't even know what half of those even are," he admitted.

"It's no problem at all," Neville said. "Madam Pomfrey says that as soon as I regain feeling in my limbs, I can go back to class."

"Why would anyone want to poison you, Nev?" Harry asked.

"They weren't trying to poison him," Milo said simply. "They were trying to poison me. What's more, I know who did it."

"What? Who?" Harry asked.

"Huh, that's unusual. The scene's supposed to change after I make a dramatic announcement like that."

Harry blinked.

"Oh. We should head to Transfiguration, or we'll be late and lose more points."

"Right."

o—o—o—o

As it turned out, they were late anyways.

"Two points from Gryffindor," McGonagall said sternly. The rest of the class sat down and attempted, with varying levels of success, to turn pumpkins into teapots. Milo, however, was given the same matchstick he'd had at the start of the year.

"I can't let you start on teapots until you've managed to transfigure more than just the colour of the stick, young man. I'm sorry," she explained, then sighed. "If you can manage to change its weight, sound—that is, the sound it makes when dropped—or shape at all," she added, "then I'll let you move on."

Milo frantically pulled out his spellbook and re-read the description of Prestidigitation. There was nothing in there about anything beyond colour. He bit his lip. There was a sewing needle in his Belt of Hidden Pouches, but Milo assumed that other students had tried to pull that one in the past and McGonagall probably had a way to tell the difference. He hadn't prepared Ghost Sound, which could create illusory sounds, but even if he had he probably couldn't get the timing right to make a ping! sound at the exact moment the pin hit the table. If he'd prepared Mage Hand, a weak telekinesis spell, he could maybe push down very gently on the pin to simulate the metal's higher density, but his only 0th-level spells were Dancing Lights, Prestidigitation, and Acid Splash.

Milo ran his fingers through his hair nervously. There was absolutely no way he could turn this stick into a pin using his arcane magic. He had one last, desperate ploy...

He slowly withdrew his wand from its pocket and, following the directions that Milo had only ever half-listened to, focused on the image of a pin in his mind. He imagined every curve, the metallic glint, the slightly heavier mass, and the steely sound a pin makes when dropped. With all of that in his mind he, very carefully, tapped the wand on the matchstick and held his breath. He closed his eyes.

Come on, secret wizard powers, activate!

He didn't feel anything happen, and very slowly opened one eye to peer at, hopefully, a shiny new pin.

Nothing had happened.

"Nuts," Milo muttered. It was probably for the best, though as he might have been stuck multiclassing into two primary casting classes—or in layman's terms, permanently magically handicapped. Milo could use the oil he kept in his Belt of Hidden Pouches to create a fire and sneak out in the ensuing chaos... no, these wizards could create water. Milo sighed. He raised his hand.

"Yes?" asked McGonagall.

"Professor," Milo said quietly, then stopped. He looked around at the other Gryffindors in the room. Harry was looking at him with an unreadable expression, Ron was trying to find his wand on the ground under his desk, and Hermione was studiously examining her newly-transfigured teakettle. He'd never been quite sure what they thought about him. Milo was certain none of them completely believed his story about being from another world altogether, so they probably thought he was mad. Milo was okay with that. All the really brilliant Wizards looked at least a little mad to outsiders. At times, they were impressed—seriously impressed—with what he could do with magic. He was the only student below fourth year who could efficiently deal with Peeves, and his defeat of the Acromantula in September was very nearly legendary. His nightly Scholar's Touch-enhanced studying had made him the top student in History of Magic, much to Hermione's chagrin. But... other times, times when he didn't have the right spell prepared, times when he asked "what's Quidditch?", times when he'd run out of spells per day, times when Arcane magic just couldn't do something – times like this, they just looked at him with pity.

"Yes?" the Professor asked.

But there was more at stake here than his own pride, although there was that, too. What would Mordenkainen—the legendary wizard, not the rat—say about this? What about Elminster, Treantmonk, and Otiluke? Sorry, legendary wizards, it turns out I found another universe and their magic is superior to ours. Best put away your spellbooks, start naming your currency after sailing ships, and drop by Ollivanders for wands if you want to keep up.

But what could he do? Polymorph Any Object was eighth level. Eighth! Most Wizards never made it past 3rd-level spells. By the time Milo could turn this match into a pin, if he ever even got that high level, he'd be able to alter reality to his liking. He'd be going toe-to-toe with Wyrms.

Even Wizards can't do everything, he reminded himself, so there's no shame in admitting defeat. It takes a Cleric to heal... well, actually, a Wizard could just summon a monster that can heal people for him. It takes a Rogue to pick a lock... actually, that's not true, a Wizard could just cast Knock. Okay, a Rogue to sneak around... no, Wizards can cast Invisibility.

Ah, screw it. So maybe Wizards can do everything. But not all at once, not all in one day, not with only one Wizard, and not all at level three.

"I – I can't do it," Milo admitted bitterly. "I can't turn one thing into another like this. It just can't be done."

McGonagall remained silent for a moment, her eyes boring holes into his head.

"I see," she said simply. "Well then. Drop by my office after your Defence class and we'll decide what to do."

"I have, uh, prior arrangements," Milo confessed. The other students avoided making eye contact with him.

"Then cancel them," McGonagall said simply. "Your education must come first."

"You'll, ah, have to take that up with Professor Snape," Milo said. "I've got detention. Again."

McGonagall briefly covered her face with her hand.

"Very well. Come afterwards as soon as you can," she said, then left to go help Ron, who had only managed to transfigure his pumpkin into another pumpkin.

Milo then realized his mistake: there was still half an hour left to Transfiguration class, and it was going to be awkward without anything to do. Next time, he thought, if there ever is a next time, never admit defeat without an exit strategy.

Milo spent the time trying to figure out what to use as his Hallowe'en costume, but hadn't made any progress by the time the Professor dismissed them for lunch.

"So," Harry asked him expectantly as they walked towards the Great Hall, "Who did it?"

"Did what, convinced the capricious, adolescent, vengeful, petty being who runs the universe to make my life as difficult as possible? Me. It's my fault for trying to push Spontaneous Divination."

"You shouldn't talk like that," Hermione said. "You might offend someone."

"I think he's already pretty offended," Milo said. "That's sort of what I was getting at."

"What?" Hermione asked. "Wait, you think you offended God? Wait, you believe in God?"

"Wha?" Milo asked. "Gods? Sure, there's loads of 'em. Not believing in them is like not believing in magic. In fact, it's exactly like not believing in magic—ask a Cleric."

"Wait, no, I meant—" Hermione began as they entered the Great Hall, but Harry, uncharacteristically, cut her off.

"And I meant, who poisoned Neville?" Harry said. Milo waited to respond until they'd approached the person he was looking for. Milo crept up directly behind him

"Draco Malfoy," Milo said, simultaneously to answer Harry's question and get Malfoy's attention.

"Oh, it's you," said the blond Slytherin, jumping slightly. "What do you wa—"

"This morning Neville Longbottom was poisoned," Milo cut him off. "It was by someone attempting to get at me. Someone, probably, with access to Snape's storerooms, someone with an inexplicable grudge against me, someone with access to my food, and someone stupid enough not to watch me long enough to realize I never eat any food offered me."

"What are you blabbering on ab—" Malfoy began, but was cut off again.

"That would narrow it down to a limited list of suspects, but you even practically told me who did it. You arrogantly bragged something about the Quidditch game, frankly I wasn't really listening, but you seemed to think a victory for the Wrongton Wunderbars, or whatever, was a problem for me. So I thought, what made you think I care about Quidditch? And realized, nothing. You knew I don't care about Quidditch, no, you wanted the Great Hall empty this morning. So the ridiculously circuitous plot that your twisted brain invented was to somehow rig the Quidditch Midwestern Final Pseudo-Regionals so that all the students in Hogwarts would be so busy being flabbergasted about their beloved Cuddly Cannons losing that they'd skip breakfast. All the students except for me, that is – me and Neville, who came in from St. Mungo's. And so you poisoned my treacle tart where there would be no-one to help me. Draco Malfoy, you tried to poison me. And you would have gotten away with it, if it wasn't for my Everlasting Rations. And the fact that you came by to gloat in the middle of the assassination attempt. I mean, seriously."

"He had me up until 'Wrongton Wunderbars,'" Ron said quietly to Harry.

"It was the Pseudo-Regionals that got me," admitted the Harry.

"Cuddly Cannons," Hermione laughed. An uncharitable person would call the sound she made a giggle, because while it was still politically correct to have giggling girls in a piece of literature in 1991, this is no longer the case.

Malfoy stared at Milo completely disbelievingly for a moment, then laughed. His laugh was like a Wizard's power progression by level: it started slow and weak enough to lose a fair fight with a cat on occasion, worked its way up gradually to defeating, with some difficulty, Hobgoblins and Bugbears, then in the snap of a finger was suplexing the laws of physics and ruling the universe before breakfast.

"You seriously think I tried to poison you? Milo, if my family wanted you dead, you wouldn't still be standing here. And besides, that's not why I rigged the Quidditch game, and you know it."

"Wait, he actually—" said Ron, flabbergasted.

"This whole wild accusation is just to divert attention from the blow I struck to your real masters," Malfoy sneered, "and only serves to underscore your own defeat. Fool." With that, Draco spun on his heels, and started walking away. Then he paused, and turned around. "Actually, this is my table. Gryffindor's is back over there. You leave."

o—o—o—o

"Crap," Milo muttered when they got back to their table. "I was pretty sure, like, 70% at least, that it was Malfoy who did it."

"I dunno," Ron said. "I still think it could have been him."

"Nah," Milo said. "If it was, he either would have denied everything, or fessed up and challenged me to an honour duel or something. He admitted to being behind the Quidditch thing, so it can't have been him."

"So what was he trying to do? What did he mean by 'your real masters?'" Harry asked.

"Who knows? Who cares?" Milo shrugged. "Anybody want my treacle tart?"

Chapter 11: The Troll and the Dementor

Author's Notes: I've gone back and changed the scene breaks on earlier chapters to the o—o that I use now, which actually appears on Fanfiction. Also, I've edited some cases of the word Wizard to standardize capitalization: Capital W refers to the D&D Wizard class, lower-case wizard refers to Harry Potter wizards. However, I've probably missed a lot of them, but that's what I'll be using from here on out.

o—o—o—o

"All students, return immediately to your Common Rooms," said a beleaguered Professor Trelawney—an attack by a Troll was enough to knock even the Divinations Professor out of her usual half-asleep daze—to a group of Gryffindors lounging in the Great Hall.

"Excuse me, Professor," said Percy, the Gryffindor Prefect. "what's going on?"

"There's a Troll loose on the second floor!" she said anxiously. "And to think of all the poor students who saw the Grim today..."

"Right! Just leave it to me, Professor," said Percy, standing to his full height (as if that would do much against the twelve-foot-tall monstrosity on the loose). "Gryffindors, come with me! Are we missing anyone?"

The Gryffindors, mostly first years, looked around at each other.

"Hannah's outside, by the Lake," said Lavender Brown.

"And Milo's with Snape," said Ron.

"Professor Snape, Ronald," corrected Percy. "And he'll be fine if he's with a professor. I'll find Hannah after I've walked you all to the tower, come along—quickly, now!"

Harry, Ron, and Hermione shared a quick look as the other Gryffindors started filing out of the massive room.

"Snape must have released the Troll!" Harry exclaimed to the others. "We've got to go find Milo."

"Professor Snape can't have released the Troll, the key was in the Headmaster's office," said Hermione.

"So, what, Dumbledore set the Troll loose? Obviously someone must have pulled a fast one on him," said Ron. "And now Milo's alone with old batface, and it's a perfect time to just throw him out a window and say the Troll did it. Let's go, Hermione," Ron pleaded.

"But—"

"I'm done talking," Harry said. "Our friend could be in danger right now. Hannah's outside, she's probably the safest of all of us. I'm going, with or without you two," and with that, Harry stood up from his table and walked away from the group.

"Harry Potter!" said Percy. "Where are you going? The Common Room is that way!"

"Going with Trelawney," lied Harry. "To help find the Hufflepuffs—you know how they are."

"Good man!" said Percy. "Best take Ronald with you—he could use someone like you as a role model. Well—good luck," he said, and left leading the others.

"Someone like you as a role model," sneered Ron. "Wonder what he'd say about that if you knew you lied right to his face? Grumblegrumblegrumble..." Ron trailed off.

Hermione sighed.

"All right, I'm coming with you. Someone has to keep you two from getting into trouble," she said airily. Secretly, her heart was racing with excitement and anticipation.

"Great job you've done so far," said Ron.

"Enough talking," snapped Harry. "Wands out, and let's go, already. Hermione—ask the paintings if they've seen Milo or Snape anywhere. They'll talk to you, you're top of all our classes."

"Not History of Magic," said Hermione, her face flushing slightly.

"Ron, keep an eye out for teachers and prefects," said Harry. "Oh, and rampaging Trolls."

o—o—o—o

Why, Milo wondered (briefly), am I looking up at the floor?

—Thud—

Milo hit the ground—hard.

"I have to stop doing that," he groaned. He'd gotten lucky and made his Reflex Save for half damage when the Troll dropped a wall on his face, but was somewhat less fortunate on his follow-up Grapple check to avoid being thrown across the room. A normal human would have broken numerous bones or died, but adventurers are somewhat more resilient than that. In total, he'd taken 8 points of damage—and for those of you keeping track back home, that put him at precisely 0 hp. That left him Disabled, meaning he can either shuffle about slowly or try to attack (or cast a spell), but doing the latter will knock him unconscious and dying.

Milo crawled slowly around a corner, and tried to stay as silent as possible. Next time, he thought, make sure there's a Potion of Cure Light Wounds in your Belt of Hidden Pouches.

Snape was nowhere to be seen.

I need a distraction.

"Sorry, Mordy," he whispered to his familiar. He had a bad feeling that, in a few levels, when Mordy could speak back, he'd be getting an earful for this.

Mordenkainen, rodent extraordinaire, leapt out of his home in Milo's belt and scurried around the corner to the Troll. Milo couldn't see what happened, but heard a mighty roar worthy of an Elder Wyrm, and then a loud crash.

While the alleged Troll was occupied, Milo got to work. Reaching into his Belt, he grabbed his flasks of oil and unstoppered their lids. Oil from his universe goes a long way, and was enough to cover a five-foot square. The hallway was closer to ten feet wide, and so Milo used four flasks to cover the whole hallway ten feet deep. He then spread caltrops (nasty, spiky contraptions) across the hallway as well.

Lastly, he (very carefully) took out a small, extremely valuable feather. The feather, much stiffer and heavier than a mundane feather, was one of Milo's most treasured possessions. It only worked once, and, while he had three of them, he wasn't getting any more until he could return home. Gingerly, he placed it on the ground in the oil, surrounded by caltrops.

"Hey, ugly!" Milo shouted around the corner. "Leave my friend alone!" On cue, Mordy scurried away from the Troll, up Milo's leg, and into his magic belt.

The Troll gave a mighty roar and charged Milo's position.

Milo grinned an evil sort of grin.

As the Troll placed its first heavy footstep on the oil-slick polished stone floor, it lost its balance. It slid forwards a few feet, an almost comical expression of surprise on its ugly features. It then fell backwards onto the hard floor—and the scattered caltrops. They weren't even close to powerful enough to deal any real damage, but all Milo needed was to keep the troll in position for a round. The Troll let loose a bellow of pain that shook the castle as Milo muttered the command word to his Feather Token.

For those unfamiliar, the Tree Feather Token is the most useful magic item ever devised. On command, it instantly creates an entirely real, nonmagical oak tree five feet wide and sixty feet tall.

There was a swift, sudden breeze and a loud pop as a tree appeared in front of Milo. It didn't grow, it didn't start small and swell up, it was just there.

The ceilings in Hogwarts were as varied as the halls, paintings, and geography on a day-to-day basis, but here they were only eight feet tall (the Troll had to stoop). The tree, which appeared directly underneath the Troll, blasted it through the ceiling. And the one after that. And the one after that.

In total, the Troll was pushed bodily through seven floors, including three hallways, two unused classrooms, Professor Binn's quarters, and the Hufflepuff common room, which was now home to the forty-foot-wide canopy of a great oak tree.

"Quaal," Milo said weakly to the mythical inventor of the Feather Tokens, "I'm leaving everything to you in my will."

Crash.

"Uh," said Milo.

Crash.

"That really can't be good."

Crash.

"I'll just hobble away at half speed, shall I?" Milo limped down the hallway, which ended in a dead-end, and a large window.

Crash.

"Milo!" Milo heard someone say. "We're here, to, ah, rescue you..."

Crash.

"Blimey, was this great, dirty old tree always here?"

Crash.

"Ron!" said a sharp, female voice, "Careful, watch where you step. Someone's booby trapped the ha—"

CRASH. The ceiling caved in, and the Troll (heavily battered and bruised, but still in the game, so to speak) landed, gracelessly, directly behind Milo. Fortunately, it was looking away from him. Milo stood there breathlessly, trying to make as little noise as possible. Maybe it will just... go away? That could happen, ri—

Milo's watch chimed, loudly, and then started to speak.

"Milo's got a da-ate, Milo's got a da-ate!" it sang cheerfully. "Don't be late, don't be late, 'cause Milo's got a da-ate!"

"Oh, uh, hi there. See, the thing with the tree, that was nothing personal, right?" Milo said weakly. "So, why don't we just put this behind us—"

The Troll grabbed Milo with one arm, and, with a casual underhanded swing, neatly defenestrated him.

Harry, who had boldly ran across the slick, spiky hallway, frantically tried to help; but the young Wizard was out of sight before Harry was halfway through "Wingardium."

Then the Troll turned to face the three under-trained, under-prepared, under-aged wizards (well, two wizards and a witch).

The glass shredded Milo's already scorched and torn robes, but fortunately his Mage Armour protected his skin from the worst of it.

Milo made a high, graceful arc over the Hogwarts Lake before he managed to stop blubbering long enough to cast Feather Fall.

Our Hero, covered in dust and soot, his black robes in tatters, his hat missing, his shoelaces untied, slowly floated to the ground, landing, as it would happen, in the arms of a giant pink bunny.

"Amazing Dementor costume!" Hannah (in fancy dress) exclaimed. "Nice entrance, too!"

Milo grinned briefly, then collapsed as his hit points dropped into the negatives.

o—o—o—o

Concealed by his Disillusionment charm, Snape waited.

The Cerberus slept, the low rumble of its triple snore shaking the floor slightly.

Still, Snape waited.

Outside, the Troll was very likely killing one of his students.

Still, Snape waited.

His quarry was as invisible as he, but Snape had an advantage: the bane of all invisible wizards, everywhere. One that would stop the Dark Lord himself, were he invisible.

The door was closed. Quirrell would make his move—soon. Releasing the Troll was an obvious distraction to allow him to get in here unnoticed.

Still, Snape waited.

The good-natured Muggle Studies Professor had come back from Romania... different. Something had happened to him there, and it hadn't been vampires. The good-natured Muggle Studies Professor was gone, now. The Headmaster knew something, but whatever it was, he kept it to himself.

Still, Snape waited.

The castle shook, and a deafeningly loud CRASH shook the room. One of the Cerberus's heads, jostled out of its slumber, perked up curiously.

Still, Snape waited.

The doorknob turned slowly.

Still, Snape waited.

Roots, of all things, slipped through the cracks in the masonry, breaking apart the mortar. The walls buckled slightly.

Still, Snape waited.

The door opened, and closed.

Still, Snape waited.

o—o—o—o

"Uh, Hermione," said Ron anxiously. "If you were planning on doing anything smart, now would be the time?"

Hermione simply stood staring up at the Troll, her face pale.

"Ron!" Harry shouted, barely dodging a large stone block. "What spells do we know?" The block, thrown by the Troll, exploded on the wall behind him.

"Uh. There's the one that makes our wands glow," he said. "and we can Transfigure teakettles. Sh-should we Transfigure teakettles?"

"What about Wingardium Leviosa?" Harry suggested.

"I dunno," Ron said skeptically. "That Troll looks a little heavier than a textbook to me."

"Not the Troll, the blocks!" Harry realized. Desperately, they began Levitating anything in sight—stone blocks, the weird spiky metal things, paintings—over the Troll's head and dropping them. It was, it appeared, only marginally effective. The Troll's thick skull was made of sterner stuff than even the thousand-year-old masonry. If I get out of this, Harry resolved, I'm going to learn how wizards fight. And I'm going to be the best there is. Nothing is going to threaten my home ever again.

"...to all those who ask," Harry heard Hermione whisper.

"What was that?" Harry asked, his brow drenched in sweat from the effort of Levitating the stone blocks that once made up the walls of his beloved castle. His castle. This Troll would regret the second it scuffed the first candlestick in his castle.

"Portraits of Hogwarts!" Hermione roared. "Run! Run to your neighbours, shout, scream, anything. Find the Headmaster, or McGonagall, or Flitwick, Filch, anyone." A nearby painting of a knight drew its sword and saluted, and with a cry of "Yes, My Lady!" rode away on its stallion. The others just stared at her, stunned.

"Well, I never," said a portrait of a fat lady (but not the Fat Lady) in an evening gown. "The nerve of students these days, why, in my day, they employed the whip."

"Couldn't have said it better myself, Agnes," said a bespectacled man.

"RUN!" she screamed at the paintings again. She didn't need to tell them a third time.

"Right!" said Harry. "Now we just need to slow it down."

"Yeah," said Ron dismally, "assuming we can rely on Agnes to talk to Dumbledore about anything other than the state of today's youth."

"Hermione, do you know any spell to create fire? Or sparks?" Harry asked. Hermione shot a questioning look at him, before realizing what his plan was.

"Incendio," she cast, pointing her wand at Milo's oilslick. The lantern oil erupted in flame, which quickly spread to the great oak tree. There wasn't enough flammable material to create anything so impressive as a wall of fire, but it did create a lot of smoke. Fortunately for the paint-based residents of Hogwarts, all of the living portraits had fled the area at Hermione's instructions earlier; unfortunately, their homes were caught in the inferno. The Troll was blinded by smoke, and started coughing hoarsely as it flailed its fists around.

"What about wind? Harry asked. "We need as much dust in there as possible."

"Well, there's the Gust Jinx," admitted Hermione skeptically, "but it's advanced. third-year."

"Hermione, can you cast it or not?" Harry pushed.

"Well... I've read about it," she said hesitantly. "I've never, you know, actually tried it."

"No pressure or anything," urged Ron, "but if you mess up, we'll probably all die."

Hermione's forehead wrinkled in concentration. She very carefully (and slowly) placed her feet in the fencing-like casting position used when performing complicated magic, and pictured the page in The Standard Book of Spells, Volume 3 that described the wand motions.

"Swish, flick, counter-swirl, three-quarters-twirl-clockwise, diamond-inside-a-circle, VENTUS!"

It started gradually, building up strength somewhere behind Hermione. She felt her robes stir gently, and her hair started to rustle. At first, she thought she must have botched the spell (a thought which mortified her to her core), and then it happened.

There was a rush of air that nearly knocked her from her feet, whipping her curly hair around her head. Dust from the ruined hallway was picked up from the walls, floors, the children's clothes, and from under the heavy masonry. Hermione thought Harry's plan was to fan the flames with more air, until...

o—o—o—o

The third-floor window that Milo had flown out of exploded. A blossom of red fire erupted from the remains of the frame, leaving spots in Hannah's eyes.

"That," she said, "can't be good." She drew her wand anxiously, but wasn't sure, exactly, what she should be doing with it. She was, technically, a witch... but needing magic for a potentially life-or-death situation wasn't something she thought would ever happen. In fact, needing magic for anything outside of class had simply never occurred to her. Imagine suddenly finding yourself having to calculate how long it would take a sedan accelerating at 6 m/s2 to a maximum of 80 km/h to catch up to a truck moving at 60 km/h with a forty-five-minute head start... to save the Prime Minister.

That, in a nutshell, is what Hannah felt like.

First things first, she thought, deal with the unconscious boy. What Hannah didn't know was that Milo, not simply unconscious, was, in fact, dying. Every six seconds he'd drop one hit point until hitting negative ten, when he'd buy the proverbial Outer Plane farm.

That leaves her, for those of you keeping score, fifty-four seconds to stabilize him.

Fifty-three...

Fifty-two...

"Uh, I should, uh, probably get you to the hostpital—uh, hopsital, uh. Ah. Hospital wing," she said. In another life, Hannah was a Hufflepuff. And Hufflepuffs, not that there's anything wrong with them, wonderful, wonderful people, are not typically noted (with the notable exception of the dreamy third-year Cedric Diggory) for keeping their heads in a crisis.

"Locomotor Mortis!" she cast, and Milo's legs locked together.

Forty-two...

"No, wait! Wrong spell, I'm sorry!" she stressed. It was that last bit, the Mortis part. "Locomotor Milo!" she cast, and Milo floated into the air.

Thirty-six...

"Uh, maybe I should counter that Leg-Locker Curse, now that I think about it," she said. "Finite Incantatem," she cast. Milo fell back to the ground.

Thirty...

"Oh, of course, that cancelled Locomotor as well. Locomotor Milo!" she cast again.

Twenty-four...

"Well, to the Hospital Wing it is, then!" she said, and set off. Milo drifted along behind her.

Twenty-three...

Twenty-two...

o—o—o—o

"Which one of you used the Blasting Charm?" Hermione asked, stunned, as she picked herself up from the rubble.

"What?" asked Ron.

"I said, which one of you used the Blasting Charm," she repeated loudly.

"What?" asked Ron, who had been deafened by the blast.

"Nobody here knows the Blasting Charm, Hermione," said Harry weakly. He'd been thrown halfway across the room in the explosion.

"What?"

"Then, what spell was that?"

"What?"

"No spell," said Harry.

"What?" said Hermione and Ron simultaneously.

"Well, this one time Dudley fell asleep watching cartoons and I got to watch Discovery," Harry said, "hiding in my cupboard, of course, in case my Aunt or Uncle saw, and it turns out if you throw enough dust at a fire, it, well, it—"

"—explodes?" finished Hermione.

"What?"

"Yeah, basically. That's why I asked you to conjure up a windstorm."

"What?"

"That's clever. I strongly disapprove, you broke about a thousand school rules, and maybe my ribs; also, I know for a fact 'no explosions in the hallways—NO EXCEPTIONS' is a rule, I saw it posted outside Filch's office, but it was clever, but sometimes even when a plan is clever, even when it's really clever, you should really warn me when you're going to blow something up."

"I'll do that next time," said Harry.

"What?"

"Oh, shut up, Ron!" snapped Hermione.

"What?"

"I know you can't hear me, but what you really expect to gain by saying 'what?' over and over I don't even—"

Hermione was cut off when a huge, ugly, scorched hand reached out from the smoke and picked her up by the shoulder. She reflexively reached for her wand, but realized she'd dropped it in the explosion.

The Troll held her up close to its face, gazing at her with a curious expression. Then it opened its gaping maw. A fell odour of rotting meat and extreme halitosis blasted her senses.

"Uh, please don't eat me, Mr. Troll..." she begged.

Instead of eating her or charging down the injured Ron and Harry, the Troll decided to take a third option.

o—o—o—o

Snape waited. Quirrell, Snape knew (though he could not see him), was likely deciding what to do about Hagrid's dog. Whatever action he took would be proof enough for Snape to bring Dumbledore, or even the Ministry, down on him.

Any moment now, the Defence Professor would kill the dog.

Unexpectedly, nothing happened.

What is he doing? Snape wondered. Then the Troll made an entrance.

Literally.

Stone bricks flew across the room when Quirrell's beast tore its way through the wall as if it were made of paper, carrying the Granger girl in one hand as if she were a rag doll.

The Cerberus awoke and leapt. Snape, though he would never admit it, was reminded of the time he'd seen Godzilla Versus Mothra as a boy.

Stunned, Snape fumbled for his wand while the Cerberus collided with the Troll, knocking it to the ground. Granger was tossed across the room, and slid limply along the ground. She didn't move.

The Troll wrestled the larger beast off of it and grabbed an enormous flagstone that used to make up part of the third floor's ceiling. With a mighty heave, it brought the heavy chunk of stone down on one of the hound's heads. There was a sickening crunch, and the other two heads led out bellows of rage; blood and spit speckling the Troll. The Cerberus raked the Troll with sharp claws, gouging thick slashes in its tough hide. One of is heads went for the Troll's neck, but the Troll managed to wrestle its jaws open with its hands; the other head went for Granger.

Snape began to cast a spell, but someone beat him to it.

"Avada Kedavra," Snape heard someone say, and there was a blinding green flash. The Cerberus lay dead, and Quirrell stood in the centre of the room.

"A-a-are you a-alright, Miss G-G-Granger?" Quirrell asked, his voice full of concern. When Hermione didn't respond, Quirrell frantically tore a strip of cloth from his robe and tied it around her bleeding head.

"Episkey," he cast, and several of her smaller cuts and injuries healed rapidly. "I'm s-s-sorry," he said, "that's the b-b-best I c-can do until h-help arrives."

Quirrell, Snape noticed, never seemed to stammer when casting a spell. Well, at least now his plan is clear. Really, it was obvious in hindsight, Snape sighed. He should have seen it coming. Quirrell released the Troll not only as a distraction, but as an excuse to enter the forbidden corridor and kill Fluffy. He used a Forbidden Curse, but even those were technically legal against non-humans. It did further cement Snape's view that Quirrell had gone Dark, however. On top of everything, Quirrell would now be a hero in everyone's eyes. What this had to do with Milo, however, Snape still couldn't figure out.

Wait, he thought, why was the Troll holding Miss Granger?

He paused. Granger must have been in the hallways, and where there's Granger...

...there's Harry Potter.

Climbing over debris and deceased dog, Snape rushed through the Troll's wall entrance. The Troll itself lay gasping for breath under the hound's body.

Outside, in the hallway, was an... interesting sight. The window had been blown open, taking much of the surrounding frame with it. The ceiling had not one, but two troll-sized holes in it; one of them was at least mostly filled... by a great oak tree, which was, incidentally, on fire. Just down the hallway was another flattened wall, where the Troll had first entered. The sheer level of damage was unlike anything Snape had ever seen before—not even Fred and George... not even James and Sirius had ever... no-one, so far as Snape knew, had ever done so much raw, physical damage to the Hogwarts school in a thousand years, much less under a minute.

Surely, the Dark Lord's hand must be at work, here...

Snape shook himself out of his reverie, and began searching for Potter. The boy must live, everything—and everyone—else was expendable. Dimly, he was aware of movement behind him.

There was a brief, blinding flash as Dumbledore arrived, carried by his fiery bird.

"You can come out, now," said the Headmaster. The eccentric Headmaster, it seemed, had not taken Hallowe'en lightly, and was wearing an uncharacteristically sombre gray robe and hat. Of all things, a sword was buckled to his side. At first, Snape thought Dumbledore had directed the remark at him, but the Headmaster looked right at him and winked.

The Troll, burnt and bloody, staggered out of the forbidden third-floor corridor.

"You have damaged my school," the Headmaster said gravely. "You have injured my students." The Troll cocked its head to the side, as if it actually understood what he was saying. "And for these things that you have done," the Headmaster continued, "you will leave. Now."

There was no threat, just a simple statement of fact. The Troll stared at the Headmaster blankly.

"Fly, you fool," Dumbledore said quietly. The Troll turned and leapt out the window. Snape, dismissing his Disillusionment Charm, walked over to the edge. The Troll was running towards the Forbidden Forest as fast as it could go.

"Professor," Snape heard a weak voice from behind them. Dumbledore turned to see Harry and Ron lying, partially buried by (surprisingly dust-free) stone bricks.

"Mr. Potter! Mr. Weasley! We have to get you to the hospital wing at once!" the Headmaster said in alarm.

"No, worry about us later," Harry said stoically. "Milo... was thrown out the window. He—I'm sure he—"

"Say no more, I'll take care of it," Dumbledore said reassuringly. "Snape, make sure these two—and Miss Granger, she should be around here somewhere—get to the hospital wing." With that, and a flash, he and his Phoenix vanished as quickly as they'd appeared.

o—o—o—o

"W-w-w-wingard... Wing... Wingardium Leviosa!" Hannah shouted, lifting Milo into the sky. She was sure—okay, pretty sure—okay, she hoped she'd found the window to the hospital wing.

Ten...

Milo slowly floated up to the fourth-storey window. Hannah hoped that someone inside would see him and help.

Nine...

She considered sending up sparks with her wand, or even using magic to break the window, but she wasn't sure she could do that and hold Milo at the same time.

Eight...

On the other hand, if necessary, she could always just shove him through the window.

Seven...

What would that accomplish? If there's nobody in there, there won't be anyone to help him.

Six...

Milo dropped to -9 hit points, not that Hannah knew that.

Five...

I'm sure someone will notice him eventually.

Four...

Though I'm not sure for how long I can keep this levitate running.

Three...

There was a loud Crack and a blinding flash. Dumbledore appeared in front of her, with a fiery bird perched on his shoulder.

Two...

Hannah's concentration broke, and abruptly she felt the strain of her Levitation Charm vanish. Milo, no longer protected by his Feather Fall, started to fall to the ground. Fawkes, with a mighty cry, leapt from Dumbledore's shoulder and flew towards the falling boy.

One...

o—o—o—o

Milo awoke to an all-too-familiar ceiling. He heard raised voices from the other side of the curtain surrounding his hospital bunk. He felt... well, pretty great, actually. It was sort of hard to put his finger on.

"No, I don't know when he'll wake up!" said the frustrated voice of Madam Pomfrey.

"You are a mediwitch, aren't you?" said the stern voice of McGonagall.

"Yes, and I'm fully trained and qualified to heal humans. What he is, I don't even—"

"So you're telling me you don't have a clue whether he's going to live or die."

"I'm telling you that he's survived life threatening injuries in the past; I don't even know if he can die."

"Uh," Milo said cheerfully. "I'm awake! Hello?"

Abruptly, the curtain was drawn back from around his bed. McGonagall looked concerned, and Pomfrey looked terrified.

"Wh-what, already?" she asked, trembling. "You should have been... I mean, you shouldn't have..."

"What Madam Pomfrey is trying to say," said McGonagall, "is that we're very relieved to hear that you're all right."

"Yup, just dandy. Can anyone tell me what happened? The last thing I remember is nearly killing myself casting Feather Fall... of all the ways to die, I think that would have been the most humiliating. I can't believe it actually was the fall that killed me."

"Do you mean to tell me that you were performing dangerous magic—" McGonagall started, but Pomfrey cut her off.

"Well, I can only assume we have Fawkes to thank," said the mediwitch. "although as to why the Headmaster's been keeping a miracle cure like Phoenix Tears locked away in his office, I suppose I'll have to bring that up with him..." she said, trailing off into a series of angry grumbles. Milo thought he caught the words "puts me completely out of the job" and "could have saved that Longbottom boy a world of hurt"

"Uh," said Milo, "could anyone tell me what happened to the Troll?"

"Professor Dumbledore drove it away," said McGonagall. "I believe it's likely still running, actually. Although your friends performed more than their share of Gryffindor heroism, and, not that I'd like to encourage this sort of thing, together you've all earned more than enough points to offset your... unruly... behaviour."

"How come I'm not dead?" Milo asked, bluntly.

"Miss Abbot carried you back to the castle, and I rather think she was about to break the door down when the Headmaster found you—his Phoenix, Fawkes, has certain powerful healing abilities. She's quite distraught, in fact, and has hardly left your side."

"I don't suppose you could tell us why you're awake?" asked Pomfrey. "Everything I know tells me you should have either been completely restored when the Phoenix healed you, or, failing that, unconscious for days. It's only been three hours."

"Well, I've got a hit point. If I had to guess, that Phoenix cured me into the positives, and I was just sleeping since then. It was your shouting that woke me up. Still, I feel sort of... weird."

Madam Pomfrey frowned.

"Lumos," she whispered. "Right, follow my wand with your eyes..." she waved the wand slowly back in front of his face. When he, presumably, responded normally; she followed up with a number of diagnostic spells.

"Look, I feel fine," he said. "Better than fine, actually; sort of like... I could go toe-to-toe with a Ghoul or armwrestle a Bugbear. Like I could be or do... well, anything. Like I'm full of untapped potential..."

"Well, Phoenixes have been known to have a sort of euphoric effect—"

"No, it's not that. I think... I think I... my gods!" he said as he realized what had happened.

"What?" asked McGonagall, alarmed.

"I've levelled up!" It had never happened while he was unconscious before. "Leave me alone for a minute, I need to pick skills."

McGonagall gave him a peculiar look and turned to leave with Madam Pomfrey, but Milo ignored them both.

"Oh, by the way," said Madam Pomfrey as she left. "You're not to leave your bed for at least 24 hours."

"Sure, whatever," Milo said absently.

Skills is easy, Milo thought. I'll just add another rank in what I've already got. As for feats...

This part was really difficult for Milo. As a level five Wizard, he got a bonus metamagic or item creation feat. Under normal circumstances I'd go for Extend Spell, but...

I might have to face the fact that I'm going to be stuck here for a while, Milo thought bitterly. I have to be self-sufficient. I have to be a whole party, a whole economy, by myself. If I keep being tossed into encounters above my ECL like this, I'm going to wind up dead.

What are my assets?

I have time.

With Harry Potter, I have money.

Feeling somewhat sick, Milo did something he swore he would never, ever do. Mentally, he wrote down "Craft Wondrous Item" on the character sheet in his mind.

If I ever get to go home, he reassured himself, I'll just retrain it.

When it came to spells, Milo felt like he might cry. I only get two. How can I live with only two?! There are dozens of third level spells I absolutely have to have. Haste. Fireball. Shrink Item. Fly. Summon Monster III. Heroics. With tears in his eyes, Milo chose Fly and Summon Monster III. Next level, he promised himself. Next level, I learn something that goes boom.

"What was that?" Milo heard a familiar voice.

"Sorry, Nev. This place has me talking to myself," Milo said.

"It's not so bad," he heard Neville say from next cot over. "Though I'd like to try sleeping in our dorm once, if only for the novelty of it."

"You've never slept in Gryffindor Tower?" Milo heard Hermione say.

"Blimey," said Ron. "Now that I think about it, I don't think I've ever seen him in there."

"My suitcase isn't even unpacked," Neville said sadly.

Milo looked around. Harry, Ron, and Hermione were all lying in hospital beds as well. Hermione's bushy brown hair was hidden by thick bandages around her head, with more wrapped around her chest. Harry and Ron were similarly bandaged, albeit to a lesser extent.

"Holy crap," Milo said, stunned. "What happened to you guys?"

As they filled him in on the events of their day (Milo was stunned at the revelation that dust could explode; the possible applications for that were endless. Okay, well, really there was only one application for it, and that was for making things go boom on the cheap.) That these three "wizards" very nearly took out that "Troll" made Milo's respect for them go up several notches.

"So all they were keeping in the chamber of die-a-horrible-death was a gigantic three-headed dog?" Milo asked. "Huh. I always had it figured for the Philosopher's Stone. Guess that explains why Hogwarts had a gigantic ultra-secure cage, though."

As Milo was talking, the door to the hospital wing opened.

Hannah Abbot, in full rabbit regalia, entered, followed by a hovering trolley covered in food.

"Seeing as how you're missing the Hallowe'en feast," she said, "McGonagall made a special exemption and let me bring the feast to you. Also," she added, "you lot—Milo excluded, of course; very spooky as a Dementor—wouldn't be allowed in there without a costume, anyway."

The eyes on Harry's, Ron's, Hermione's, and Neville's eyes lit up simultaneously. Milo shrugged and reached for his Everlasting Rations.

"She also said to tell you that it came with a twenty Gryffindor House Points for each of you (except you, Neville, sorry), and five for me," she said happily. "Oh, also," she said, looking archly at Milo. "If you even think about eating those bland, tasteless Rations, I will personally throw you through another window."

Ron choked slightly.

"McGonagall said that?"

"No," said Hannah. "That was me."

Hannah walked past her grievously injured friends, passing out plates piled high with food. Milo felt that elaborate descriptions were in order, but, frankly, he didn't know what three-quarters of the stuff was even called. Hannah sat down on the bed next to Milo and passed him a plate.

Milo sniffed it suspiciously.

"Detect Poison," he muttered. Everything looked clean (except Neville, who still had enough poison in him to be flagged as 'poisonous'), but that paradoxically only made him more nervous. The poison might be really well hidden...

"Oh, just eat it," Hannah said. "What could happen? You're already in the hospital wing."

"Fine," Milo said reluctantly. He took a tiny bite of something sort of orange-ish. His hand was already reaching for Antitoxin before he finished chewing, but, surprisingly, he felt fine.

"Hey," he said, stunned. "This... this is pretty good."

"See? I told you so," Hannah said with a grin. Where Milo came from, taste was only ever described when it was dramatically required, but here... everything was so full of flavour, even—or, perhaps, especially—when it was completely inconsequential.

"Beans," he said suddenly.

"Sorry, what was that, mate?" Ron asked.

"The Gringotts Every-Flavoured Beans," Milo said. "I want some. Now."

"They're Bertie Botts Every-Flavoured Beans," Ron muttered. "And there's a box on the trolley, but, blimey, Harry made me swear to warn anyone before their first time—"

"I can handle it," Milo said, grabbing the box. He licked his lips hungrily and downed a handful at a time.

Milo passed out from sensory overload.

"This," said Harry as Milo came to, "was the best Hallowe'en ever. Normally, the Muggles only let me have the candies they took from Dudley because they think they have razor blades in them."

Milo was forced to agree, and not only because it was the only Hallowe'en he'd ever had. He'd fought monsters, survived by the skin of his teeth, levelled up, discovered the wonders of a whole new sense, and felt, for the first time in a long time, like he was part of a party again.

It was, rather, like coming home.

Chapter 12: Of Rats and Bowler Caps

Author's Notes: Milo's new level five character sheet can be found here: ?sheetid=421496. because Fanfiction seems to dislike entire URLS.

Thanks to everyone for your nice reviews! If this story were a Wizard, those reviews would be his spells per day.

o—o—o—o

Harry and Ron were released on Friday evening, but Milo and Hermione were obliged to stay in the hospital wing for the weekend. Gryffindor (and even a few Hufflepuff and Ravenclaw) well-wishers had brought in flowers, candy, and cards to speed their recovery. Milo wondered idly where the students had got them from, because it wasn't like there were any shops in the castle, and students couldn't just leave the grounds.

"Owl-order," answered Hermione when he asked on Sunday evening. "Also, third-years and above can go to Hogsmeade a few times a year."

Milo was disappointed at how... mundane the answer was, but liked the sound of the Hogsmeade trips once he hit third year...

Milo cut off that line of thought quickly. There's no way I'm still going to be here in two years, he thought firmly. Why, Zook and the others are probably already paying to have a whole battery of Divinations cast to find out where I am.

Totally.

...and the reason that's been two months, why, they're probably just trying to find a really good Diviner to do it. Yeah. Totally. Or a Conjurer to Plane Shift me home.

Milo sighed.

They could have at least sent a Sending once in a while, is that too much to ask?

Of course, this all assumes they weren't TPK'd by Thamior because they didn't have me to do, well, everything.

"Why the long face?" Hermione asked, full of concern.

"I think," said Milo, "that all of my friends back home might be dead."

"What?" she asked, her face gone white. "That's terrible! What... why... who... Oh, Milo, I'm sorry. I'm so sorry; that's about the worst thing I've ever heard."

Milo blinked. He'd forgotten that the people here seemed to view death as more than a mild inconvenience.

"It's not so bad," he said. "I mean, this isn't the first time it's happened."

"You don't have to put on such a brave face," she said. "It's only me."

"Where I come from, you can pay to have people brought back from the dead," Milo said simply. "It's really not such a big deal."

Hermione just stared, thunderstruck.

"That's... so..." Hermione paused to collect her thoughts. "You really are from another world, aren't you?"

"Yeah," Milo said quietly. "Everything was really—"

"Hey!" Milo heard a small, sharp voice say.

"Uh, Hermione, did you say something?" Milo asked

"Listen!" the voice said.

"What?" Milo asked, irritated. Milo got a flash of Irritation, Frustration, Annoyance from his empathic bond. "Mordy? Was that you? Since when can you talk?"

"It's amazing, really, it is," the voice (presumably Mordy) said. "You remembered to put a skill rank in Decipher Script, as if you'll ever find any use for that, but you forgot that I got the Speak With Master ability?" Mordy crawled out of his home in Milo's bag, and up his robes to talk to him face-to-face. Hermione had an odd look on her face, watching the exchange.

"Well, I feel like that's more your business to keep track of—" Milo protested weakly.

"I'm your class feature," said Mordy firmly. "Bet you forgot my Natural Armour increased, too, didn't you? No, don't tell me; I don't think my poor, adorable little rodent heart could take it."

"Yes, well, but—"

"And it's been ages since I got any share of the loot," Mordenkainen continued as if Milo hadn't spoken.

"Share of the—"

"That's right, my fair share of the loot. I do all the most dangerous jobs—distracting the Troll, spying on Snape's secret meeting with Lucius—"

"Wait, what—"

"—and what do I get in return?"

"Supernatural power above and beyond that of an ordinary rat, humanlike Intelligence, magical knowledge rivalling my own, the Skill Ranks of a level five Wizard—but that's beside the point. What's this about Snape's secret meeting?"

"Right after you were doing your 'Crime Scene Investigating' in the Forbidden Forest—I'm sorry, are you not taking me seriously? You're laughing."

"It's hard to maintain a straight face," Milo said between laughs, "when you see a rat make little air-quotes like that."

"Stay on topic, would you? Snape snuck out to meet the Smarmy Git's father, before you ask, yes, I could tell by his scent who he was but also because the Oily One called him 'Lucius Malfoy.'"

"And? What did they talk about?" Milo asked, intrigued.

"You know, I got mauled by a cat once, helping you," Mordy said.

"What happened to 'Stay on topic?'" Milo asked.

"I just wanted you to appreciate how difficult my job is, sometimes."

"Yes, yes, you're very appreciated, now get on with it."

"Well, the Sire of Smarm told the Oily One that you weren't a wizard—"

"Not a Wizard?" Milo asked, enraged. "I will end him! I'll show him which one of us isn't a Wizard when I shove some high-powered arcana down his—"

"—and that he wants the Oily One to have you expelled."

"...Huh," said Milo flatly. "Expelled? That's it?" From where he was from, enemies generally wanted you, dead, undead, re-dead, disgraced, disintegrated, detained, and/or devoured. Being expelled seemed so... unimportant. "It must only be Phase One of his plan. First, get me expelled, then, eaten by Bugbears."

"That's what I assumed as well. So, boss, what's the plan? Oh, before I forget, there's this one other th—"

"Okay," said Hermione, as if it had taken her this long to work up the courage to mention it. "What are you doing?"

"Talking to Mordenkainen," he said. "Can't you tell?"

"No," said Hermione. "It sounded like you were spouting gibberish. You can—wait, you can talk to rats? You're a... a... huh. I don't actually know if there's a word for that. A rodenttongue? Rattongue?"

"No, just to this one. I'm the one-and-only Mordytongue," Milo said. He'd forgotten that the Speak With Master ability magically prevented anyone from understanding what he said to Mordy, and vice-versa. Handy, he thought.

"So, what are you saying?" Hermione asked curiously. "Er, that was rude. I didn't meant to pry, or interrupt a conversation, or anything, it's just that it's not every day that—"

"Mordy was telling me that Snape and Lucius Malfoy met secretly in the forest," Milo explained, "and that Lucius asked Snape to get me expelled."

Hermione frowned.

"This was when you went to the forest to investigate the Acromantula?" Hermione asked. "I'd been meaning to ask—what did you end up finding?"

"The Acromantula had a missing fang," Milo said. "And that I couldn't have killed it with the log."

"But, that means..."

"Someone else must have done it, though I didn't see it happen. I would have thought it was Quirrell, but he was very clear about the fact that he was nowhere near the scene at the time. Also, the math on the Experience Points checks out if I split it fifty-fifty with a more experienced character than myself."

Hermione blinked.

"You know, when I was in school, people said I was weird."

"Must be nice," Milo said, "to have a backstory. Seems like a lot of work, mind."

"You... you don't remember your childhood at all?"Hermione was shocked.

"Before I became an adventurer? Not really. I know that at some point, I became a vagabond street thief, but I'm not really sure how that happened."

"But that's so sad," Hermione said, her eyes misting up.

"It let me become a Wizard younger," Milo said. "It's sort of complicated, and it doesn't stand up to close inspection. It's... weird. For me. This only became a problem when I came to this world, it's like... I'm cut off from something. I don't suppose we can change the subject?"

"What were we talking about?" Hermione asked. "Oh, right. Snape trying to get you expelled. Only Professor McGonagall and Professor Dumbledore have the authority for that," she said, "short of the Minister for Magic stepping in personally. It's out of Snape's hands."

"I guess Snape could try to set it up so that they had no choice but to—aw, crap. The potion."

"Milo!" Hermione said. "Language!" she paused for a moment. "Also, what potion?"

"For Snape's detention on Hallowe'en," Milo said. "I thought he was trying to kill me, having me make an exploding potion, but it was a test. I failed."

"Failing Potions isn't enough to have you expelled," Hermione said. "I mean, take Neville."

"Hey!" said Neville from his bunk. He was back in the hospital wing after being mauled by (and they wouldn't have believed it if there hadn't been twelve witnesses) a Flobberworm. Flobberworms have no teeth, fangs, spikes, poison, spit, anything. Their one claim to fame is their (harmless) slimy mucous. They'd quite forgotten about him.

"Sorry, Nev," Hermione said, her face pink.

"No, it's not just about being even more hopelessly incompetent than Neville," Milo said as if Neville hadn't spoken. PCs could be like that around NPCs, sometimes. "Snape told me himself: a newborn with a hint of magical blood could make that potion. All you have to do is stir it, you don't need to think about it or concentrate or anything."

"So?" asked Hermione. "What's your point?"

"I couldn't make the potion," Milo said quietly.

There was a meaningful silence.

"Maybe you had the ingredients wrong?" asked Hermione.

"No, they were perfect. Snape even checked them beforehand. It's not like I kept it a secret, I'm not a wizard like you are."

"Witch, actually," said Hermione pointedly.

"But the only thing keeping me here is that Dumbledore thinks I'm like you," said Milo, "only crazy and deluded—and even worse at magic than Neville."

"Hey!"

"No, that can't be," said Hermione. "If you weren't a wizard, the wards wouldn't let you enter Hogsmeade or Hogwarts. You'd suddenly remember an important meeting and run off, I believe."

"I suppose it depends on the exact wording of the spell. Maybe the wards target everyone who isn't 'a wizard, witch, squib, or magical creature,' or something. I don't suppose you have the spell description in the library?"

"Uh," said Hermione. "I... don't think so."

"More importantly, I've..." Milo's tongue tripped over itself. "I've..." he sighed. "I've already lost. Snape won. I'm going to be expelled."

"No, I think it would take more than Snape's word for something like this. It's completely unprecedented; the Ministry will want to be involved, Dumbledore too—and McGonagall, of course—the department that handles underage magic... the point is, I don't think we need to worry until ministry officials start showing up—"

"Hello!" said a cheerful voice, interrupting Hermione mid-sentence. Milo turned to see a portly (one) little (two) man in a pinstriped cloak and green bowler cap (three! Major NPC) standing at the entrance to the hospital wing.

Hermione gasped, her face completely white.

"Erm," said Milo. "Hello, ah, sir?" he was guessing wildly, but judging by Hermione's reaction, this was either a local king, evil vizier, or Lord Voldemort himself. Milo carefully re-arranged his blankets so they wouldn't impede him if he made a run for the window, and stuffed Mordenkainen back into his belt.

"Oh, that won't be necessary," said the man. "I'm Cornelius Fudge, the Minister for Magic."

Milo blinked.

Aw, crap.

"M-M-Milo Amastacia—"

"—Liadon," Fudge interrupted as he moved to sit next to Milo. "Yes, yes, I know who you are."

Milo licked his lips, which had gone suddenly dry. He wouldn't be up to full hit points until midnight, when his second day of full bed rest finished. He slowly pulled both hands out from under his blankets so they wouldn't interfere with Somatic spell components. This man, as Milo understood it, was king of an entire country of wizards. He probably had access to enough Arcane power to rewrite reality according to his whims.

"I'm afraid there's been a spot of trouble," the Minister said. "I'm sure it's nothing, but it has a lot of us at the Ministry scratching our heads. I'm here with some colleagues—who are waiting in the hall; your mediwitch was quite... severe with them, demanded no more than one of us be let in at a time—who are here to sort it out and solve the little mystery. Shouldn't take more than a moment, really."

Hermione shot Milo a look of absolute panic.

"H-how can I help, m-m-my lord?" Milo asked.

"Really now," said Fudge, "I'm not a lord, you know."

"F-forgive me, your Divine Imperial Majesty!"

The fat little man sighed and removed his bowler cap.

"Just Mister Fudge will do, Milo. And to answer your question earlier, all you have to do is follow me, answer a few questions, and brew a potion. We can have you back to your bed and friends in a few minutes."

Milo panicked. It was the end of the day, and he was almost out of spells. He couldn't prepare new ones until Monday.

"I, ah, I'd love to but I'm afraid I'm... I'm grievously injured," Milo stammered. "I was thrown out a window just the other day, you know?"

"The lovely Ms. Pomfrey assures me that you're in good enough shape to move about, if only for a short time," said Fudge. "And I'm afraid I have to insist. It's quite out of my hands, you see..."

"But you're the—" Milo said, before remembering who he was talking to. Fudge could probably lay waste to armies with a wave of his hand. "...okay. I'll go with you," he said meekly.

"Good lad!" said the Minister as Milo climbed to his feet.

"I want to go with him," Hermione said firmly.

"Er," said the Minister. "Well, shouldn't you stay here and rest?"

"No," she insisted. "I'll be fine, Pomfrey is just being over-protective. I'm not letting him go anywhere alone—you wouldn't believe what happens." Milo grinned; it looked like she was finally grasping Adventurer Rule One: you never split the party.

"Well, um, very well, but let it be known this wasn't my idea."

Hermione weakly struggled to her feet. Her head was still tightly bandaged, as was her chest. From what Milo could understand, witches and wizards—and Muggles, too, likely—had a completely different healing process from what he was familiar with.

Milo moved next to Hermione (just in case) and together they followed the Minister for Magic. Outside the hospital wing's large double doors were four of his flunkies.

"These are my colleagues," Fudge gestured at his underlings, "Mafilda Hopkirk from the Improper Use of Magic Office," he said, pointing at a stern, gray-haired witch, "Dolores Umbridge, Senior Undersecretary to the Minister for Magic," Fudge pointed at what Milo could only assume to be a Half-Toad clad all in pink, "and Broderick Bode of the Department of Mysteries," Fudge pointed at a sallow-skinned wizard. "In the back there is Walden Macnair of the, er, the Department for the Regulation and Control of Magical Creatures. I'm sure he won't be necessary." Fudge pointed at a huge wizard standing head-and-shoulders taller than the others.

"This the little beastie?" Macnair asked in a low rumble.

"Well," said Fudge awkwardly. "That, er, has, ah, yet to be determined. If you'll all follow me?" Fudge asked, with a small gesture. Milo frowned. Is his timid incompetence an act, as obfuscation? Or is he really this anxious all the time? If so, how did he become ruler of en empire of what are, essentially, demigods?

He can't have, Milo realized. Either he's a brilliant chessmaster behind this facade, or...

Fudge led the group into the dungeons, but Milo barely noticed.

...or someone else is the real power behind the throne. But is it Dumbledore, Lucius, Voldemort, or some third party?

Either way, I really need to figure out how to pass Snape's test.

It wasn't that impossible, really. All he had to do was get a cauldron to bubble instead of exploding.

The only catch was that he hardly had any spells left; he'd been using Scholar's Touch to catch up on his reading.

Milo ran his fingers through his hair. He hadn't quite realized how vulnerable that made him at night.

"How long is it to midnight?" he asked Hermione, who checked her watch.

"Less than two hours," she said with a yawn. "It's way past my bedtime."

Milo chewed his lip. He had a plan, of sorts. He just had to delay until midnight, and then delay for an hour while he prepared spells. And then he had to figure out how to make a handful of spells designed for killing orcs in ten-by-ten stone rooms do something they were never intended to.

All the while with the most powerful men in the country breathing down his neck.

Wonderful.

"I'm sure if you just double-check your measuring," Hermione said in an attempt to be reassuring, "you'll do fine."

Milo grinned nervously, then steeled himself. He had the beginnings of a plan in mind, but for that he would need spells.

"So, erm, Milo my boy, where did you say you came from?" Fudge asked.

"Myra," Milo said proudly. "City of light! City of Magic!" The Myrari government, though completely inept at dealing with dragons, goblins, and bandits, nonetheless had a sophisticated system of Divinations set up to detect citizens who didn't add the legally-mandated city motto after saying the city's name. Milo wasn't sure exactly how far-reaching the effects were, so even here he made sure to say it—and, for that matter, think it. Nobody knew exactly what the punishment was for breaking that particular law, because nobody knew anyone who had ever done it.

Personally, Milo suspected that lawbreakers were retroactively erased from the timeline altogether.

"Where is that, exactly?" asked Fudge. "America? Europe?"

"Uh," said Milo. He wasn't sure, exactly, how secret he was supposed to keep his otherworldy nature. On the other hand, Fudge was probably watching him with a battery of Divinations (or whatever the local equivalent was called) to catch him lying. So, I can't tell the truth, and I probably can't tell a lie. "No," Milo said. "Not America or Europe." And now I need a diversion... "Did you see that ludicrous display last week?"

"I daresay! I had more Galleons riding on a Wanderer's victory than were in the Spanish Armada," Fudge said. "Mind, the Cannons were all riding Nimbus Two Thousands," he said. "That must have been the reason. Donated at the last minute by an anonymous benefactor. The Wanderers, though; rumour has it they were on an experimental new broom. Must have been rubbish, though."

Milo's curiosity was perked. If there's one thing every adventurer listens to, it's unfounded rumours told by fat little men. He knew his present situation was dire, but he just had to dig for more information.

"An experimental broom?" Milo asked.

"So I'd heard. Made by a total unknown in Wales somewhere, doesn't even have a proper name yet. It's all very hush-hush, even to me—and I'm the Minister!"

"So, your, ah, Ministership, sir, do you have any guesses about who donated all the broomsticks?"

"Off the record? There's only one family with the wealth and influence to afford a team's set of Nimbuses with a vested interest in seeing the broomstick succeed," Fudge said conspiratorially, "and that's the Malfoys. Mr. Malfoy is on the Nimbus board of directors, you know."

Milo had no idea what a board of directors was, but he didn't care. Everything he heard seemed to be pointing to that family: the manor he first woke up in, Draco's very existence (and at the exact same age as him, too), Lucius in the forest —and wasn't Draco taunting him about Quidditch just the other day?

Milo knew an adventure hook when he saw one.

Later, Milo thought. First, I need to avoid being expelled. Expulsion would be inconvenient and annoying, but it wasn't as if Milo had any vested interest in obtaining a magic education in the wrong sort of magic. Mostly, he just wanted to stay in Hogwarts because Lucius, for some reason, wanted him out.

"Ah, here we are," said Fudge as they approached Snape's classroom in the dungeons. "You know, when I attended this school, this was where they used to lock us when we misbehaved. Ah, the joys of youth."

Without even being prompted, Macnair and Bode each opened one of the double doors, allowing Fudge to enter. Milo was still unsure if the man's bumbling nature was an act or not.

Milo and Hermione followed, with Fudge's underlings behind them.

Dumbledore, McGonagall, Snape, and a small group of men Milo didn't recognize were waiting in the classroom for them. Something about the way the group of men stood, and the fact that they were all dressed the same, made Milo think they were some form of wizard police or military. What was the word for that? They had a word for that¸ Milo thought, trying to remember. It was in one of the books he'd read with Scholar's Touch.

Sitting in the middle of the classroom was a small, pewter cauldron. Next to it were the ingredients, such as they were, for Snape's test potion. Snape looked excited, McGonagall worried, and Dumbledore as enigmatic as always.

"In accordance with Section Thirty-Two-Point-One-Four-One-Alpha of the 1634 Statute on Inexplicable Phenomena of a Magical Nature," Umbridge declared in an authoritative voice, reading from a scroll she'd been carrying somewhere on her person, "which states, in the words of the Great Wizard Peabody, 'When something really, really, really wyrd happens, and hear ye me I do mean REALLY wyrd, and lo, it hath never happened before, and neither sir nor gentle lady knoweth what to do, let the goddamned Department of Mysteries handle it, y'hear? And forsooth, maketh sure there are at least a half-dozen Aurors around, if ye know what be good for ye,' the first preliminary inquiry to determine the nature of one entity known as 'Milo Amastacia-Liadon,' of a species yet to be determined, is to be convened, under the supervision of one Broderick Bode of the Department of Mysteries and in the presence of six fully-qualified Aurors of the Department of Magical Law Enforcement. Also in attendance are Hogwarts Professors Albus Dumbledore, Minerva McGonagall, and Severus Snape, Dolores Umbridge, Senior Undersecretary to the Minister for Magic, Cornelius Fudge, Minister for Magic, Walden McNair of the Department for the Regulation and Control of Magical Creatures, Mafilda Hopkirk from the Improper Use of Magic Office, and... Ms. Hermione Granger. The objective of the inquiry is 1) to determine the species of the individual in question, 2) if he turns out to be human, whether he is a wizard, squib, or... otherwise, 3) if not a wizard, determine how he got past the magical wards protecting this castle and the village known as Hogsmeade, 4)if not human, to turn the inquiries over to the Department for the Regulation and Control of Magical Creatures for study and, if deemed appropriate, execution. Let the inquisition commence."

Umbridge put away her parchment and stepped back.

Milo blinked. Well, he thought, this is unexpected. Bode, the strange, somber man from the Department of Mysteries moved forwards slightly.

"Now, Milo, I want you to understand that these are just preliminary inquiries. There are a lot of unanswered questions, and we're just going to try and see if they're worth looking into is all. That business about the execution is just a formality," he said in a dry voice. Milo had just started sighing with relief when he continued. "Unless, of course, you aren't human, and are some form of hitherto-undiscovered magical creature, in which case you'll be staked, beheaded, buried upside-down in sanctified concrete for a year and a day, then dug up, salted, shot with thirteen silver bullets, cremated, and Disapparated into the sun. In my experience, that'll kill anything short of a Dementor."

Milo laughed weakly.

"So," Milo said nervously. "How, exactly, are we going to go about this?"

"The first test is easy enough. Your Potions Master was good enough to brew us up some Veritaserum. You just have to drink a drop."

"And what will that do, exactly?" Milo asked.

"It'll make it impossible for you to tell a lie," Bode said.

"Okay, hit me," Milo said, and reached out. Snape, with a grin, produced a tiny vial of clear potion from his robes. For one brief, extremely embarrassing moment, Milo wished he were a Bard in order to cast Glibness. Snape poured out a single, tiny drop of Veritaserum into a glass of water, stirred it slowly, and passed it to Milo.

"Er," Milo asked. "How long will this last for? It's not permanent, is it?"

"Unfortunately," Snape said, "It will wear off in a few hours."

"Okay then," Milo said, and gulped the potion down in one go. To his surprise, it didn't really taste like anything, and he didn't even feel different. Dangerous, he thought. A colourless, tasteless potion that makes one tell the truth.

"Now," said Bode. "Are you a human?"

"Seriously?" Milo asked. "That's your test? Yes, I'm a human."

"What town or city are you from?"

"Myra (cityoflight!cityofMagic!)"

"And in which country is Myra situated?"

"The Azel Empire."

"And on which continent is this... Azel Empire located?"

"The Azel continent."

"Milo, are you, in fact, from another world?"

"Yes," Milo said simply. Feeling he had to elaborate, he continued rapidly, the words almost spilling over themselves in an effort to be said. "A few months ago, I was summoned, without warning, to a manor near the village I later learned was Hogsmeade by a group of Death Eaters—"

"Oh, surely we're not believing this nonsense?" interrupted Fudge rudely.

"I must remind you," Dumbledore said calmly, "that he is under the effects of Veritaserum."

"Then he must be deluded. His wild tales are proof of that—surely you can see that, Albus."

"We should wait for Bode to finish," Dumbledore said. "And then make a judgement."

"Very well. Carry on, then."

"Milo, I'll be as direct as I can here," Bode said. "Are you a Muggle?"

"No."

"Are you a Squib?"

"No."

"Are your parents wizards?"

"I don't know."

"Are you an orphan?"

"I don't know."

"Are you a wizard?"

"Hells yes I am," Milo said fiercely. "And anyone who says otherwise has another thing coming."

There was a low murmur from the Aurors present.

"Well, there you have it," Dumbledore said. "From his own mouth and under Veritaserum. I don't think this breach of my student's privacy has to go any further, do you?"

"He could be Confunded," Fudge said stubbornly. "In fact, I'd bet my hat that he is."

"If you were going to come to that conclusion in any case," Dumbledore said with a slight edge to his voice, "then, pray tell me, why bother questioning him at all?"

"The Board of Governors insisted, Dumbledore. It was out of my hands."

"I wonder how many of the Governors are under the impression—mistaken, I'm sure—that their families would be put in danger if they didn't insist?" Dumbledore asked.

"Albus!" Fudge gasped, sounding scandalized. "What are you suggesting?"

"Nothing," he said. "I was just thinking out loud. Don't mind me."

"As I am led to believe," Bode said. "Your Potions Master has developed a test which he believes can prove conclusively whether or not you do, in fact, possess any magic. Professor?"

Snape stood up from his desk. He looked... almost happy. Snape happy terrified Milo far more than Snape wrathful.

"Most conventional tests of magic," Snape said in a lecturing tone, "could be fooled if the subject is merely extremely incompetent or weak. Even the simplest of charms can be fumbled by the mentally deficient. That Milo is the worst student of magic to enter this school in a century at least is not in question. What remains to be seen is whether he possesses any magic at all."

Magic isn't a thing you just have, Milo thought angrily. It's something you have to work at. Something you earn. You have to take magic for yourself; it isn't simply handed to you.

"To that end, I have developed a test," Snape continued. "A potion that requires no thought, concentration, knowledge, or effort in the slightest. I will measure out the exact proportions of the ingredients, which will be checked by Albus Dumbledore and any others who wish to. All the boy has to do is pour them into the cauldron and stir once, counterclockwise. If the potion is created, he is a wizard. If not... it will explode, and I will leave him in the more than capable hands of the Ministry to deal with as you see fit." Snape's expression harboured no doubt about what he thought should be done with 'the boy.'

"Er, excuse me," Milo said. He could feel everyone's eyes on him. "Does anyone have the time?"

There was a brief silence. Eventually, Fudge fished a gold pocketwatch out from under his cloak.

"Half past eleven," Fudge said. "So could we hurry this up? Some of us have to be up early tomorrow."

This has to have been deliberate, Milo thought. Someone knows I have limited spells per day—they might even know that I routinely burn my remaining spell slots on Scholar's Touch before bed—and scheduled this accordingly. Why else would the Minister for Magic himself consent to an inquisition at this hour? Surely he has other things to be doing.

"I think it's been established that I'm rubbish at Potions," Milo said nervously. He had to kill time until he could prepare spells. "Would anyone mind if I did a quick read-through of my Potions textbook to make sure I did this right?"

"But you just have to stir it!" Fudge said exasperatedly.

"Better safe than sorry," Milo said. "If I mess up the stir, the whole experiment is void and I get buried in concrete. I might need the extra help. After all, 'help will always be given at Hogwarts—'"

"—To those who ask for it," Dumbledore finished his motto softly. "Very well," he said to the assembled government types, "I think the request is reasonable enough." Dumbledore said it without any particular weight to it, but somehow it was very clear that, even if he wasn't technically in charge here, his word on the matter was final.

"So I'll just run off and grab my text—"

"I don't think so," Bode said firmly. "If you are some sort of magical creature with powers unknown, I don't think we should let you out of our sight. Professor Snape, do you have a copy of whatever your first year textbook is on hand?"

"Accio Magical Drafts and Potions," Snape said, and, with a flick of his wand, a textbook flew out of a nearby bookshelf and into his hand. Convenient, Milo thought. And a lot less expensive than Drawmij's Instant Summons, that's for sure.

Without a word, the Potions Master passed Milo the heavy, and more importantly, large textbook. If there's one thing about wizards (and Wizards), it's that they never use standardized sheets of A4.

Milo made a big show of opening up the book and reading it studiously. Very studiously.

Twenty-eight eyes bored into Milo's head as he, eventually, turned a page and continued reading at a snail's pace.

"Oh, surely this isn't necessary," Fudge said impatiently. "Just go and stir the ruddy pot, boy!"

"How far from the rim?" Milo asked. "How fast? With what length of spoon? No, I'm sorry Minister, but my life is on the line here. If I'm going to stir it, I'm going to stir it right. I'll just be a minute."

Milo turned another page.

Minutes rolled by. Fudge glanced at his watch every few seconds, and began tapping his foot in irritation. Eventually...

"It's after midnight!" Fudge muttered. "Must we play along with this charade?"

"Oh, it's not so bad," McGonagall said. "I can't remember the last time I've seen someone his age—except for you, Miss Granger, of course—studying so diligently."

"What if he's delaying until the Veritaserum wears off?" Fudge asked.

"A simple enough question to answer," said Dumbledore. "Milo, if you would be so kind as to answer, are you studying with the intention of delaying until the Veritaserum wears off?"

"No, sir," Milo said truthfully, and had to stifle a laugh. That is not why I'm delaying.

"Well, there you have it," said Dumbledore. Fudge grumbled quietly to himself.

Milo slowly reached into his Belt of Hidden Pouches and recovered his most precious possession: his spellbook. Slowly, very slowly, he lifted the thick (but small in terms of height and width) tome and placed it such that it was hidden by Magical Drafts and Potions.

Milo grinned as he began preparing spells. Good thing I was bedridden all day, he thought. Gave me my required eight hours of 'rest.'

Spell preparation is a bit of an odd quirk of the Wizard class. It involved carefully poring over every intricate detail of the magic and memorizing it, but also, at the same time, casting the vast majority of the spell. Ninety-five percent of the casting was done during preparation so that only the very final stage had to be done on the fly. The result was that every Wizard went about their day holding, depending on their level, potentially dozens of unimaginably complicated spells all at the point of being almost finished. Each spell was like a sentence that just didn't quite. Was it any wonder that so many powerful Wizards went mad?

"Not like I have anything better to do," Fudge muttered. "Just a country to run, that's all. Don't mind me."

It takes a Wizard exactly one hour to prepare all of their spells, regardless of how many there are. However, a very infrequently used rule allows them to prepare a fraction of their daily allotment of spells in the same fraction of time, to a minimum of fifteen minutes.

Milo could prepare at most seventeen spells per day, so in fifteen minutes he could prepare one-quarter of that (four spells). He chose Prestidigitation, Tenser's Floating Disk, Mage Hand, and Invisibility.

He quickly stashed his spellbook back into his belt and stood up.

"Okay," he said. "Let's do this thing. But if we're doing it, we're doing it right. I'm a Wizard. I shouldn't have to prove that to you—but seeing as how you're forcing me, I want to make sure there are absolutely no doubts after the fact. And for that, I demand your largest cauldron."

Chapter 13: Roleplaying

Author's Notes: The reviews I got this week really got to me. I'd hoped, but I'd never really believed that something I wrote would be read around the world (I just found out from Fanfiction that some of you live in places as far away from me as Hong Kong, Jamaica, and South Africa) and actually enjoyed. Reading your thoughts on what Milo's plan for escape would be was some of the most fun I've had, ever. Coming up with his actual plan required me and a team of three highly trained, well-equipped, professional, fully qualified geeks to stay up until the birds outside started singing. The result is one that I'm particularly proud of, and tops most of my zany D&D schemes by a wide margin.

Anyways. I'd just like to give a huge thank you to you folks around the world for making a dream of mine come true.

P.S. Could someone with a recent print (i.e., bought it up to a few years ago but not when it was new) of Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire PM me? It's important.

P.P.S. From here on out, a double-length bar-o-thingy denotes the end of the author's notes and the start of the story.

o—o—o—o—o—o—o

"The nerve!"

"Who does he think he is?"

"He's in no position to make demands!"

The reaction to Milo's request for a larger cauldron was... varied.

"It's clearly a ploy," Snape sneered. "He hopes to dilute the potion so that it won't explode in his face when he fails. It won't work."

"If he fails, Severus," Dumbledore said.

"No," Milo said. "Scale up the other ingredients proportionally."

There was a meaningful silence.

"Tell me, boy," Snape said finally. "Do you have a death wish? Do you have any idea how large an explo—"

"Oh, come now," Fudge interrupted. "We're in the presence of six of the Department of Magical Law Enforcement's finest, not to mention the Supreme Mugwump himself. I think we have more than enough magical muscle between us to keep anyone from being harmed. Let's just get him a bigger cauldron and be done with it."

"But—"

"Do remember to whom it is that you are speaking, Severus."

"As you command," Snape said between clenched teeth. "Accio Cauldron Size Twelve." A large, heavy cauldron ponderously hovered from a store room, knocking over a variety of expensive-looking magical doodads in the process. It (slowly) came to a stop near the centre of the room. Milo gave it a quick look. Only two-and-a-half feet in diameter, he thought. Needs to be larger.

"No," Milo said. "Bigger."

"That is the largest potions cauldron I keep in the dungeon," Snape protested angrily. "Unless you plan on cooking a Troll—"

"Of course!" Dumbledore said. "We can use one of the cooking pots from the kitchens. The House Elves make enough oatmeal for hundreds of students on Tuesday mornings in just one pot, except for this one occasion in 1941 when there was a shortage of rolled oats and—"

McGonagall coughed pointedly.

"—and where was I? Oh yes."

Before Snape could say something biting and sarcastic, Dumbledore clapped his hands twice. A small... creature... appeared in front of him with a loud crack. It was, if you rounded up, entirely composed of large, floppy ear.

What the Hells? Milo wondered. Is that... some sort of goblinoid?

"Floppy, would you be so good as to fetch the kitchen's largest cooking pot?" Dumbledore asked kindly.

"Yes, master," Floppy responded in a high, squeaky voice. "Right away, master." With another crack, Floppy was gone.

There was only one explanation for the creature that Milo could think of, impossible as it seemed. He'd heard that the kitchens were staffed by Elves, which was insane, but this world seemed to turn everything he knew on its head. So... so that little goblin-like creature he saw...

Milo broke into a cold sweat.

...must be a slave of the elves. Of all of the hundreds of subspecies of elf, only one kept slaves.

Hogwarts has dark elves in the kitchen, he thought with growing horror. And they have teleporting goblins in their employ. No wonder there was poison in that tart, there's enough Chaotic and Evil in the kitchen for it to qualify as a suburb of the Abyss.

After a few seconds, there were six simultaneous pops. A half-dozen of the goblinoid slaves appeared carrying a mammoth pot over their heads.

The goblins are apparently super-strong, Milo noted with steadily rising panic. And can ignore Hogwarts' anti-teleportation Abjurations. Oh, gods.

"Yeah," Milo said, tearing his eyes away from the humanoids. "That'll do."

As Snape began gathering buckets of glycerol and Flobberworm mucous from his storeroom (Milo wondered briefly how he managed to fit everything in there, before realizing the closet was probably of Holding), Milo mentally ran over his plan. I can prevent the liquids from mixing using Tenser's Floating Disk, he thought. Tenser's Floating Disk was a moderately useful spell that created an invisible shallow bowl that hovers three feet off the ground. He could dump the mucous into the water, cast the spell above the liquid, then pour in the glycerol. The tricky thing is that it's three feet wide—but this cauldron is more than sufficient. Then it's a simple matter of using Prestidigitation to create bubbles. Milo had never actually tried it, but he was pretty sure that creating a few bubbles in a pot fell within Prestidigitation's ability to exert about a pound of force.

"There," Snape said in growing frustration. "You have, here, precisely the correct amount of mucous and glycerol." He gestured to a pair of buckets. "Can we get this over with, now?"

"You said the Headmaster was to check them," Milo reminded him.

Dumbledore thoroughly, and, to the Minister for Magic's irritation, slowly examined the contents of both buckets.

"Everything seems to be in order," Dumbledore said. "Would anyone else like to take a look?"

Hermione coughed awkwardly.

"I would, Headmaster—if it's all right, of course," she said. Milo blinked. Was this Hermione doubting her professors? What was the world coming to?

Hermione, still wrapped in bandages, painfully limped over to the cooking pot in the centre of the room. She examined it until she saw, engraved near the bottom in tiny letters, "CAST IRON 112 GALLONS." Then she hobbled over to the side of the room and picked up a set of heavy brass scales. Then, with the Minister for Magic, two of her teachers, her headmaster, four senior Ministry officials, and six Aurors watching her intently, she limped over to Snape's desk. Carefully avoiding eye contact with the Potions Master, she placed the heavy measuring scale on the desk with a thud.

Hermione's right arm was in a splint, and Milo could tell that she quickly realized there was no way she'd be able to lift either of the two buckets. She drew her wand.

Six Aurors drew wands simultaneously and aimed steadily at her. Hermione looked like she would die in a panic.

"Peace," Dumbledore said. "She was just, I presume, about to perform a simple Hovering Charm?"

"Featherweight Charm, actually," Hermione said matter-of-factly, although she still looked nervous. "And then a Hovering Charm. You see, the two charms combined are over one-fifth more efficient than a single, more powerful—"

"Nobody asked for a lecture, Miss Granger," Snape snapped.

"Five points for Gryffindor," McGonagall said simultaneously. Upon hearing Snape's remark, she added, "That's really rather clever, Miss Granger."

The Aurors put away their wands, looking somewhat sheepish at having drawn on a twelve year-old girl. The two Heads of Houses glared at each other as. Hermione carefully weighed both buckets (dispelling the Featherweight Charm in the process, of course). Then she nodded at Milo.

"Thanks," he muttered as she walked past him to her earlier position.

"Any time," she said simply. She looked a bit stunned.

"Oh, before you begin," said Bode, "you should probably be informed that a number of anti-cheating enchantments have been placed in this classroom."

Milo paused.

"Explain," he asked.

"Obviously I can't go into too much detail, but suffice to say that we'll be well aware of any magical illusions that you create, or if you try to add anything to the potion without our knowledge."

Milo frowned. This shouldn't cause any problems, he thought. Invisibility is the only Illusion I'll be casting, and it isn't really an Illusion that I create, exactly. That sounds like more of a Figment or Glamer.

Hopefully.

Well, I'd best begin. No time like the present. Pushing his fear and nervousness to the side, Milo tried to emulate the tone of a performing Bard he once heard back in Myra (cityoflight!cityofmagic!).

"All right. Professors, Minister, Officials, Government Goons, just sit back; you're about to see magic done," Milo announced confidently, rolling up his sleeves.

"What does he think he is, a stage magician?" Fudge murmured quietly.

"This reminds me of a time I was in a tavern back in my world," Milo said as he unceremoniously dumped the bucket of thick, slimy Flobberworm mucous into the cauldron. "It was a nice little place, as far as roadside taverns go. Their soup was terrible. It went by the name of Tenser's Floating Disko," he said, casting the spell. Fortunately enough, the story was true. A retired Wizard built the entire establishment hovering two feet off the ground using a copious number of Immovable Rods; The Disko was famed far and wide for its resilience to earthquakes, its Dancing Lights, and its terrible soup.

"Isn't he only eleven?" Fudge asked in astonishment. "What tavern would—"

"But that, of course, was in another world," Milo said, pouring the glycerol into the cauldron. Snape looked as if he were about to duck beneath his desk for cover. Unbeknownst to the audience, the thick liquid hit, instead of the water in the cauldron, Milo's magical disk. "A world which now seems to exist only in the hazy reaches of my memory, and every day seems to be slipping deeper into the murky depths of Invisibility." In the blink of an eye, the glycerol (which, if anyone had looked, would have appeared to be floating in the air inside the darkness of the cauldron) vanished.

Milo grabbed his ladle and dipped it into the cauldron in the area between the force disk and the edge. The pot was so huge that, in order to stir it, he'd have to actually walk around the perimeter of the cast iron monstrosity. When he was about three-quarters of the way around, he began to speak again.

"And this, as you will soon see, was no mere sleight of hand, legerdemain, or," he completed the circuit, "Prestidigitation."

The pot bubbled.

Milo almost couldn't believe that he might actually be getting away with it. He'd made the damned pot bubble, nothing had exploded, and Lucius's plot was foiled. He felt lightheaded. He wanted to go back to the Gryffindor Common Room and celebr—

"Curious," Dumbledore said, raising his half-moon spectacles.

Snape smiled triumphantly.

"In this manner I will, of course, defer to the Potions Master," Dumbledore said, "but... tell me, Severus, does this potion usually bubble?"

Milo froze.

"No doubt, it's bubbling because of how vigorously young Milo wanted his potion to succeed," Snape suggested with amusement. Milo looked around the room in a panic as Snape moved excitedly towards the cauldron to investigate.

It's not supposed to bubble? He'd miscalculated Snape. The devious Potions Master had anticipated Milo's ability to fake the effects of the potion and hadn't told him truthfully what they should, in fact, be.

Milo looked pleadingly at Dumbledore, and then at McGonagall, but neither offered him any help. He was sure to be ousted as a fake wizard and expelled from Hogwarts, falling right into Lucius's (presumably) evil plot (whatever it happened to be). Tap. Tap. Tap. Snape's polished leather loafers made loud, echoing sounds as the greasy Potions Master approached. In blind desperation, Milo looked into the faces of the Minister, his cronies, and even the mooks. I need help, he thought frantically. I need someone who knows what—oh, right.

Catching Hermione's eye, she mouthed it turns purple. Milo had heard that, in the distant past, only Rogues were able to read lips. He was blissfully happy that this was no longer the case.

Fortunately, Prestidigitation (which, in Milo's firm opinion, was the best spell ever invented) could last up to an hour—and it could recolour liquids. The spell wasn't an Illusion (it actually changed the object's colour), so it (hopefully) wouldn't trigger their wards. By the time Snape got to the cauldron, the liquid inside was a pale shade of violet. Milo could feel his heart pounding against his chest as he waited for the anti-cheating alarms to sound. He nearly fainted with relief when nothing happened, although the "potion" still had to pass one more step... Milo just hoped he'd got the shade of purple right.

Snape peered inside suspiciously, and then did something Milo hadn't anticipated.

To Milo's horror, Snape picked up the ladle. As he moved to dip it into the pot (presumably to investigate the potion), Milo ran through his options. Tenser's Floating Disk was not a dismissible spell; at Milo's level, it would be blocking the majority of the cauldron's opening for another five hours. Snape was sure to discover the invisible force disk, and Milo would be expelled. Then (presumably) killed horribly by Death Eaters.

"Sorry, what was that Hermione?" Milo asked loudly, improvising wildly. "You require help tying your shoes because your arm was grievously injured while Snape was supposed to be protecting you from a Troll? Why, of course I can help you!" Technically, no lies. Milo bolted towards Hermione as fast as he could run.

Milo collapsed at Hermione's feet and started fumbling with her laces.

"What on Earth are you—" she asked, surprised.

"Tenser's Floating Disk disappears if you move out of the spell's range," Milo explained quietly. "I need to get another ten feet away from the cauldron before Snape realizes what's going on." Hermione's back was to the door; ten feet would put Milo well into the hallway.

"Your rat," Hermione whispered. "Ask him to run out, and chase him."

"Good plan. Mordy?"

"Don't need to tell me twice, boss," Milo's familiar squeaked. Mordy leapt out of Milo's belt and made a mad dash for the exit.

Snape dipped the ladle into the cauldron, and Milo heard a quiet thud as the steel instrument hit his force bowl.

Snape blinked.

"What—" he began.

"Mordenkainen!" Milo shouted, and pursued. Shortly after he reached the exit, he heard a muffled splash from the cauldron as the Tenser's Floating Disk winked out of existence.

"Here, now!" Fudge said. "We can't just have him leave."

There was a brief pause.

"Everyone duck for cover!" someone shouted. Evidentially, they had taken Milo's flight to mean that the potion was about to explode.

"Accio Milo," one of the Aurors muttered, and Milo felt a strange tug in the region of his stomach. The next thing he knew, he was being pulled to the centre of the room by invisible hands. It was a weird feeling.

"You'll have to look for your rat later, Milo," Bode said in his dry monotone. "We can't allow you to leave until the inquiries are closed."

"Right, of course," Milo said. Careful not to lie, he reminded himself. "I'm only eleven; eleven year olds are notoriously flighty."

"Don't need to tell me twice," McGonagall muttered.

Snape, who had evidently been distracted by Milo's unexpected flight, began to test the potion again. As soon as his ladle entered the cauldron, Milo had a burst of mad inspiration.

"I think I've more than proved that I'm a legitimate Mage, Hand me that quill, Headmaster, would you?"

"Sorry, what was that?" Fudge asked. Milo concentrated on the Mage Hand spell (a handy (sorry), weak telekinesis), and, targeting the water in the cauldron (Mage Hand can't target held objects, such as Snape's ladle) Milo created a small current which forced the ladle to move in a very tiny counterclockwise circle.

Snape frowned. He wasn't sure if it was a trick of his eye, but he could have sworn that the purple potion became slightly darker as he stared at it.

"I was just asking the Headmaster to hand me the quill on his desk," Milo said. "But on second thought, I realize, I don't need it. How's the potion check out, Professor Snape?"

"I think your student might be a bit funny," Fudge said not quite quietly enough to Dumbledore. "A tad... off in the head, if you catch my meaning."

"I am quite sorry," Dumbledore said apologetically. "I didn't bring my fishing rod! I had no idea we were going out to catch meanings on this fine evening. Why, once, when I was a boy, my brother and I caught a meaning that weighed—"

McGonagall coughed again.

"—but perhaps that story is best told later," Dumbledore said.

Fudge sighed and muttered something under his breath. Milo wasn't sure, but he thought he caught the words 'surrounded by nutters' somewhere in there.

Snape carefully extracted a small amount of the potion with his ladle and stared at it in astonishment.

"Well?" the Minister pressed. "What's the verdict, Severus?"

Snape stared at the contents of the cauldron, his face livid with barely contained rage.

"You." He said, turning to Milo. His voice was like a Polar Ray with a confirmed critical. "If I ever find out how you did this, boy, you'll rue the day your mother first laid eyes on your fath—"

"Severus," Dumbledore said reproachfully. Snape reined himself in with obvious effort.

"I have the... unequaled pleasure—" Snape said through clenched teeth, but Milo was pretty sure he meant the other thing, "—to say that this potion is, against all odds and reason... adequate."

McGonagall looked relieved, Bode appeared somewhat disappointed (Milo was willing to bet Bode hoped he'd discovered some form of new and exotic humanoid monster in Milo), while Dumbledore (and only Dumbledore) started clapping. Hermione stood in the corner beaming at him. Best of all, he earned 800 XP. That alone will cover months of item crafting, Milo thought.

"Ruddy waste of time, this was," Fudge complained to Umbridge as the Ministry officials filed out. "Wonder why he insisted it be done so late at night—and on a weekend, too?"

"Minerva," Dumbledore asked politely, "would you please take Miss Granger back to the hospital wing?"

"Of course, Albus," McGonagall said politely, and moved to the injured girl. Snape was pacing back and forth by the cauldron, fuming.

"Milo," Dumbledore said, "I understand that it's late, and you have class tomorrow, but—would you mind coming to my office for a brief chat?"

"Of course, Headmaster," Milo said politely. There were no rules anywhere for sleep deprivation, ergo, Milo could stay up as late as he wanted.

The eccentric Headmaster led Milo through the labyrinthine castle, up the stairs (skipping, unconsciously, the trick step in the second-floor staircase) and, at last, to a random dead end.

"Uh," Milo said. "Your office isn't just out here in the hall, is it?"

"Sherbet Lemon," Dumbledore said.

"That's... not really an answer, you know."

"Ah, young Milo, in that, you are wrong."

A nearby gargoyle statue slowly began to move.

"Holycrapgargoyle!" Milo shrieked. "Glitterdust!" He held out his hand, but nothing happened. Right, he thought, embarrassed. I'm completely out of spells. Until he had a chance to prepare new spells, Milo was basically a Commoner with a high Will save and a pet rat.

The gargoyle, however, proved to be merely a statue, which rose as it turned, revealing a spiral staircase.

"Sweet entrance," Milo said appreciatively.

"No pun intended?" Dumbledore asked wryly.

"What?"

"Well, you said sweet entrance, and the password, of course, is my favourite form of sweet..."

Milo stared at him blankly.

The Headmaster just sighed and began climbing the formidable staircase.

Dumbledore's office was awesome. There was simply no other word to describe it. Wondrous Items of all sorts decorated every flat surface that Milo could see; many of which were ticking at inconsistent, conflicting speeds—no doubt, Milo assumed, to confuse his enemies. Up on the walls were more animated portraits looking down at them, and, in the corner, lay the sorting hat.

"Please, sit down," Dumbledore said. "Can I get you anything? Cocoa? Tea?"

"That first one," Milo requested. "I have no idea what it is."

Dumbledore waved his wand lazily, and a large mug of hot cocoa appeared in front of Milo. They have a spell for that? Milo wondered. Just for conjuring steaming hot mugs of cocoa?

"You're probably wondering why I've invited you here," Dumbledore said. Unless, of course, it's a spell that summons arbitrary hot drinks.

"Actually, I was wondering what spell you used to conjure the drinks," Milo said, then frowned. Wait, why on the Prime Material did I just say that?

"A nonverbal variant of the Summoning Charm," Dumbledore shrugged. "Created by Helga Hufflepuff herself to summon food from the kitchens of Hogwarts. It only works within the grounds."

I must still be under the effects of the Veritaserum, Milo realized. Was that why Dumbledore had summoned him up here now?

"Now you're probably wondering why I've invited you here?" Dumbledore asked, somewhat hopefully.

"No, I was wondering if you'd invited me here now because I'm still compelled to speak only the truth," Milo said. Aarrrgh!

Dumbledore chuckled.

"As much as I feel the world could do with a little more honesty, no, that's not the reason. I was travelling the past few days—Wizengamot business, you understand—and my sleep schedule is quite turned upside-down. This was the first in quite some time that I've had a spare moment, in fact."

"I see," Milo said. "Okay, I'll bite. Now I'm wondering why you've invited me here."

"I wanted to know how you did it," Dumbledore said.

"Did what?" Milo asked.

"Faked the potion well enough to fool Snape. That's no easy task, you know."

Milo froze. He nearly dropped his cocoa (which, by the way, was delicious).

"Oh, don't worry," Dumbledore said. "I'm not the Ministry. You're not in trouble."

Milo only then realized how vulnerable he was. No spells. No familiar. No-one who knew where he was. No escape plan. No ability to lie.

"I used magic to keep the mucous from mixing with the glycerol," Milo confessed, "then ended the spell right as Snape tested the potion. I then used some very weak telekinesis to cause Snape to accidentally stir the liquid, thus completing the final step in creating the potion."

"You mean to say that Snape created that potion?" Dumbledore asked, amazed. Then he burst out laughing, and continued to do so until there were tears in his eyes. "I haven't laughed so hard in days," he admitted. "And don't worry, your secret's safe with me."

"Yeah, I guess it is pretty funny," Milo conceded. "And thanks."

"Don't mention it. Not since the days of Emeric the Evil were Headmasters involved in the business of having their students executed. But that wasn't the only reason I asked you here."

"Oh?"

"You fought a Troll on Hallowe'en," Dumbledore said, "instead of doing the sensible thing and letting trained, fully-qualified adult witches and wizards handle it. Why?"

"It came at me," Milo said.

"You could have run for it," Dumbledore countered.

"It had me cornered."

"You could have jumped out the window," Dumbledore pressed. "You have, after all, a spell for that exact purpose."

Milo frowned. He could have easily escaped the Troll with Feather Fall, now that he thought about it.

"The thought never occurred to me," Milo answered honestly.

"Why not?" Dumbledore asked. "For nearly anyone else in the world, it would be the only thought that occurred to them."

"It's not what I do," Milo said. "Running away from monsters, that is."

Dumbledore's eyes twinkled.

"But, have you ever asked yourself, why not?"

"I... no. No, I haven't," Milo paused. "But only because I haven't had to. I'm an adventurer. Fighting monsters is what I do."

"Because you're an adventurer? So you do it... for the sense of adventure?"

"No, that's not it at all. It's... it's hard to explain." How do you explain to someone something that's so obvious? Adventurers fight monsters. That's just how it is. You'd have as much luck trying to explain to someone why two and two made four.

"You're a smart boy. Try."

"I'm a PC. An adventurer. A hero. When there's a monster, or an evil necromancer, or a murderer, or whatever, it's my job to take him out."

"But in this case, in Hogwarts, there are others who could fight that Troll, do that job, at least as well as you could."

"It... it doesn't matter. I was there. The Troll was there. It happened for a reason; I was supposed to fight that Troll."

"You're a bit young to have set so much stock in fate."

"Not fate. Planning by a higher power."

"By God?" Dumbledore asked.

"Hah, no. In my experience, gods spend too much time fighting amongst themselves and making powerful, yet shockingly unoptimized, magical artifacts and holy relics to plan people's lives out."

"Then... who?"

"The same entity that makes sure that, eventually, a villain will always be defeated by a hero. That arranges for Draco and Harry to be the same age, at the same school. That arranges for the Philosopher's Stone to be hidden at that same school in their first year. That keeps the background world running when we're not looking at it."

"That sounds like fate to me," Dumbledore said. "Except maybe for that last one."

Milo simply shrugged.

"So, you believe it is your fate to fight monsters?" Dumbledore pressed.

"I... I don't think I'm being clear," Milo said. "I fight monsters. I'm an adventurer. A hero. It's a fact of life. There's no why to it, it's just... how my life goes."

"Is it to protect innocent lives?" Dumbledore asked.

"Not... really. But when it happens, that's a perk, I suppose."

"To right great imbalances in the universe?"

"No. Are there great imbalances I wasn't aware of?"

"Not to my knowledge. Is it for revenge?"

"No. I don't have anything I feel all that... bitter about."

"For the thrill, then?"

"I don't do anything for the thrill of it."

"For glory and respect?"

"No, without Leadership, glory's about as useful as Skill Focus (Craft (Basketweaving))."

"And you don't see yourself as a leader, then?"

"A planner, maybe, but... a leader? One who stands on a crate and gives inspiring speeches to a bunch of low-level Commoners and Warriors? No, I'll leave that to someone else. What's with all the questions, Headmaster?"

Dumbledore sighed heavily.

"I've known witches and wizards—and more than a few Muggles, for that matter—who set forth to battle evil without any clear motivation for doing so. They... tend to fit into one of two categories. Either they discover the reason within themselves later, and go on to do great things, or, more often... they fall."

"They die? Because I'd have to disagree, Professor; Neutral adventurers tend to be much more pragmatic and level-headed and overall far less likely to die some a stupid sacrifice or last stand than Good ones."

"Sometimes they do," Dumbledore admitted soberly. "But more often, they find themselves becoming what they once fought."

"What, they go Evil? I don't think I'm in any danger of that. It's just not... in character." Milo sighed. "I'm not... I'm not really equipped to discuss philosophy, Headmaster."

"And why is that?"

"I... I fight monsters," he said firmly. "I kick down doors. I find treasure. I gain Experience. I spend an inordinate amount of time in taverns. I operate best in groups of four. I solve mysteries. I use magic. I don't... the discussion of why very rarely comes up. And even then... if it did, the reason for it would suddenly appear in my head. Poof. Like it had always been there, the same as if you asked me what my parents' names were. It's like a part of me, the part that makes those decisions and created the history and the hopes and dreams... it's gone. I'm just the collection of stats and spells with a race and alignment. I don't know how to explain it; to my knowledge this has never happened to anyone before. It's like... like I'm a character in a play, and the player was left behind when I was brought here."

"Maybe," said Dumbledore, "it's time you started to think for yourself? To be more than a simple mask?"

"Are you suggesting..."

"If you're a character," Dumbledore shrugged, "I don't see any reason why you can't be your own player."

Milo stared at the Headmaster, completely dumbstruck.

"And now, I believe, it is time for us both to go to bed. You seem to be quite recovered, but would you do me one more favour and spend the night in the hospital wing? You'll see why tomorrow," Dumbledore said.

"Sure," Milo shrugged. He was used to sleeping in the wilderness and in ancient crypts, anyways. While a step-and-a-half down from the four-poster beds in Gryffindor tower, the hospital cots were a great deal more comfortable than a bedroll—not, when it came to it, that Milo much cared.

"Goodnight, Milo."

"'Night, Professor."

Milo was already halfway back to the hospital wing when he realized that, when Dumbledore asked him how he faked the potion, it meant he actually believed that Milo was a different sort of Wizard.

What does he know that I don't? Or rather... what does he know that I know that I don't know he knows?

And why does Lucius want me expelled?

And who really killed the acromantula? And why was it missing a fang?

The lack of injuries on the nonetheless dead spider implied one thing...

Death Effect.

The Killing Curse.

Chapter 15: Quidditch

Author's Notes: To my surprise, my writing is actually ahead of schedule and I'm already putting the finishing touches on chapter 16. I've found that I write faster (and better) when I'm under pressure, so tomorrow (Sunday the 11th), I'll be posting a bonus chapter.

o—o—o—o—o—o—o

Milo waited for Friday to roll around with ever-increasing anxiety and anticipation. His time was entirely taken up with classes, spell research (Milo decided to start researching Benign Transposition, a handy 1st-level spell that swaps the positions of a pair of willing creatures), and magic item crafting. The latter was proving increasingly frustrating: one of the oft-forgotten requirements in creating a magic item was that, during the creation process the crafter or an assistant has to cast whichever spell the magic item most closely replicates. Normally, this is no problem at all—for a small charge, any item crafter could hire a high-level Cleric or Wizard to cast the spell for them. Milo, obviously not having this advantage, was severely limited in his choices of items to craft—and, worse, most of them produced effects he could already manage much less expensively by just casting a spell.

Despite the severe restrictions, the Milo that entered McGonagall's office on Tuesday was wearing a pair of sleek midnight-blue gloves with tiny yellow stars on the knuckles. Twice a day, Milo's new Arcanist's Gloves could add a significant amount of extra kick (+2 Caster Levels' worth of kick, to be precise) to his low-level spells.

To McGonagall's increasing frustration, Milo showed no noticeable improvement in his Transfiguration abilities, even under her expert tutelage.

"You have some sort of learning block," McGonagall had explained. "We just need to figure out how to work around it. If you can pull off even one successful Transfiguration, I'm sure you will have no trouble at all with further ones."

She'd decided to try trial-and-error. Since Transfiguration was largely performed in the mind rather than with the wand, she'd explained, it only followed that Milo had to try thinking differently, and the easiest way to do this was to change environmental factors more-or-less at random.

She made Milo try to Transfigure outdoors, indoors, while balanced on one foot, while blindfolded, while hanging upside-down, while inhaling burning incense, with his wand in his left hand instead of his right, with his wand held in his feet, with his wand held in both hands, with her wand, with no wand at all, while under water, and while floating in the air—and every possible combination of the above.

"Maybe," she said thoughtfully, "if you're blindfolded and slowly turning counter-clockwise while in the presence of a horned toad and the room is smelling of lavender—"

"Professor," Milo interrupted. "I don't mean to be rude, but... doesn't this strike you as a bit ridiculous?"

"Of course!" McGonagall said, and for a moment Milo thought she'd agreed with him. "Laughter! Maybe you'll be able to Transfigure while laughing. Tell me, Mister Amastacia-Liadon" (Milo rolled his eyes. He hated being called by his last name) "tell me, how many centaurs does it take to light up a wand?"

Milo sighed.

"I don't know," he said obligingly. "How many?"

"None," McGonagall said with the tone of someone saying something clever, "for Mars is unusually bright tonight."

o—o—o—o

When the other Gryffindors returned from their communal detention, they found Milo sitting in the Common Room stitching up his fifth-hand robes.

"Still working on that?" Ron asked, interested. "They already fit better than mine do—mind, mine were Charlie's originally."

Hermione stared at the thread Milo was using with interest.

"Is that—is that unicorn hair?" she gasped.

"Yeah, wand-grade." Milo said. "I was going to use silk, but it wasn't expensive enough."

"Wasn't expensive—" Ron said, his face going red. He paused to get control of himself with obvious effort. "You're just as bad as Malfoy, you are."

"No, no," Milo said, aghast. "It's just that, for my magic, I need to use magical components that cost a certain amount. And," Milo said with a grin, "when I'm done, these robes could fit Hagrid."

"How much unicorn hair—"

"Magic items resize to fit their wearers," Milo explained patiently. "Everyone knows that, Ron."

"Thought we weren't going to do that anymore," said Harry.

"Couldn't help myself. Everyone ready for tomorrow?" Milo asked, setting aside his under-construction Robe of Arcane Might. It would take another twenty days, but when he was done, Milo would be a force to be reckoned with. Or not to be reckoned with, Milo could never remember how that saying went.

"Yeah," Harry said.

"'Course," Ron added.

"Well—if you insist," Hermione said, although Milo guessed that her reluctance wasn't entirely genuine.

"Excellent. Let's begin, then."

o—o—o—o

Milo waited until he could hear the thunder from the Quidditch pitch outside to begin his heist.

"Invisibility," he muttered and withdrew his eleven-foot pole, looking appraisingly at Snape's office door.

With a deep breath to steady his nerves, he turned the doorknob with Mage Hand and gave the door a firm push with the wooden pole.

Nothing exploded. Milo wiped sweat from his brow. Really, this is what Rogues are for, he thought sourly. Milo stepped cautiously through the apparently un-trapped doorway and entered Snape's office. He wanted to spend as little time in here as possible.

"Spontaneous Search," he cast. Milo located the Veritaserum instantly in Snape's cupboard. It was in a small cauldron next to one containing a thick, bubbling orange potion Milo wasn't familiar with.

Milo reached into his belt and grabbed a small ceramic flask, filled it with the truth potion, and gave it to Mordy, who was also invisible.

"Run this over to Hermione," he whispered. "I'll be right—"

Milo started as the office door slammed shut. He hadn't seen anyone enter, but there was no reason it couldn't have been someone invisible...

"See Invisibility," he cast as quietly as he could, though the spell didn't turn up anything.

He exhaled. It must have been the wind...

...there couldn't possibly be any wind in the dungeons, could there?

So, maybe I should use Detect Thoughts? While he debated spending another 2nd-level spell slot on what might be nothing, Milo suddenly felt himself being yanked upwards into the air.

"Gah!" Milo shouted reflexively as he dangled by his ankles.

To Milo's horror, the air near the door seemed to run like wet paint towards the ground, revealing a very smug-looking Professor Snape, wand brandished like a sword.

Unfortunately for our hero, the Disillusionment Charm only makes the target very, very difficult to see by changing their colour to resemble the background—rather like a chameleon—rather than being actually invisible. As such, See Invisibility—which only revealed invisible creatures and objects, was ineffective.

I'm still invisible, Milo reminded himself. Maybe this dangly spell affects a wide area and he doesn't actually know where I am...

"Finite Incantatem," Snape muttered, but nothing seemed to happen. "Accio Invisibility Cloak." Milo held his breath. Snape frowned, staring at his wand as if it must be broken. With a shrug, he cast "Accio Flour."

A heavy burlap sack flew from one of Snape's many supply cupboards and into Snape's hand.

Milo panicked. Flour was, in addition to closed doors, an infamous bane of invisible characters everywhere—it was much like a Cleric's Glitterdust.

"Ventus," Snape said with a sneer, and the flour in his hand was blasted around the classroom.

Milo looked up at himself: he was completely covered in the white powder, which gave away his position completely. He sighed.

"Look, I—" Milo began.

"Stupefy," Snape cast, and with a red flash everything went black.

o—o—o—o

Quirrell sat by himself watching the Quidditch match without much enthusiasm. Despite the crowd, all of the seats nearby him were strangely empty—likely because of the strong scent of garlic his turban emanated.

"Slytherin in possession again," Lee Thomas announced miserably to the audience. "Those Firebolts must be something else entirely." Lee sighed audibly. "Oh, and guess what? They scored. Again. That puts the score at 140-30 for Slytherin, although, might I remind you that all three of Gryffindor's amazing goals were made by Angelina Johnson, the lovely and talented—and, might I say, beautiful—"

"No, you may not," interrupted McGonagall.

"Sorry Professor. Anyways, oh, Slytherin's got the Quaffle again..."

To Quirrell's great surprise, Milo came and sat down next to him.

"Sh-sh-shouldnt you b-b-be with your friends?" Quirrell stammered.

Milo simply shrugged.

"I-I suppose you c-c-came to t-t-talk about v-v-v-vampires again?"

Milo stared up at him and frowned.

"Yeah," he said. "Remind me again where we left off?"

Quirrell eyed his student suspiciously.

"You w-w-were t-t-telling me how you b-b-believed that H-H-He-Who-M-M-Must-N-N-Not-B-B-B-Be-N-N-N-Named" (Quirrell resolved to say "Y-Y-You-Kn-Kn-Know-Who" from there on out, if only to save time) "had s-s-servants r-r-rounding up v-v-vampires."

Milo stared at him with an unusual expression.

"Did I, now?" he said softly. "And, have you thought at all about it? What do you think... Professor?"

Quirrell paused. What did he think? The truth of what he believed was something he tried not to think about, lest his master discover how odd he thought it that becoming a vampire hadn't been his first plan...

"The D-D-Dark L-L-Lord is widely known to b-b-believe strongly in b-b-blood purity," Quirrell explained. "I d-d-don't b-b-believe he would b-be w-w-willing to b-b-become a v-vampire."

Milo choked somewhat, but recovered quickly. Something is not right here, Quirrell thought. I have to press him for information... can he really bring back the dead?

"M-m-more importantly," Quirrell stammered, "what y-y-you said earlier—is it t-true?"

Milo hesitated for a fraction of a second before speaking.

"Yes, of course."

"But—h-how?"

In the background, ignored by both of them, Slytherin scored again.

Milo paused.

"In the same way that all wonders are achieved," he said. "I think you know how."

Quirrell frowned.

"N-no, I r-r-really don't."

Milo looked vaguely disappointed.

"Where's Snape?" Milo asked suddenly. "I wonder what he might be up to while the students are all here, watching the game?"

Quirrell himself had just been wondering the selfsame question.

"Y-you think h-h-he's trying to g-g-get the Stone again?" Quirrell asked.

"Maybe. What are we going to do about it?"

To Quirrell's surprise, a small rat climbed up his leg without warning. Quirrell reached for his wand to hex it, but noticed the rat was holding a tiny roll of parchment between its teeth.

Unfurling it, Quirrell read:

Professor Quirrel,
Snape has me locked in his office. He hexed me and fled, I'm almost completely immobilized. You're the only professor who knows what he's up to. Help!
—Milo

The writing was messy and hasty, and the ink blotches ran in the wrong direction, almost as if it had been written upside-down.

"Oh," Quirrell smiled darkly. "I don't think you'll be needing to worry about Severus Snape for much longer."

Without another word, Quirrell stood up and strode out of the stands, his purple robes trailing behind him.

"Oh-oh OH!" Lee shouted, "POTTER'S SEEN THE SNITCH! HE'S GOING AFTER IT AND—"

Dozens of students nearby saw it happen. His face mottled with rage and frustration, Milo, to the horror of all watching, drew his wand and, pointing it at Harry Potter, clearly cast the Hurling Hex. Ignoring the shocked looks of horror on the bystanders' faces, Milo left the stadium.

o—o

Harry was shocked to find that his beloved Nimbus was, suddenly, actively attempting to throw him off.

"—what's going on?" Lee asked in alarm. "Potter seems to be having some difficulty with his broomstick. We were so close!"

"That's the signal, boys!" Flint, the Slytherin captain, shouted to his players.

Pucey, a Slytherin Chaser, abruptly screamed and went careening off into the stands.

The Nimbus gave another lurch, and Harry slipped off of it. For a moment he felt like this was the end, but he miraculously managed to catch hold of the shaft with his left hand.

Harry risked a glance at the rest of the match. The Slytherin team was in absolute disarray, flying chaotically and apparently at random. A second Chaser and a Beater joined Pucey on the ground as they abandoned their apparently uncontrollable broomsticks. Out of the corner of his eye, Harry saw a tiny flicker of gold.

No... he thought. Could it be?

o—o

"Oi, Malfoy," Ron said with a sneer. "Think fast!"

Before he finished speaking, Ron chucked a Veritaserum-laced water balloon at Malfoy's face. That had been Hermione's idea: if all it took was a drop of the potion, then surely he'd swallow at least that much by accident, right? Not to mention how much got into his eyes. That rat always delivers, Ron thought to himself. Unlike Scabbers.

"Agh—what—WEASLEY!" Malfoy spluttered, water pouring all down his front. The crowd of students around him were too focussed on the game to pay much attention to yet another Malfoy vs. Weasley row.

"So, Malfoy, what are you up to?" Ron asked casually.

"Trying to decide what to hex you with!" Malfoy said, then frowned.

"I meant, what's your evil plan?" Ron clarified.

"It's none of your business that I'm trying to get the Slytherin team to stop pretending their fake Firebolts, which are really Nimbus Two Thousands in disguise, are going haywire because its only Potter that's been hexed and they're going to get flattened!" Malfoy clutched his hands over his mouth, as if to stop it from speaking. He glanced around frantically—where were Crabbe and Goyle?

"And why are the Slytherins riding fake Firebolts?" Ron asked, intrigued.

o—o

Harry was jostled back to his senses as his Nimbus gave another kick and his hand slipped about two feet down the shaft towards the end. In addition to rocking wildly back and forth, the Nimbus was still flying forwards at the speed it had been when Harry had last had control over it.

The Snitch, if that's what it was, was on the other side of the pitch. Harry swung his legs sideways, angling the broomstick, still bucking chaotically, around in a wide arc.

He could see the snitch, buzzing above the stands. Nobody else seemed to notice it, they were too fixated on the havoc that Harry's and the Slytherin's broomsticks were wreaking. Harry was just a few yards away from his target when the broomstick gave a particularly powerful kick and he lost his grip entirely—literally and figuratively.

"AAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAH!" he screamed, flying through the air in a high arc towards where the Gryffindors were sitting. His Nimbus, meanwhile, continued flying over the audience and into the distance like a speeding bullet.

A red-and-gold sea began to part in front of him as Gryffindors fled. Harry saw a tiny flicker of silver ahead of him and desperately reached forwards. It was just over a foot away... now just inches...

Harry's gloved hand clasped around something round and heavy when everything went dark.

The last thing he remembered was Neville's horrified face.

o—o

The door to Snape's office re-opened and Mordy, now visible, scurried through. Milo was still hanging upside-down, which was making him dizzy and likely gave him all kinds of circumstance penalties.

Milo glanced up from his furry friend and saw Quirrell's trademark purple robes and turban.

"Hey," Milo said. "Did you get my note?"

"I-i-indeed," he stammered. "Liberacorpus," he muttered, and Milo slammed into the ground.

"Well, that was embarrassing," Milo said. "Writing with Mage Hand is a really weird experience, I'm surprised you could even read that."

"Show m-m-me your w-wand," Quirrell commanded. Milo stared at him blankly for a moment before remembering he even had one.

"What, this old thing? Sure, it's all yours." Milo pulled his chestnut wand from his pocket and tossed it to the professor. Quirrell caught it with surprisingly quick reflexes, and examined it closely.

"A-as your Defence Professor," Quirrell said absently, "I w-w-would advise against s-s-surrendering your w-wand in the f-future." Milo snorted.

"What am I going to do, poke you with it?" he asked with a laugh, standing up from the floor. At some point while he was stunned, Snape had cleaned all traces of flour from the office.

"Priori Incantato," Quirrell said under his breath. If he was surprised when nothing happened, it didn't register on his face.

Apparently satisfied, Quirrell handed Milo back his stick. Weird, Milo thought. Wonder what that was all about?

"Erm," Milo said. "I don't suppose we can leave now? Before he comes back?"

Quirrell gave Milo a quick appraising look.

"H-have you ever h-heard of Polyjuice P-Potion?" he asked.

"Uh," Milo said. "Maybe? It was in something I'd read in the Library." He frowned, and, for once, succeeded on a skill check. "It lets you disguise yourself as someone else, right?"

"C-correct," Quirrell said. "W-would it s-surprise you that s-someone is w-walking around right now l-looking like y-you?"

"Well, that can't be good," said Milo, somewhat irritated that they weren't leaving yet. "I wonder what Snape's up to?"

"H-he tried to f-find out how I was d-d-defending the Stone," Quirrell said. "After that, I d-don't know. W-walk with me," Quirrell commanded.

Milo shrugged and followed. Mordy, whose little rat legs couldn't keep up, sat on his shoulder.

"I n-notice your m-mind jumped straight to the P-Potions Master," Quirrell said. "W-why?"

"He's working for Lucius Malfoy," said Milo. "Who was a Death Eater, and therefore working for He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named." As Milo filled Quirrell in on his theory about Draco, Snape, and Lucius, they approached Quirrell's office. The simple wooden door opened with a wave of Quirrell's hand.

"H-how do you know that L-Lucius is still loyal to the D-Dark L-Lord?" Quirrell asked. "Hasn't h-he told the w-w-world that he was 'b-bewitched,'" Quirrell said the last with a sneer, sitting down behind his desk.

"Well, for one, that's obviously a lie. Everything about the Malfoys has evil written all over it. But also, when I was summoned here, I woke up in the Malfoy manor surrounded by dark wizards in masks that sound an awful lot like the old Death Eater getups."

"S-so," Quirrell mused softly. "They're still active, even w-without their m-master..."

"Oh," Milo added as an afterthought. "While I'm here, want me to protect your office against vampires?"

"W-what?" Quirrell asked. He seemed totally thrown by the question. "Why?"

"To keep Vampiremort from murdering you in your sleep when he fails to get the Stone," Milo said. It took effort not to add 'duh.'

"Wh-what exactly c-can you do against v-v-vampires? Y-you're only eleven," Quirrell said, taking a sip from a glass of water that he created with a wave of his wand.

"Ah," Milo countered. "I might be twelve, now—I don't know when my birthday is."

"Q-quite besides the p-point," Quirrell said.

"It's easy, really," Milo said. "I just carve a few holy symbols onto the doors, windows, vents, and, ideally, every brick of the wall. You've already got the garlic covered—I don't suppose you can get Holy Water in this universe? Eh, nevermind, it's suboptimal anyways. 'Course, the vamp can just Dominate you with a look—you guys have anything like Protection from Evil?"

"W-what is this 'Protection F-From E-E-Evil?'" Quirrell asked.

"Handy little spell. Makes it hard for Evil creatures to touch you—they can't at all if they're summoned—and makes you totally immune from all forms of mental control, whether the originator is Evil or not."

Quirrell dropped his glass, which shattered on the hard stone ground.

"Permanently?" Quirrell asked, his expression carefully neutral.

"Nah, just for a few minutes. Want me to Prestidigitate that?" he asked, pointing at the shards of glass.

Quirrell shook his head, carefully waved his wand, and the glass shards were gone. He looked and moved as if every part of him were focussing on the simple cleaning spell.

"I think," Quirrell said slowly and deliberately, "that it would be best, if we are to work together, if you explain to me just how your magic works."

Milo shrugged.

"It's simple enough. There are ten levels of spells, from 0th to 9th. There are thousands of spells out there that wizards have invented (and a few dozen by Sorcerers), but I can only cast ones that I've written into my spellbook. Every morning, I can prepare a fixed list of spells from my book, and I can cast those—and only those—at any point that I want. How many spells, and of what level, is determined by my Wizard level—not to be confused with spell level. I'm a level five Wizard," Milo said proudly, "so I can cast up to 3rd-level spells. At every second Wizard level, I can cast a higher level of spell."

"So, you can increase in level? How?" Again, Quirrell seemed to be spending a large amount of effort concentrating on his words. Maybe it's a trick to avoid stuttering? Milo thought.

"There are a few ways, but the main one is combat. Defeating monsters and such gives me Experience Points, when I have enough of those I go up a level."

"You said you could cast up to 3rd-level spells. Could you give me an example?"

"Sure... Summon Hippogriff."

Milo decided, in hindsight, that summoning the largest possible creature that he could manage into Quirrell's compact little office may not have been the best idea.

The Hippogriff, a massive, aggressive Magical Beast that looked like the front of a giant eagle on the body of a horse, let out a roar that knocked the stunned Quirrell out of his chair.

"Uh," he said. "Sorry about that." With a deliberately casual wave of his hand, Milo dismissed the voracious omnivore before it developed a taste for human flesh.

"So, you gain power directly by being involved in combat? By defeating your foes?"

"Yup."

"Does the strength of the foe matter?"

"Oh, yeah. The harder the challenge, the more XP I get—assuming, of course, that I survive."

"Indeed."

"So, about the vampires and Protection from Evil—" Milo began.

"It is of no matter. I already told you that I don't..." Quirrell paused. "I mean, as I was telling your doppelganger, I don't believe the Dark Lord will become a vampire; he has always believed strongly in blood purity" he said, smoothly changing the topic.

"That's why the villains always lose," Milo said. "Blinded by their own prejudices and killing their own minions. If I had minions," Milo said with a slightly dreamy expression, "I'd treat them right. Well, I mean, I'd work them like slaves, I wouldn't pay them, and I'd feed them only enough to keep them from starving to death—it's just efficient—but aside from that, I'd treat them right. Oh, and if I can find some way to keep them working without needing sleep, I'd use that, of course, but honestly."

"Do you have any theories," Quirrell said carefully, cutting off Milo's rambling speech, "as to why Lucius brought you here?"

Milo frowned.

"I'd just sort of assumed it was an accident," he said. "I mean, whatever they were doing, it didn't look like they expected an eleven year-old to appear on their dining room table in the middle of it."

"And yet, you yourself admitted that you could, one day, have the power to bring back their lord."

"I don't follow," Milo confessed.

"You can bring back the dead," Quirrell said. "That makes you, Milo, a prize greater than any Philosopher's Stone."

Before Milo could respond, there was a brisk rap on the door.

"E-enter," Quirrell said, looking frustrated, his concentration evidently broken.

The door opened to reveal a very, very angry looking Professor McGonagall.

"You," she said, pointing at Milo. "Come with me." Her tone brooked no dissent.

o—o—o—o

"Blimey," said Fred as Harry was carried out of the stands.

"Just once, we're going to be able to throw a party on a Friday—" said George.

"—and the star of the show won't be in the hospital wing—"

"—and on that day, the house-elves will overthrow their masters, and become lords of the universe."

Chapter 20: The Mirror of Erised

Author's Notes: Sorry for the short chapter this week (a mere 7 pages instead of the usual 10). I'm out of town with the family, so next week's chapter will either be short as well or delayed a few days (Monday most likely, Tuesday at the very latest). Also, as a result, this chapter hasn't been edited for grammar and spelling as thoroughly as they usually are, but I'll come back and clean it up later. Hopefully it's not too bad. Sorry about all that! Hopefully all the bonus chapters last week and the week before make up for it.

Anyways, on with the story!

EDIT: Most of the typoes and things seem to have been caught now. Thanks to everyone who helped point them out!

o—o—o—o—o—o—o

"Look, I know people always say you look just like your dad, but with your mum's eyes —" Ron said.

"No, that's not what I meant. I actually saw my parents in this mirror. And their parents, and their brothers and sisters, and a whole family." Harry told them how, the night before, he'd gone exploring under his Cloak of Invisibility and discovered the magical mirror in an unused classroom.

"Wow," said Ron, clearly impressed. "That must be some mirror."

"Show me," said Milo.

"Wait!" said Hannah. "You can't just go gallivanting off! You're supposed to have complete bed rest, remember?"

"You sound just like Hermione," Ron muttered.

"Someone has to," said Hannah defensively.

Milo cursed. She was actually right — if he got out of bed, he'd have to come back and stay a whole 'nother day to get back to full hit points.

"I think I'll have to chance it," Milo said. With luck (something he very rarely seemed to have) he wouldn't be needing all of his hit points for at least another day or so. Harry's mirror, however, might not be there tomorrow at all, and frankly, it seemed fairly plot-relevant.

"Let's go find it," Milo said, ignoring Hannah's protests. "But first, Harry — put it on your list. That, the Power of Love, and the Imperius Curse."

Harry shrugged, pulling the small stack of parchment which held The List (Milo made a note to make a few backups of it with Amanuensis or the Pen of Plagiarism +5, just in case) out of his school bag and diligently wrote them down.

Milo uncomfortably pulled his filthy Robe of Arcane Might over his pajamas. The way things were going recently, he didn't want to waste a Prestidigitation to clean it off — there was no telling when he was going to be ambushed next.

"All right," he said. "Lead on."

Harry, Ron, and Milo strode out of the hospital wing

"We should hide under the cloak," Harry suggested when they were out of earshot of the other patients.

"Oh, come on," Milo scoffed. "Three people can't wear one magic item. It just can't be done. I know I like to bend the rules sometimes, but seriously. Three people under one cloak? That's a stretch."

"Really?" Harry asked. "That's somewhat surprising. It seems large enough to cover all of us; I mean, it was made for an adult, right?"

"Trust me," Milo said authoritatively. "It's patently impossible. It'd be like trying to cast a spell in the same turn as running, or drinking two potions in a six-second period. Can't be done. End of story."

"Huh," said Harry. "Go figure. Okay, well you should wear it, then, because you're supposed to still be in the hospital wing."

"Good plan," Milo said, pulling the cloak over his dirty, bloodstained magic robes. "All right, let's go."

Harry led them through some unfamiliar Hogwarts corridors (always a rather risky prospect), past a door pretending to be a wall (and once, embarrassingly, directly into a wall pretending to be a door), down a staircase that turns into a ramp if you don't ask it nicely not to, and, finally, into an old, abandoned classroom. The Cloak of Invisibility turned out to be unnecessary, as the only person they encountered (if the word 'person' could even be applied here) was the Bloody Baron, who, as usual, ignored them entirely. In the classroom were cobwebs and a thick coating of dust on most of the desks and chairs, except for a wide corridor down the middle where a number of them had been pushed to the side — presumably to allow persons unknown to carry in Harry's mirror, which sat at the front of the room, where the Professor would stand to lecture the class.

Milo let out a low whistle.

"Now that," he said, "is one Hell of a magicky-looking item." The mirror was, for one, huge. It's top nearly touched the ceiling, and Milo couldn't figure out how anyone could possibly have gotten it through the door. The frame was of intricately worked gold, and if that didn't scream Magic, nothing did.

"That the technical term, you figure?" Ron asked wryly.

"Come on," Harry said impatiently. "Sit in front of it and look, it's my mum and dad."

"Whoa, hold on there," Milo said. "If there's one thing you learn as an Adventurer it's that you don't just go looking in random magic mirrors before finding out exactly what they do."

"But I know what this one does," Harry protested. "It shows my parents."

"Maybe," Milo said cautiously. "I've seen mirrors that create evil copies of anyone who looks at them, mirrors that suck you in and trap you, mirrors that blast you forwards in time, mirrors that switch your mind with the owner's, mirrors that make Suggestions you can't refuse —"

"My mirror does that!" Ron interrupted. "Tells me whether my shirt's untucked, my laces are undone, or there's something in my teeth! And when you ignore it, blimey, does it make a fuss."

"But this mirror doesn't do anything like that!" Harry protested again. "I looked into it, and I'm fine!"

Milo looked at him suspiciously.

"How do we know that?" he asked. "Seems awfully suspicious, doesn't it? I mean, if you were possessed by some evil being who placed the mirror here, the first thing you'd do is try to convince others to look at it, too, wouldn't you?"

"But I'm not — I'm fine, really. You're just paranoid 'cause of Hannah."

"Use Protection From Weevils," Ron suggested. "Remember, the thing you did on Hannah that made her Hannah again?"

"Good thinking. Protection From Evil," Milo cast on Harry. The Boy-Who-Lived was surrounded by a brief glow which faded in a fraction of a second. "Feel any different now?"

"No," Harry said with an audible edge in his voice. "Because I wasn't possessed. Can we look at the mirror now, or do you want to throw me in the water and see if I float first?"

"Why would I —"

"Ah, nevermind. Just look at the bloody thing."

"Fine," Milo said. "Ron, you go first." If the mirror did launch some form of attack, Milo figured that, of the three of them, he would be the best equipped to deal with it and therefore couldn't afford to be neutralized on the first round. That was his story, and he was sticking to it. Eagerly, Ron stepped forwards and stared at the mirror.

Ron gasped, and Milo nearly started raining arcane doom everywhere before he started speaking again.

"Blimey! I'm — I'm head boy!" Ron said, astonished. "And I'm holding the Quidditch Cup! I — wow, it looks like I'm captain of the team!"

"What?" Harry asked. "Let me see that!" Giving Ron a little shove, he positioned himself right in front of the mirror. "No, look, see? It's my mum and dad! They're right there in front of us!"

"Maybe," Ron said slowly, "it's different for everyone?" Then his eyes widened. "Do you reckon it shows the future?"

"How can it?" Harry asked. "All my family are dead, remember?"

"That doesn't really mean anything," Milo said. "There's no reason, beyond the fact that it would be highly improbable, that Ron couldn't become both head boy and Quidditch captain."

"But —"

"And as for your parents, well, there's dozens of ways for my kind of magic to bring back the dead," Milo said slowly.

"Right," Harry said in an odd voice. "I'd forgotten about that." Perhaps it was an unusually high Sense Motive roll for once, or Milo's recent ... confused state, but something told him that Harry was lying and hadn't, in fact, forgotten for a moment that Milo could, one day, Limited Wish Harry's parents back to life.

"Well," Milo said eventually, screwing up his courage. "I think, maybe, I should have a go at the mirror."

With a fair amount of trepidation, Milo stepped up in front of the ornate mirror while trying to avoid thinking of all the various kinds of horrible, trapped mirrors out there. Now that he thought about it, he couldn't recall a single magical mirror that didn't have some form of vicious curse. His eyes were still carefully averted, staring at the toes of his adventurer's boots.

Why, oh why did I use my only Protection From Evil on Harry? Milo berated himself.

Steadying himself with deep, calming breaths, Milo forced his eyes to stare directly at the polished silver surface.

The universe unveiled itself in front of him, and, while, conceptually at least, Milo knew from Wizards experimenting with Divinations and Greater Teleport that the distance between stars was inconceivably far and that the distance between galaxies made even that colossal distance seem completely negligible, Milo could see, clearly, pinpoints of light unfolding before him in numbers so large that they didn't have names. Many of those stars had planets, and many of those planets had moons, and a rare few of those planets and moons had life. Milo saw stout, bearded dwarves bustling about in their mines and forges, not knowing that with every greedy swing of their pick they unwittingly brought themselves one step closer to their own inexorable demise as they approached the horrors which lay beneath their underground cities. Milo saw proud elves, comfortable in the fact that they'd been toying with the very fabric of the universe and living in shining cities and soaring towers while the lesser races had yet to discover fire; blind, in their arrogance, to their ever-waning power, numbers, and relevance to the world outside of their sequestered paradises. Milo saw humans beyond number, living their lives, tilling soil, and always expanding outwards, propelled by their adventurous spirit and search for excitement, not knowing what was in store for them when they found there nowhere else to discover. Milo saw ankhegs, centaurs, chimera, dragons, gnomes, halflings, half-elves, aquatic elves, wood elves, dark elves, high elves, gray elves, wild elves, wood elves, orcs, goblins, hobgoblins, bugbears, half-orcs, magmin, barghests, blink dogs, dinosaurs, dire animals, ghosts, ghouls, ogres, oozes, mephits, medusae, merfolk, sahuagin, sprites, lamias, wyverns, will-o-wisps, and wraiths. Milo saw the entirety of the Prime Material as if he were examining every object, creature, and wisp of smoke with intense scrutiny. Milo saw the Great Wheel of the Outer Planes, the sixteen infinitely large planes of Celestia, Bytopia, Elysium, the Beastlands, Arborea, Ysgard, Limbo, Pandemonium, the Abyss, Carceri, Hades, Gehenna, Baator, Acheron, Mechanus, and Arcadia arranged clockwise around the barren Outlands, which, from its heart, rose the impossibly tall Spire, ringed at its peak by Sigil, The City of Doors. Milo saw the Lower Planes ripped apart by the never ending Blood War and the uncaring laughter of their thirsting gods. Milo saw the Inner Planes of Air, Fire, Earth, Water, and Positive and Negative energy from which the Multiverse itself was made. Milo saw the Astral, Ethereal, Shadow, and elusive Mirror Transitive planes, and the madness of the Far Realm. Milo saw the Multiverse in its entirety, and it was all his.

Milo saw himself, with an infinitely high level in every Class and Prestige Class, with every feat worth taking and a good many that aren't, with infinite ranks in infinite skills, with infinite ability scores and infinite ability modifiers, with infinite hit points, with infinite spells per day and every spell known, lounging on what, at first glance, appeared to be an intricately carved throne of every precious metal, expensive special material, and gemstone Milo had ever heard of (and several others, as well) but upon closer inspection were, in fact, Epic Magic Items and Artifacts. Milo saw a backrest composed of dozens of Staffs of the Magi sitting on piles of Rings of Universal Energy Immunity and Bracers of Relentless Might. One armrest was simply the Axe of the Dwarvish Lords while the other appeared to be the great battleaxe of Heironeous Himself, sitting on a pile of the six weapons of his archenemy, Hextor. Milo, the most powerful character conceivable, lounged on his terrible throne, staring at His gauntleted hand (in some detached part of his brain, Milo realized it was nothing less than the Iron Gauntlet of War), an expression of detached ennui on his blank face. In his other hand, he idly spun the Gold Dragon Orb around his fingers, one of the most powerful artifacts in creation reduced to a mere stress ball. Who has any need of an Orb of Dragonkind, even the most powerful one, when Milo could simply rewrite reality to create a breed of better dragons, forced to bow to his every will?

Milo had no enemies, for they had all long since been defeated. He had no adventures to undertake, for there were none of an appropriate Encounter Level. He had no friends, for he needed none. He had no dungeons to raid, for he had the Multiverse in his inventory. He had no familiar, for they could be traded for more powerful alternate class features. He had no partymembers, because in the impossible event that he would need allies, what could be more powerful than Simulacra of himself?

The Milo in the mirror had everything he'd ever wanted, everything he'd ever seen, everything he'd ever heard of, everything he'd ever only conceived of.

Milo —the real Milo — wasn't sure when he'd started screaming. He felt hands (the detached part of his brain that kept noticing minute details even in impossible situations noted that it must have been Ron and Harry, not that the rest of him cared) struggling to pull him away from the mirror, but even as they dragged him away from it he couldn't summon the willpower to tear his eyes from the horrible visage. Eventually, one of them wrapped the Cloak of Invisibility around the artifact, and the visions stopped — but the memories remained.

"What the bloody hell was that?" Ron asked, his face pale and bloodless.

"I... I saw everything," Milo said weakly. He tasted blood in his mouth, he must have bit his tongue at some point. "And ... and it was mine. I had everything ... everything except a reason to..." he trailed off, his brain still not fully functioning.

"Reason to what, mate?" Ron asked nervously in an odd, falsely cheerful voice.

"Anything," Milo said. "No reason to anything."

"Look on the bright side," Ron said. "If that's the future, it means we beat You-Know-Who."

"You-Know-Who?" Milo asked, his voice full of scorn. "The me in the mirror could have vaporized You-Know-Who with a Silent Stilled Heightened Maximized Empowered Intensified Twinned Explosive Quickened Cantrip just by willing it to be so."

"But that's good, isn't it?"

"I'd imagine it would get dull after a few eons," Milo said, still trying to shake the horrifying images the mirror had shown him. Had it really shown him the future? What were the rules that governed it? "I'll need to take another look," Milo said eventually, staggering to his feet. He spat blood on the floor of the classroom, and wiped at his mouth with his even grimier robe.

"No," Harry said firmly. "Absolutely not."

"I need to know how it works," Milo said. "I need to know if that's really the future."

"You're not going anywhere near that thing," Harry insisted.

"Fine," Milo said sharply. "Then one of you two give it a close examination and tell me if you see anything weird. Look at the frame, and try not to get sucked in." Not even Milo was sure if he meant that last bit literally or figuratively. "I'll even close my eyes. See? 'Cause I don't. On account of my eyes being closed."

"I'm not taking the Invisibility Cloak off until you're out of the room or blindfolded," Harry said stubbornly.

With growing irritation brought on by his numerous injuries and conflicted feelings about his vision in the mirror, Milo muttered a few choice oaths as he fished a scarf out of his Belt of Hidden Pouches and obligingly tied it around his face.

"Can we get on with it now?" he snapped. Then he took a deep breath and tried to calm himself down. "Sorry," he said eventually, picturing their hurt expressions. "I'm still kind of in shock from the... mirror thing. And yesterday's thing." Then he realized what he was doing, and his breath caught. "Damnit! I shouldn't have to care about your feelings! Argh, let's just examine this mirror and get it over with already."

Milo heard a rustling of cloth as, presumably, the mirror's Cloak was lifted. There was silence as Ron and Harry were (hopefully) diligently examining the mirror's border and not being absorbed by its eldritch powers.

"Oi, Harry, look at this," Ron said.

"Yeah, I saw that," Harry said. "Just looked like a load of Gobbledegook to me."

"Nah, doesn't look anything remotely like Gobbledegook."

"Could one of you tell me, pray, what it is that you are speaking of?" Milo asked.

"There's some writing on the mirror," Harry said. "But it's nonsense."

There were a number of ways Milo had available to transmute nonsensical writing into its sensical variant, but all of them required that he be able to actually see the words in front of him.

"Write it down on some parchment," Milo said. "Make sure you get it exactly right — does it use the Common alphabet?"

"Uh..."

"English. The English alphabet."

"Oh, yeah, definitely."

"Fortuitous. Shouldn't be too hard, then." Milo heard the unbuttoning of a school bag and hurried scratching of a quill before a piece of parchment was placed into his hands. Milo very carefully turned so he was facing away from the mirror and removed his blindfold. Written on a small scrap of parchment was, in Harry's scrawl,

Erised stra ehru oyt ube cafru oyt on wohsi.

Milo stared at it for a moment, but concluded it wasn't in any language he recognized.

"Comprehend Languages," he cast, a spell which allowed him to understand any written and spoken language. To his faint surprise, the writing remained completely nonsensical — the only conclusion was that it had to be in code of some form.

"I'll have to do this the good old fashioned way," Milo muttered. He'd been habitually placing skill ranks in Decipher Script every level because it was Intelligence-based and understanding ancient runes seemed the sort of thing a Wizard ought to be able to do, but he hadn't actually had a chance to use them before. Nevertheless, inconsequential problems such as never having tried to decipher anything before did nothing to prevent the fact that, by any standard, Milo was very nearly an expert cryptoanalyst. Milo was a little excited to finally have the opportunity to put his Skills to use, testing them against the no doubt formidable defences of the accursed mirror. He cracked his knuckles and stretched, pulling out a few sheets of parchment and his quill. It was time for some serious, heavy-duty Script Deciphering.

"It's backwards," he said, sounding somewhat disappointed. "I show not your face but your hearts [sic] desire."

"Your heartsick desire, eh?" said Ron skeptically. "That sounds sort of ... racy, to be honest."

"No —"

"Maybe it was confused," Harry mused. "Because we haven't got any heartsick desires, so it just showed us whatever we wanted to see?"

"But —"

"So, you reckon the mirror just shows you whatever you want?" Ron asked, impressed. "Clever, Harry."

Milo simply groaned and seriously contemplated applying his forehead directly to a very inviting-looking hewn stone wall when a thought struck him.

The mirror shows you your heart's desire, he thought. Even if you don't already know what it looks like —like Harry's parents or my, well, my entire Multiverse.

Milo's face broke into a wide grin. He saw an exploit.

All I have to do is figure out how to change my heart's desire, he realized, and I can see whatever I want.

Ron, however, was developing an increasingly worried look.

"There's something my dad always says," he said, "How did it go? Oh, right: Never trust anything that can think for itself if you can't see where it keeps its brain. Mind, I've gotten some right peculiar looks from his Ford Anglia now and again, and it seems perfectly friendly."

Infinite power might be my long-term goal, Milo thought, although, to be fair, I'm starting to seriously reconsider that. Well, within reason, anyways. But what I really want, right now, more than anything else, is to find out what Voldemort's up to. Yup, honest. That's what I want.

"Now show me, mirror," Milo said quietly, and turned around. As a precaution, he readied an action: look away if it shows me anything other than information on You-Know-Who. You can't back down from readied actions.

He winced in almost physical pain as he was given another infinitesimally short view of the Multiverse and his own horrible fate again.

"What are you doing?" Harry asked. "Don't look at the thing!"

"No, trust me," Milo said, clutching his aching forehead. "I know what I'm doing. Sort of."

Okay, so maybe I really don't care that much about the Dark Lord after all. How about something a little smaller... I want, more than anything, to see what Kelgore's Fire Bolt looks like written out in a spellbook. That was sort of true, in fact — he had just decided, after all, that it would be his next research project. If he could somehow finagle the mirror into showing him what to write in his spellbook, he could save a week's work and a thousand gold pieces.

When Milo turned around again, it was with enough presage to fill a Type II Bag of Holding. Unfortunately, the mirror once again saw through his mental tricks, and he was treated to a view of Mirror-Milo killing time by covering every square inch of the Prime Material in Arcane Marks.

"I'm getting away from this thing," he said, flinching and attempting to look anywhere other than at the nightmare being played out in the glass. "The mirror, it's... it's... agh, nevermind. I'm going back to bed."

He'd been about to say 'the mirror, it's Evil,' but it clearly wasn't. It was absolutely, brutally, horribly Neutral. It showed you what your heart desired, but sometimes, what you desire isn't the same as what you desire you'd desire...

As Milo walked back to the hospital wing, his head off in space, he suddenly had another idea.

"I wonder if someone here can bewitch me to desire nothing more than the spellbook entry for Kelgore's Fire Bolt?" he mused aloud. "Or other spells, for that matter. Mordy, remind me to ask Hermione, okay? Thanks."

Milo's familiar poked its furry head out of his extradimensional belt and nodded.

Maybe it was simply an unusually good roll, or maybe it was the +2 bonus to Spot and Listen granted from his bond with Mordy, but Milo suddenly felt as if a White Dragon was breathing down the back of his neck. Mordy's ears perked up, suddenly alert.

Milo knew not to look around stupidly and say 'Hello? Ron, is that you? Harry? This isn't funny, guys!,' followed by the inevitable 'Aaaaargh!' as whatever it was that was hiding out there ate his face. Instead, our gallant hero simply licked his suddenly-dry lips and walked forwards as casually as he could manage.

Cursing himself for leaving the Cloak of Invisibility with Harry and Ron, Milo reckoned his best chance was to — wait...

Harry and Ron.

Patting his pockets as if he had forgotten something, Milo cursed in a somewhat overdramatic fashion (not having any ranks in Disguise or Bluff, Milo was a terrible actor) and started to return to the room with the mirror. Whatever it was that had triggered Milo's Spot check (if that was, indeed, what it had been) had easy access to those two, who, still being relative novices at this plane's peculiar branch of magic, were nearly defenceless. Equally importantly, Milo didn't particularly want to face it alone in his current state.

While turning around and searching his pockets, Milo had a chance to look around the corridor, which remained empty save for the obligatory suits of armour and statuary. Mio considered casting See Invisibility, but remembered how that had seemed to have no effect, oddly, on whatever it was Snape had used to hide himself in his office before the Quidditch match.

"Detect Thoughts," Milo muttered under his breath. Mere Invisibility would be of no use against the spell, which revealed the presence — and, if he concentrated on it long enough, the number — of intelligent, conscious creatures in a cone emanating from Milo.

The spell immediately alerted him that he was right — something intelligent was standing within sixty feet of him. Milo forced himself not to look around nervously, waiting for the spell to cough up how many people — or bloodsucking monsters — there were skulking around him.

When it finally did, Milo was so surprised that it almost broke his concentration on the spell. He'd thought there would be one, or two at the most, sneaky persons and/or bloodsucking monstrosities for him to Glitterdust and run away from.

Within the fairly narrow conical field that Detect Thoughts covers, Milo detected in the seemingly-empty corridor no less than twelve sentient creatures.

Chapter 24: Nick of Time

Author's Notes: For those who don't know, the Far Realm is basically the Elemental Plane of Cthulhu. Also, Liquid Sunlight can be found on page 110 of Complete Scoundrel and is useful for literally any character.

Minor Rules Note: I only realized today that 3.0 and 3.5 have different XP reward rules. I never did get the 3.5 DMG and the SRD doesn't have the XP chart, so who knew? Because it's what I'm more familiar with, I, as DM, rule that Harry Potter and the Natural 20 uses 3.0's system for that alone. Anyways, on with the story!

ORWELLIAN EDIT: Fixed a number of typos and some weird tense problems.

EDIT2: To clarify, I'm using 3.0's Experience Point rules, but 3.5 rules everything else. The difference is that 3.0 awards XP based on the average party level (so the PCs all get the same amount), whereas 3.5 awards it by the character's individual level (so lower-level PCs get more than higher-level ones from the same fight).

o—o—o—o—o—o—o

Milo had heard it said that a Wizard, given time to prepare, could defeat any obstacle in existence. To be fair, most of these times had been from Milo's own mouth. Also, the saying assumed the Wizard had access to Magic Item dealers and a way to purchase spells. And, for that matter, three to four meatshields. That said, walking down the dirt path to the Forbidden Forest at 8:00PM on Friday evening, Milo felt ready for anything.

He had a holy symbol of Boccob around his neck with his Amulet of Protection From Evil, a holy symbol of Pelor wrapped around his left wrist like a bracelet and a holy symbol of Heironeous around his right — even Mordy, sitting on his shoulder, had a compact symbol of the local variety (just a pair of lines intersecting at a right angle; how boring could you get?) held prominently in his hand. The symbols were all of silver and polished till they shone like mirrors for optimum effect. He'd whittled twelve wooden stakes, six of which he kept in his Belt and six scattered about his person. That morning, he'd poured several pounds of fine garlic powder into the water supply before showering; the other Gryffindors had not been amused, but, Milo was pretty sure, neither would any vamps who tried to suck his blood.

Somewhat more significantly, Milo had finally finished the Headband of Intellect +4 that he'd been putting off for months (in actuality, it was a small, discreet silver hairclip that would be all but impossible to notice in his tangled hair — local wizards, from what Milo could tell, rarely, if ever, wore the headbands that were all the rage back in Myra (city oflight!cityofmagic!), but Milo still thought of it as a headband). In addition to making him marginally better at crossword puzzles, the Headband significantly increased the number of spells Milo could prepare every morning. Spells which Milo had finally gotten around to researching and he was dying to test out, ideally on some unsuspecting bloodsuckers.

And this time, if only for the novelty of it, Milo had decided to actually make sure that local vampires were anything like the vampire's back home. Quirrell had given him permission to read books from the restricted section on the subject, and, fortunately, they seemed more or less the same as what he was familiar with. Pale skin? Check. Inexplicably heavy accents? Check. Vulnerability to sunlight, running water, garlic, and mirrors? Check. Fangs? You betcha.

What had surprised Milo, however, was their apparent acceptance in wizard society. From what he could tell, they were persecuted, sure, but were still allowed to walk down the street in broad daylight (so to speak). Fred and George said that Honeydukes even sold blood-flavoured lollypops, although he wasn't sure how far he could believe anything they told him. Throughout the Azel empire, being publically known as a vampire was a death sentence. Werewolves seemed to be similarly treated, which, once again, it made Milo wonder why, exactly, everyone claimed there were werewolves living in the Forbidden Forest when there seemed nothing illegal with them simply renting a flat in Cardiff. Ah, well, Milo thought, best not draw too much attention to it. It was a well-known fact that the universe generally responded poorly to any attempt to draw attention to its numerous flaws.

As to these particular vampires, Milo assumed they were either criminals or ex-followers of Voldemort on the run. Either way, Milo thought grimly, they picked the wrong forest to haunt.

"Y-you're late," Quirrell said calmly as he approached the Defence Professor standing on the snowy path, silhouetted by light from the castle.

"A Wizard is never late," Milo intoned, as if quoting an ancient saying.

"Most t-timepieces would d-d-disagree with you," Quirrell said. "Irregardless," (Milo winced) "we m-must p-press on."

"Oh," Milo said suddenly. "Before I forget, you'd best take this." Milo fished out a small necklace from his belt and held it out for Quirrell.

"W-what is it?" Quirrell asked curiously.

"Amulet of Protection From Evil," Milo explained. "In case they try to Dominate —"

Quirrell dropped the Amulet as if it were a Stone of Weight.

"I th-think," Quirrell stammered, "that it w-w-would interfere w-w-with my... p-protective Charms. Y-y-you t-t-take it."

Milo blinked. Quirrell was lying. He'd actually made a Sense Motive check for once.

"Sure," Milo said, keeping his voice neutral. "Mordy can wear it." Why would he refuse protection? Milo wondered. He could only think of three reasons: either Quirrell wanted to be possessed by something, he was already Imperius'd and his controller ordered him to drop it, or he had a different magical amulet on already — wearing two at once prevented either from working reliably. Milo dismissed the first as patently ridiculous, and as for the third ... there was no reason, as far as Milo could tell, for Quirrell to lie about that. So. Quirrell was already controlled by the enigmatic ... whoever.

Unless I failed my Sense Motive check so badly I registered a false positive, Milo thought. No, wait ... that's impossible, isn't it? Because a Sense Motive check wouldn't even be called unless he was Bluffing. I think. Milo had never paid all that much attention to the NPC interaction rules — that's what Bards were for. Well, it was biting him now. Next time I'm home, I'm buying a rulebook and I'm going to Autohypnosis the entire thing, no matter how long it takes.

Regardless, Milo didn't see that he had much choice. If Quirrell was possessed, he'd very likely just kill Milo if he tried to flee. If Quirrell wasn't possessed, then there'd be no reason to flee, anyways.

"Okay, let's go," Milo said, his voice steady with confidence he no longer felt. Quirrell gave a barely perceptible nod and headed off to the forest. "What's the plan?" Milo asked, falling into step with the professor.

"W-we go in, w-we s-send them b-b-back to their f-f-foul m-master, w-we g-go home."

"Fair enough. Does the Killing Curse work on vampires?"

"It w-works on anything," Quirrell smiled. "Except f-for D-Dementors." Milo bit his lip to keep from blurting out that he had a pretty good idea of something else the Killing Curse wouldn't work against. I should probably keep that little gem close to my chest until I find out why Quirrell is lying to me. However, it did imply that the local vampires were somewhat different from what Milo could not help but consider 'normal' ones.

"This Plane is so weird," Milo said under his breath. "I wonder if I didn't accidentally fall into the Far Realm somehow." Milo harboured brief thoughts of having, maybe, gone beyond the Far Realm, but cut that line off quickly; madness lay in that direction. "Any idea of their numbers?"

"N-No."

"Well, you, sir, are just full of useful information today, aren't you?"

"These ... Experience P-Points"— Quirrell's mouth twisted with obvious distaste —"of w-which you sp-speak... w-will y-you earn them if I d-defeat the v-v-v... the c-creatures of d-darkness?" Quirrell said it as if he were simply making conversation.

"Yup," Milo said cheerfully, "just so long as I help in some way."

The Forbidden Forest, unusual among forests of the world, had a very clear and obvious boundary. On one side of an invisible line lay grassy areas where students were allowed and Hagrid lived; on the other, dense, dark, deep, dangerous woodland. Whether this was due to concerted effort on Hagrid's part, some powerful anti-growth Charm, or just one of nature's quirks, the result was a veritable wall of trees. Quirrell simply walked calmly down the path into the cavernous woods, but Milo paused at the border.

"Just because every trip you've made into this place has ended in disaster doesn't mean this one will," he said quietly to himself. "Besides, it's just trees." Wizards and forests, historically, do not get along well. Wizards generally prefer to live either in massive metropolises surrounded by other Wizards, or, alternatively, in precariously crooked towers on the edge of sheer cliffs or floating in the centre of a volcano. Forests, on the other hand, were strictly the domain of Druids (and the odd Cleric of Obad-Hai, god of nature, but Milo generally thought of those as wannabe Druids). Druids and Wizards got along like orange juice and toothpaste. "I am a master of the arcane powers that make the cosmic forces of the universe my plaything nineteen times per day," he said to himself, "and there ain't no fur-wearing treehugger that's going to stop me from going where I please."

If he said it firmly enough, he reasoned to himself, he might actually believe it.

Without further delay, he hustled into the woods after Quirrell.

"Lumos," Quirrell cast, and the tip of his wand began to glow like a torch. Milo winced as his eyes re-adjusted to the light and realised that, if he were ever separated from the Defence Professor or Quirrell dismissed the spell, Milo would be all but blind in the darkness. Milo could, if he wanted to, cast Dancing Lights to create lights of his own, but they only lasted for a minute and he could only do it once.

Instead, he fished out his liquid sunlight from his Belt of Hidden Pouches. The small glass sphere held a glowing golden liquid that was originally intended as a grenadelike weapon to mildly irritate light-sensitive creatures (or do negligible damage to vampires, for that matter), however, it proved universally more popular pressed into service as a torch that could never go out — and all for much less gold than an Everburning Torch.

Passing the glowing sphere up to his familiar to carry, Milo eyed the sides of the path with caution. The last time he'd been down this way, he'd been with Hagrid to collect the rope and canvas he'd used the time before the last time he'd been here. And that time...

Milo's shiver had nothing to do with the icy wind.

"When we get to the vampire nest," Milo said, "We should try to get them all in a group. I'll immobilize the lot, then you pick them off one by one." By far the most effective use of Arcane Magic in combat was at disabling large numbers of enemies simultaneously, generally for the Big Stupid Fighters to move in and finish the job. Milo had one Kelgore's Fire Bolt prepared just in case, but Quirrell would be infinitely more effective at single-target killing than Milo ever would be.

Assuming he's not possessed by Lucius or Voldemort or someone...

Well, if it came to that, Milo was prepared. He would bet his life — in fact, that's exactly what he was betting — that he'd found a way around the Killing Curse. To a certain extent. For a few seconds. With luck.

As long as he won Initiative, that is.

Not for the first — or the last — time he wished he were a Cleric and could just cast Death Ward.

"Be silent," Quirrell hissed. Milo hadn't realized that he was still repeating 'I am a master of the arcane powers that make the cosmic forces of the universe my plaything. I am a master of the arcane powers that make the cosmic forces of the universe my plaything...' over and over under his breath. Around him, dark bushes and creepers, almost black in the darkness, seemed to be reaching towards him hungrily.

"Sorry," Milo muttered.

"Foliage," Quirrell whispered. "Three O'Clock."

The instant of warning was all Milo needed to avoid being taken by surprise as the monstrous spider — Acromantula, he reminded himself — leapt from nearby undergrowth at him.

"Kelgore's Fire Bolt." The spider erupted into flame in midair and came crashing into the earth with a heavy thud, where it lay still. "I don't understand," Milo said. "Everything I've read said these bugs were smart — almost as smart as humans, actually. Supposedly, they can even talk."

"C-correct," Quirrell said.

"So... why do they keep rushing me like this?" Milo wondered. "They can shoot webs. They can think for themselves. Hells, they're even supposed to ..." Milo's voice trailed off somewhat as realized what he was about to say. They hunt in packs. "Glitterdust!"

Shining golden particles — no matter how many times he cast the spell, Milo was always struck by how pretty they were (not that he'd ever admit to thinking that; it'd be undignified in a Wizard) — exploded around them. Milo generally used the spell to blind his enemies, but, in this case, it's other function — to reveal targets — served just as well.

What Milo had taken to be a cluster of particularly evil-looking shrubbery revealed it's sinister nature as a writhing, dark sea of chitin.

"Aw, Hells," Milo said. "Run?"

"R-run," Quirrell agreed. The forest exploded all around them as they bolted down the path, the spiders' hard carapace making angry chittering sounds as they rubbed against each other.

"Why do the spiders hate me so much?" Milo asked as he practically flew down the path. "I mean, what did I do to them? Except kill their nephew."

He risked a glance over his shoulder and was surprised to see barely a speck of golden light. At first, he thought that maybe he'd managed to lose his pursuers — then the more pragmatic, less wildly optimistic part of his brain added, helpfully, that no, he hadn't lost them; the Glitterdusted Acromantulas were simply being blocked by the swarming masses of their non-glowing brethren.

Not only am I going to be eaten, Milo thought grimly, but I've already garnished myself up for it. He was practically sweating garlic. While Milo knew, academically, that Acromantulas were not the Monstrous Spiders of home, they seemed closely related; Monstrous Spiders, no matter how large, moved at the same speed as an unencumbered human. The Acromantulas, if they were gaining on him at all, were doing it slowly.

What they did have that he didn't was endurance. Why the Hells did I dump Constitution for Charisma? That has to be the stupidest thing done by a Wizard since the dawn of time.

Boccob, god of magic, has a higher Charisma than Constitution, part of his brain added in defence. Milo's breaths were becoming increasingly laboured, and his legs burned with effort. Quirrell, running very slightly ahead of him, seemed to be doing just fine.

You—are—not—Boccob, the other part of his brain added vehemently.

Everybody's a critic.

"I don't suppose," Milo said between beleaguered breaths, "that you can do some magic on them?"

"Against one? M-maybe. B-but on f-fifty?"

"Screw this," Milo muttered. "Time for plan B. Web!" Layers of sticky strands, stronger than steel, shot out of his hands and created a near-solid wall of silky webs between the trees on either side of the trail.

Web is one of those beautiful, beautiful spells in which, even if the victims make their saving throws, they're still pretty much screwed.

"How's that for delicious irony, eh? Eh? Think twice before you try to eat a Wizard, next time!" Milo shouted at the trapped spiders, who were angrily clawing at his webs. "Now you kill one or two," Milo added to Quirrell. Even as he spoke, he saw that no less than three spiders had nearly managed to free themselves from his webs; doubtless, several others further back were trying to find a way around.

"Avada Kedavra, Avada Kedavra," Quirrell cast the Unforgivable Curses (that is, Unforgivable when used on a human) as dispassionately as one would swat a fly. With a pair of eye-searing green flashes, two trapped spiders abruptly stopped struggling. "B-but I d-don't see... ah," Quirrell suddenly realized. The spiders' — those that still lived — struggling had taken on a very different form.

"'When you're being chased by an Owlbear in the woods,'" Milo quoted, "'you don't need to run faster than the Owlbear — just faster than the delicious, juicy Halfling.' Still, we'd best move along."

Despite the grisly carnage behind him, Milo grinned. Just like that, he'd covered one-third of the distance to level six. As he cautiously walked down the snowy path with Quirrell and ran the numbers on the Experience Points, his smile started to slip.

"Together we killed three spiders," Milo said quietly. "and I got 450 XP each. I got 600 from the one back in September, but I was lower level then..." he frowned. "...which is exactly how much I would have gotten if it were CR 6 and I had help from..." Abruptly, Milo stopped moving. If he had help from a CR 12 ally each time.

"W-what was that?" Quirrell asked. "W-we really ought to p-press on. The A-Acromantulas will g-get through eventually."

"It was you," Milo said quietly.

"E-excuse me?"

"It was you, the whole time — I've been an idiot! You killed the Acromantula."

"Just c-calm down and —" without warning, Quirrell shouted "Oblivia—"

"Nerveskitter! Grease!" Quirrell's wand slid from his hands and buried itself in the snow. "You didn't think I'd say something like that without a Readied Action to back it up, would you? Mage Hand." Quirrell's wand flew into Milo's grasp. Thank you, Harry, for making me learn that trick.

"This is all just a b-big m-misunder —"

"You lost any chance of convincing me of that when you tried to erase my memory just now. So, who do you really work for? Lucius? Fudge?" Quirrell's mouth twitched slightly.

"I w-w-work for D-Dumbledore and the M-M-Minist—"

"Yeah, and I'm Pun-Pun the Kobold. Mordy — get the manacles." Milo kept a set of heavy steel manacles with one of the best locks on the market to avoid the infamous Prisoner's Dilemma (that is, what do Good adventurers do with captured Orcs?). Mordy dragged the manacles onto the ground at Quirrell's feet, then scurried back to Milo's shoulder. "Cuff yourself, and don't try anything funny if you want to avoid becoming a greasy stain on the ground." Milo was lying through his teeth — the magic he had available with the most killing potential was Acid Splash.

"This is m-m-madness," Quirrell said, but complied. "Y-you don't understand—"

"What I understand is that you've clearly been lying to me for some time — and you took my memories. I want to know why. And, Professor — make me believe it."

o—o—o—o

"Anybody seen Milo anywhere?" Ron asked. "His version of Wizard's Chess is surprisingly addictive."

"Nope, sorry," Hermione said, lying back in one of the Common Room's overstuffed armchairs.

"He had that mysterious assignment with Quirrell, remember?" Harry said.

"Oh, right," Hermione remembered. "The one he refused to talk about."

"He's going to the Forbidden Forest with Quirrell," Hannah said calmly. "They're going to hunt vampires."

"There aren't any vampires in the Forbidden Forest," Ron snorted. "The werewolves wouldn't put up with them. They hate each other so much it's proverbial."

"How did you know that, Hannah?" Hermione asked, ignoring Ron.

"He's a terrible liar," Hannah explained. "And whenever I asked him about it, he'd glance towards the forest. Also, he stayed up late sharpening stakes in the Common Room and said 'I'm going to the Forbidden Forest with Quirrell to hunt vampires,' but I don't think he realized I was there. He often doesn't."

"Oh," Hermione said. "So that's why none of the tables have got any legs."

"He's doing what?" Harry asked. "We have to go after him!"

"Into the Forest, mate? You're mad. There's giant spiders in the Forest." Ron looked like he'd rather kiss Snape than do what Harry suggested.

"Don't you remember what happened the last time he went into the Forbidden Forest with Quirrell?" Harry pressed.

"Was it that they found buried Galleons? Can it please be that they found buried Galleons?"

"He almost died, Ron."

"Oh, come on. Milo almost dies four times before getting out of bed every morning. He'll be fine."

Hermione frowned, and set aside her homework.

"I think Harry might be right," she said. "But so is Ron. Look at it like this, though: he's almost died, what, three times? Four?"

"Or thereabouts," Harry said.

"And why hasn't he? Died, I mean."

"Hermione!" Hannah sounded scandalized.

"No, I don't mean I want him to, I'm just asking how he always survives."

"Because..." Harry mused. "Well, he gets rescued a lot."

"Grab your Cloak," Hermione said, her tone allowing no possibility of dissent. She then glanced out the window. As much as Milo drove her crazy sometimes, they were friends. "And a scarf, it looks chilly."

o—o—o—o

"Fool," Quirrell said. "You have no idea of the f-forces with w-w-which you are m-meddling."

"I tend to hear that a lot," Milo shrugged. On his shoulder, his familiar mimicked the expression. "How about you just tell me, though? If you don't, I'm going to have to assume you're an enemy."

"I-is that s-supposed to be a th-threat?" Quirrell sneered contemptuously.

"Fine, don't tell me. Presumably, you're after the Stone? Eternal life does sound like a pretty sweet deal — although, if I leave you here for the vampires to find you, you might just wind up with eternal unlife. Assuming there even are any vampires, that is, and you didn't lie about that, too."

"Oh, the v-vampires are r-real, b-boy," Quirrell said. "And a-alone? B-by yourself? Th-they'll never let you leave the F-Forest alive."

"Detect Thoughts. Whatever you do, don't think about your boss." To Milo's surprise, he picked up, not one, but two sapient minds in front of him. "What the Hells —"

Without warning, the forest exploded into varicoloured light.

"Expelliarmus!" Quirrell's wand flew from Milo's grasp. "Petrificus Totalus!" Milo's hands suddenly flew to his sides and stayed there. All of his muscles stopped responding to movement, except, oddly, his eyes — he could look around unimpeded.

Half a dozen Death Eaters, masks and all, stepped out from the trees in a loose circle around Milo and Quirrell.

"It appears my son does not disappoint — for once," said an oily voice from behind one of the masks. "When he said you'd be leaving the castle with only a single teacher of dubious competence to protect you, I thought it was too good to be true. Fortune, it would seem, favours the patient."

Milo struggled to speak, but his jaw remained clamped firmly shut. Quirrell was looking at the Death Eaters with a dangerous glint in his eyes.

"R-release me, L-Lucius," Quirrell said. "And y-you will be r-r-rewarded b-beyond your —"

"Rewarded by you?" Lucius sneered. "What could I, the wealthiest wizard in magical England, have to gain by freeing you? Who even are you? I see no reason why I should not simply kill you on the spot."

"Y-you will f-face my w-wrath if you d-do this thing, Malfoy. F-for I am L-Lord—" Quirrell broke off, screaming in anguish. Lucius looked around at his Death Eaters.

"Did one of you...?" he left the question hanging. They all shook their heads, seeming equally perplexed at the cause of the Defence Professor's sudden pain.

"F-forgive me," Quirrell stammered. "P-perhaps it is b-better to say that I h-h-have the e-ear of one that e-even y-you, L-Lucius, w-would n-not long r-regret d-displeasing."

"Would not long regret..." Malfoy frowned.

"Because you'd be dead, boss," one of the masked wizards added helpfully.

"Yeah, you'd be departed, boss," said another.

"Yes, I got that, Crabbe. Goyle. Now be silent." Had the spell preventing him from moving allowed, Milo would have grinned. Like father, like son...

"I believe you're bluffing," Malfoy said finally. "Nobody with friends that powerful would settle at being a schoolteacher."

"N-no! L-Lucius, you f-fool, you d-don't under —"

"Stupefy," Malfoy cast, and Quirrell sagged against the tree. Lucius Malfoy bent over the unconscious teacher and softly whispered "Obliviate."

o—o—o—o

"Blimey," Ron said shakily. "What happened to all these spiders?" Through the folds of the Invisibility Cloak — Milo had been wrong, it had worked for multiple people at once — they could clearly see piles of dead Acromantulas surrounding a thick web.

"It looks like they... turned on each other," Hermione sounded sick. "Although several of them look, well, just fine."

"Except that they're stone cold dead," Harry added.

"I think we should keep going," Hannah said. "It's safe to assume that Milo had some hand in this. He can't go thirty minutes without needing someone to pull him out of the fire." Despite her words, she fingered a crude-looking flower at her lapel with a fond expression.

"Right," said Harry, feeling slightly embarrassed. "On we go."

"Er," said Ron, "I hate to be the bearer of bad news, but there's a big dirty web in front of us."

"Milo once told me that magical webs burn quickly," Hannah said.

"Brilliant," Ron said. "But where are we going to get any fire?"

Hermione gave him an incredulous look.

"Where are we going to — Are you a wizard or aren't you?"

"Oh, right," Ron said, looking sheepish. "Incendio!"

o—o—o—o

"You, boy, have given me no end of trouble," Lucius sneered, his eyes narrowing through the holes in his mask. "That ritual was hardly supposed to summon an eleven-year-old abomination like you, but you'll have to suffice."

Milo suddenly saw the reason for the Still and Silent Spell metamagic feats. Without the ability to speak or move his hands, he was completely helpless.

"Crabbe! Goyle! Carry him. We must move beyond the wards."

They're taking me beyond the wards? Milo wondered. So, they mean to Disapparate. If they did that, Milo could very well wind up imprisoned in a cavern somewhere in the Earth's crust, for all he knew. It could take him centuries to earn enough XP to be able to Teleport out of that without monsters to fight. Assuming they don't just kill me, of course.

Rough hands grabbed him by the scruff of the neck and half-carried, half-dragged him through the dark forest.

Well, he thought, I am royally screwed. At least I know Quirrell's up to something, for all the good that does me.

o—o—o—o

"Quiet!"Hermione suddenly hissed.

"What?" Ron asked.

"Don't you hear that? Someone's talking up ahead."

"I think I can see light," Harry said, squinting through his sight-augmenting glasses.

As quietly as they could, the four of them crept along the narrow, winding path towards the tiny points of light up ahead.

"Looks like four or five wands lit up," Harry said as they approached.

"But Quirrell and Milo only have two between them," Ron said.

"And Milo's doesn't even count," Hermione added.

"He could have used his Dancing Lights spell," Hannah said, peering through the trees. "It would look sort of like that." She sounded somewhat skeptical, though.

"Could be," Harry said dubiously.

"I think we should assume it isn't them," Hermione said. "And that they aren't friendly."

"Good plan," Harry said. He tried to sound confident, but, really... what could they possibly do against a group of fully-trained wizards? He'd only learned how to disarm less than a week ago.

Moving was awkward with four bodies under the Cloak, but they slowly gained ground on the party ahead of them.

Ron's voice caught as they came close enough to see their masks.

"Death Eaters," he hissed. "Followers of You-Know-Who."

"Oh, Merlin," Hermione said softly. "We should go back and tell Dumbledore. We should have told Dumbledore right at the start."

"Yeah, well, he's a bit hard to reach," Ron said, "living in a password-protected secret office and all."

"Quiet, both of you," Harry snapped. "Those two, the ones built like gorillas — you see? They've got Milo. He... he's not moving."

"Is he — oh, Merlin. Can you tell if he's... is he breathing?" Hannah asked.

"No," Harry said without thinking. "I mean, I can't tell. Not... not the other thing."

"They're carrying him deeper into the Forest," Hermione mused. "They must mean to get outside the wards and Disapparate."

"Then we have to hurry!" Harry urged.

"And do what?" Hermione asked. "No, seriously. What do we do if we catch them? They'll kill the lot of us."

"We have to try," Hannah said. "He saved my life, once. He saved Neville's, too. He wouldn't even think twice."

"If we take them by surprise," Harry mused, "we can disarm the four not holding Milo simultaneously. As soon as the two big ones drop him and go for their wands, we do the same to them."

"Then what do we do?" Hermione asked.

"Whatever we want, really," Harry said. "We'll have wands and they won't."

Hermione chewed on her lip.

"Fine," she said finally. "But if we don't get them all — all of them — on the first volley, we run. They won't be casting to disarm, or even to stun."

"Deal," Harry said reluctantly. Filled with equal parts reassurance in having a plan and abject terror in the face of near-certain death, he led his three classmates towards a larger group of hardened killers.

"Okay," he said finally, ducking behind a tree about twenty paces from the Death Eaters. "We're in range. Everyone get ready, and remember practice. It's no different from the Duelling Club."

"In the club, Neville won't slay me if I mess up the spell," Ron muttered.

"We go on three, okay? One. Two. Th—"

There was a short series of loud popping noises, like small firecrackers, and the Death Eaters vanished.

"We're too late," Hannah said in a dead tone. "I can't... I mean, what... we... we're too late."

Chapter 25: Roll for Initiative

Author's Notes: Something I've been doing this whole time, which I only just realized I haven't mentioned, is that I actually do roll for Milo's hit points. He is... not overly blessed with luck.

Today's character sheet can be found here: www myth-weavers com/sheetview php?sheetid=452348 (replace spaces with periods, as usual). Note: I just realized that it was set to "Private" view, and not "Public;" you should all be able to see the character sheet now. Sorry!

The whole chapter is posted. Once again, sorry for the wait! I'm doing my best. There's a pretty good chance next week's chapter will be late as well, but after that things should be normal again.

Also, I threw in a non-canonical AU sidestory I wrote in a particularly dull European History class last week. It has moderate spoilers for Robert Jordan's The Wheel of Time, so don't read it unless you're caught up. And if you're not caught up, read the series. It's awesome.

SAD NOTE: Due to Prismatic Dragon-levels of homework, there will, tragically, not be an update of Harry Potter and the Natural 20 on (the Canadian) Thanksgiving weekend. (That's this weekend).

o—o—o—o—o—o—o

Milo stared up at the dark, dank masonry ceiling, following the patterns of the stone above him, shaking his head in disgust — something he regretted instantly as his vision swam blurrily. At some point —he couldn't remember when, which, all things considered, was concerning —he'd been searched for anything even vaguely magical-looking. His Belt of Hidden Pouches, his Amulet of Protection From Evil, his anti-vampire paraphernalia, and, amusingly enough, his wand were all missing.

All that left him with were his magic robes, 'Headband' of Intellect, and Arcanist's Gloves, and whatever spells he still had memorized — which was to say, most of his best stuff.

Except for his spellbook, which, if he didn't get it back soon, would leave him only capable of preparing the 0th-level spell Read Magic and... Milo frowned.

He felt oddly like there were a pair of other spells he should know already but somehow... didn't. Like something was missing. He dismissed the notion that he'd been memory charmed; the now-familiar feeling he had could only mean one thing: he'd levelled up.

Must have happened when I disarmed Quirrell, Milo mused. Even including the steep XP reduction for nonlethal combat, the Defence Professor had given him more than enough to level up.

"Parchment," Milo said suddenly. "I need parchment now."

When a Wizard increases in level, they learn two new spells for free. This is supposed to be an instantaneous thing — in fact, it is generally assumed that the spells learned were from ongoing research the Wizard was doing before levelling. This doesn't change the fact that if a Wizard goes through an incredibly violent day and, say, increases in level three times — an unusual, but not impossible feat — he can somehow perform months of spell research, not in the space of that one day, but in the weeks leading up to it.

Right that moment, Milo's brain was packed full of roughly three hundred and thirty-six hours of retroactive potential spell research. The fact that this was blatantly impossible didn't mean that it wasn't happening.

His hands twitched. His head felt like it might well explode if he didn't get these spells on paper soon. Looking around the dimly lit room — a single flickering lamp provided what could generously be called light — he noticed that his considerate hosts had failed to furnish his cell with a stationary kit.

Milo rolled up the left sleeve of his magically-augmented Hogwarts uniform, cursing like a level 10 Half-Orc Dread Pirate.

"I can't believe I'm reduced to this," he muttered (after heavy censorship, that is). Little-used rules allow a Wizard's forearm and upper arm to be used as three pages of spellbook each — more than enough for his purposes. The long-term thinker in him was screaming in protest at the wastefulness, both in terms of time and money, of his plans, but cold pragmatism ruled here: he still had all of his 3rd-level spell slots filled, but he'd used the lion's share of his 1st- and 2nd-level spells in the battle with the Acromantulas (or was it Acromantulae? Milo could never tell).

He had his paper analogue, but he still needed ink. With one last, choice curse (it was Orc, and it wouldn't translate, so don't ask) he bit deeply into the skin of his right index finger.

How long had he been unconscious? Eight hours? More? Wincing with pain, he frantically scrawled the mystic words of power that were the keys to Benign Transposition and Shatter on his arm. The blood ran and spread, but it would do for now. It would have to.

As for his feat... Craft Magic Weapons and Armour was all but useless to him for now, but he'd need it, soon. He could always retrain it later.

Some time later — how long, Milo wasn't sure in the dark — he heard footsteps, ringing out loudly on the cold stone floor. He quickly doused the nearby lamp and turned to face the door, Readying himself.

The doorknob turned slowly, and eventually, the heavy wooden door opened. A masked, robed figure who Milo recognized by his stature as either Crabbe or Goyle senior entered, his wand out and its tip glowing.

"Shatter." A thunderously loud ring erupted from the thin wooden stick as if a heavily optimized Hulking Hurler had thrown a boulder at a gong the size of a small barn. The light went out as the wand fragmented into splinters, leaving the two of them in near-total darkness.

In most circumstances, a young boy trapped in a dark room with a grown man built along the same lines as the USS Iowa would hardly be thought to have the advantage.

This was not most circumstances.

"Silent Image." The words were barely more than the ghost of a whisper, but in the hands of a Wizard, whispered words could be more dangerous than a rampaging Wyrm.

What Crabbe (or Goyle?) Senior saw made the illusions Milo had used on Peeves and Ollivander look like a toddler's crayon drawing.

After a moment, the man screamed.

"Take it away," he whimpered through the mask. "Please, just — just take it away."

"It's out of my hands," Milo lied. "I brought them, but they'll only leave when they're... appeased. You wouldn't want to know what they eat." Goyle (or Crabbe?) made an incoherent wordless sound. "Although..."

Milo would have bet his spellbook that, had he possessed darkvision — and had the Death Eater not been wearing a mask — he would have seen a manic glimmer of hope in the man's eyes.

"I suppose there's another way. I might be able to... intercede, on your behalf, if I had reason to."

"Yes! Anything!" An interesting quirk of the way Illusions work is that the only way to determine their true nature without magic (or by having them pointed out) is to succeed on a Will Saving Throw. A viewer is only allowed a Save against Illusions after either physical interaction or by studying them carefully. Milo doubted Crabbe (or Goyle) was blessed with a high Will save bonus, but even a 1st-level Commoner could roll a twenty. So long as Milo kept the image from actually touching the Death Eater — and kept him distracted — then Bigby himself couldn't tell the difference. In short: Illusions are like movie monsters. With a little care, even the staunchest audience will believe in them completely — until they appear on screen in clear lighting.

"Tell me where I am, where my gear was taken, and why I was brought here."

"You're in M-M-Malfoy's M-Manor." Milo was reminded briefly of the treacherous Defence Professor's stammer. "Y-your w-wand is in a st-storeroom down the hall, and you're here for the Ritual." Something about the way he said it implied a Capital Letter.

"One last thing. Give me the key."

"Key?" Of course, he thought. Wizards here wouldn't use keys; they'd just use Alohomora to open locks — and Colloportus to close them again. Great. Now what do I do with him? Seeing as how he was without his standard-issue fifty feet of hemp rope — a cardinal sin among Adventurers — and he couldn't just lock his captive in the room, he was in something of a dilemma. Eh, what the Hells. He could sit here moralizing over what to do with captured enemies, or he could act and hope for the best. "Don't even think about moving, or I'll let them have you." Without bothering to wait for a response, he walked over to the Death Eater and tore off strips of the man's robes to bind his arms and legs. Milo didn't have any Skill Ranks in Use Rope (because, seriously, who trains Use Rope?) but he hoped his crude knots would do. As an afterthought, he shoved the horrid mask into the man's mouth as a gag. Milo turned to leave, but paused in the doorframe. "I put a Contingent Curse on those knots," he said simply. "If they ever come undone, you'll die."

A Silent Image could last as long as Milo concentrated, so he changed the Illusion from the writhing mass of Indescribably Awful Unspeakable Horrors to a tiny, dull grey ball that orbited his wrist slowly. Normally, he wouldn't bother going through such measures to save spells, but without his Spellbook, they were going at something of a premium.

Closing the heavy door behind him, Milo stepped out into a dimly lit hallway. He was somewhat surprised to find it free of guards, but it made a sort of sense — this mad society was entirely populated by wizards, and wizards, by-and-large, had better things to do than guard prisoners. Not that a couple of low-level Muggles with pointy sticks could stop him if he really wanted out, if it came to that.

To his right was a narrow, slightly crooked staircase; to his left, a thick door like the one behind him. Didn't take a Genius Loci to figure out which way led to the storeroom. The door was, unsurprisingly, locked.

Shatter could destroy any nonmagical object of up to sixty pounds. The thickly Reinforced door weighed well more than that, but, when it came to it, what, exactly, was an object? A door? A plank? certainly. Part of a door? No, that was part of an object. But one of several planks making up a door? If they weren't an object, then neither was the door — by the same logic, the door couldn't be destroyed because it was part of the house, and the house because it was part of the planet.

"Shatter." Regrettably, he had to dismiss his Silent Image. The thick chunk of mahogany connected to the polished brass hinges holding up the door exploded away from Milo's outstretched palm. The rest of the door teetered precariously for a moment before falling to the ground with a deafening clatter that could likely be heard from the top of Mount Celestia. Well, stealth has never been my strong suit in any case. Zook — assuming he was still alive — would be ashamed of him. Are any of them alive? Am I the last one?

Stepping over the ruins of the once-fine door, Milo entered a surprisingly comfortable-feeling ten-by-ten stone room. All it needs now is an orc guarding a chest, he thought wryly. Dusty boxes were scattered about the floor space haphazardly.

"Locate Object — My Belt of Hidden Pouches." Heaving a sigh of relief, he allowed the gentle tug of his Divination to lead him to a box seemingly indistinguishable from the others, the lid of which came off easily. Neatly stored inside were his various magical doodads. Milo was about to reach for them, but hesitated.

This is far too easy, he thought. Overconfidence was pretty well standard-issue among archvillains, but this was ridiculous. They left him — a Wizard — alone in a room? He hadn't even been bound, blindfolded, and gagged (not that any of those would be a guarantee; Still and Silent Spell existed for a reason, after all). And putting his Magic Items in a room right next to his cell was simply insane. Frankly, he should have been executed, looted, and left in a ditch by the road somewhere.

Milo had made too many mistakes by rushing in blindly and ignoring the signs around him. He needed to stop and examine this from every angle before he got himself killed. It was time for an Intelligence Check. Time to Take Twenty, in fact. What did Milo know?

Fact: the Death Eater had said he was needed for a ritual. Presumably, they needed him alive, or they wouldn't have gone through all the effort of capturing him when it would have been much, much easier to kill him before he knew they were attacking him. He reckoned it wasn't unreasonable to assume that this ritual had something to do with the one that had summoned him here in the first place, if only because it was the only other time the words 'ritual' and 'Malfoy Manner' had coincided in this particular story arc. So... what was the goal? To send him back? Somehow, Milo doubted that a group of villains who could, apparently, 'eat death' would take pains to see him home safely.

Fact: Lucius had taken grossly inadequate measures to keep him imprisoned once captured. This either implied a serious lack of knowledge about Milo's magical capabilities — something he doubted Lucius had, seeing as how Snape, presumably acting on Lucius's orders, had nearly had Milo thrown out of Hogwarts by exploiting the differences in their respective magical abilities — or that he wanted Milo to escape. But that was stupidity. Why capture Milo only to give him what amounted to a key, a bagged lunch, and a map out of his cell? Was Lucius looking for some sort of climactic showdown? Surely not. Milo knew little of Voldemort's lieutenant, but among the list of things he did know, 'self-destructive flair for dramatics' was conspicuously absent.

Fact: all of Lucius's actions known against Milo to date had been with the end goal of capturing him alive. To do that, Milo would need to be taken outside of the grounds, where the faculty and wards would be unable to protect him.

"None of this answers the question of how I escaped so easily," Milo muttered. Maybe... could he have had help from inside Lucius's camp? It was far too tenuous to be listed among his 'facts' (many of which, Milo was sure, were tenuous enough to make any respectable logician shudder), yet it seemed the only reasonable conclusion. The only other reason Milo could think of would be some sort of trap, but he couldn't see any reason for the Lucius and the Death Eaters (a part of Milo's brain idly noted that 'Lucius and the Death Eaters' sounded like the name for a group of travelling Chaotic Evil Bards) to lay a trap for him while he was unconscious and in their hands.

If the good guys really had a mole, he had to be someone with enough decision-making power to oversee the placement of Milo's stuff, but not enough to simply leave it with him in prison. So. One of Lucius's right-hand men was a traitor.

Regardless, the room was unlikely to explode if he touched his Belt, so he suited up.

Fact: when Milo had been Imperiused, his controller had made no effort to order him outside of the Hogwarts grounds. Therefore, Lucius — and by extension, Snape and Draco — had not been responsible for having him Imperiused after Christmas.

Fact: he had, however, been ordered to investigate the Mirror.

Fact: Quirrell was a traitor, yet not in league with Lucius. Thinking back to The Plot, Milo realized he'd made a serious error: he'd assumed that the evil would be monolithic; one giant, shadowy organization out to get him. This was evidently not the case.

Fact: the Philosopher's Stone was obviously hidden on the forbidden third-floor corridor in Hogwarts.

Fact: the day the Troll was released, both Quirrell and Snape had immediately gone to that corridor.

Fact: Quirrell had killed what was at least one of the guardians of the Stone.

Fact: the Philosopher's Stone was one way for Voldemort to return.

Fact: Quirrell had uncharacteristically volunteered to lead the investigation to find whoever was killing unicorns in the Forbidden Forest.

Fact: Unicorn blood was another way for Voldemort to return.

Milo's pulse quickened.

Fact: Milo had been a blind idiot to believe the Troll was responsible for killing the unicorns.

But that wasn't the end of it.

Fact: Milo himself was another way for Voldemort to return.

Fact: Quirrell knew this, and also knew that Milo required more Experience Points to do the same.

Fact: Quirrell had taken an unusual interest in Milo, and had asked several questions about how he levelled up.

What was it the Professor had said? You, Milo, are a prize greater than any Philosopher's Stone.

Milo felt chilled to his spine, and it had nothing to do with temperature.

Conclusion: Quirrell was trying to bring Lord Voldemort back from the dead.

No, wait. That's wrong. He already has unicorn blood.

Conclusion, Revised: Quirrell has already brought Lord Voldemort back from the dead.

Milo's knees turned to jelly, and it wasn't because of the Jelly Legs Hex. His breathing accelerated into a staccato beat of shallow gasps; the edges of his vision began to darken. I told him everything he asked. I may as well have gone up to the Dark Lord Voldemort and handed him a copy of the Rules on a platter.

And he called himself a Wizard. One of the Wise. He wasn't worth his pointy hat. What had he accomplished? He'd as good as told Voldemort — Godsdamned Voldemort — about the secret workings of Arcane Magic and the D20 System. Milo had almost killed one of his best friends. With a dagger. Reality was his plaything, and he'd resorted to throwing a block of sharpened metal.

With effort, he steadied his breathing enough to speak. He felt a sharp, metallic tang of metal in his mouth.

And he called himself an Adventurer. A Hero. An Optimizer.

I dumped Constitution. What kind of Optimizer am I?

"Pazuzu." The walls of the room seemed to distort slightly, but it could have been a trick of the flickering light. The slight tremors could well have been muscle spasms.

"Pazuzu." The lights — what few there were in this basement — went out. He thought he could hear quiet laughter.

"Pa —" He yelped at a sudden, sharp pain in his hand. The light returned as if nothing had happened.

"What the Hells are you doing? Are you trying to get us killed?" The voice was small, but it seemed to fill the whole room. A small, slightly overweight, white-and-brown rat was hanging onto Milo's right hand, his fingernails dug into the fine fabric of Milo's Arcanist's Gloves.

"Mordy?" Milo asked in astonishment. "I thought you'd still be in the Forbidden Forest."

"One of the first things a familiar learns is how to disappear when not needed." Mordy took on a dry, lecturing tone. "And when Save-Or-Dies start flying is the first sign a familiar isn't needed. I ducked into my Belt as soon as you got paralyzed."

"I think you mean my belt," Milo said indignantly. "And where do you get off biting me?"

Mordenkainen snorted, a slightly incongruous sound for a rat.

"Look at it this way. What happens to you if I die?"

"I lose a bunch of Experience Points," Milo shuddered.

"And what happens to me if you die?"

Milo frowned.

"I have no idea," he confessed. "I could look it up when we get home —"

"Don't bother," the rat interrupted. "There's no mention of it anywhere. Centuries ago, when the ancestors of modern researches first began testing the laws of the universe to determine the rules, they didn't bother investigating it. That hasn't changed since. Nobody knows what happens to a familiar whose Wizard dies. Let's keep it that way, shall we? I don't fancy waking up as an ordinary rat again. Your fool stunt could have killed us both. Trying to summon a Demon Prince? What were you thinking?"

"Look—"

"My Intelligence is less than half yours — though you wouldn't know by looking — and even I know that's a terrible idea."

"It was the only way—"

"You're True Neutral. He'd have no obligation to enter negotiations with you. Once summoned, he could have gutted you like a fish and gone on to do Gods know what to this Plane."

Milo paused.

"You're right. I'm sorry."

"Did you — did you just admit a mistake?"

"Mistake? I've made nothing but mistakes. Quirrell is working for He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named. Now that he knows I'm on to him, he's probably killing my friends."

"This isn't like you. What's wrong with you?"

"Like you don't already know," Milo said sullenly. "You can read my mind, remember?"

"It's an empathic link, not a telepathic link. Moron." Despite his words, Milo felt a flash of concern through the bond.

"Whatever."

Mordy's expression — such as he had, being a rat — hardened.

"Oh, look at you, summoning Demon Princes and moping and making rules errors. You know what you remind me of?" The familiar's words were positively dripping with contempt — an effect undermined slightly by the emotions drifting through their bond. Worry. Concern. Love.

"Don't say it." But it was hopeless, Milo knew exactly what Mordenkainen was going to say — possibly because, in a manner of speaking, they were two sides of the same person.

"An Apprentice-Level hack NPC, that's what. Are you a set piece, or are you a Player Character?"

"Says the glorified Class Feature."

"Hey, at least this Class Feature knows why he's here."

"And why, pray tell, is that?"

"I'm here because you're here. I'd follow you into Orcus's Throne Room. And, more the fool I am, I'd trust you to get us back out again. But I've only got the Intelligence of an average NPC Half-Orc. Now, what are we going to do?"

"You know, you suck at giving pep talks."

"I work with what I'm given. We share Skill Ranks, and it's hardly my fault if you find better uses for them than Perform (Orator). Now. What are we going to do?"

Milo paused, his mind racing.

"We're going to find Quirrell and stop him. But to do that, we're going to need to get out of this manor. Again."

"And why are we going to do that?" Mordenkainen pressed.

"Because..." Images flashed into Milo's head. Images of Voldemort, all cloaked in black with glowing red eyes, torturing Harry and Ron and Hermione. And... and Hannah. "Because..." Of Voldemort, walking unopposed into the Potters' house eleven years ago and murdering Harry's parents. Of him committing acts so foul that, not only did nobody mention them to this day, but that caused fully trained, battle-hardened wizards to fear to even speak his name. Quirrell wanted to unleash him again on this absurd, pathetic, broken, confused, third-party, inconsistent, beautiful Plane. "Because he'll hurt my friends. Because it's the right thing to do." It should have felt more profound, more impressive, changing one's alignment. Milo felt vaguely cheated.

"Go forth and kick ass, my master."

o—o—o—o

It was the smell, of all things, that first clued Macnair in that something was awry. It started faint, and he simply ignored it. In a few seconds, it became overpowering. A dank, musty, earthy scent which reminded him of a crypt. Frowning beneath his mask, the executioner drew his wand and stuck his head into the hallway to see what was going on. Snape, relaying Malfoy's orders, had told him to keep an eye on the corridor while the others prepared for the Ritual. The oily Potions Master had been very specific; Macnair was to stand just out of sight of Crabbe. He said it was to optimize sightlines, whatever that meant.

A rat scurried between his feet — this was unusual; Dobby would likely be punished severely for his negligence — but, otherwise, there seemed nothing unusual.

"Goyle?" Macnair called out softly. Crabbe had been sent to Stun the prisoner again in case he came close to waking, but Crabbe should have been just around the corner. Idiot must have wandered off. He was about to return to his post when he noticed, just in sight at the end of the hall, what looked like a pair of feet sticking around the corner. With a sudden lurch, they were gone.

"What the H—"

"Benign Transposition." Macnair heard a tiny crack, like a mouse Disapparating, and suddenly the crypt smell was strong enough to make him want to gag. Macnair whirled, and found himself face-to-face with a walking, waking, nightmare. Empty sockets in a huge, misshapen skull stared at him, its jaw grinning grotesquely. The... thing, whatever it was, had to hunch over to fit in the cavernous hallways of Malfoy's manor, and its disproportionately long, skeletal arms ended in sharp, serrated claws. Bleached bone thudded against the polished mahogany wood as it walked calmly towards him. Macnair didn't know what it was, and wasn't about to wait to find out.

"Avada Kedavra!" A green bolt of hate-fuelled death flew at the monster and exploded harmlessly on its ribcage. Macnair stared at it in absolute amazement. "Avada Kedavra! Avada Kedavra!" Again and again, he fired the most powerful spell he knew, the spell that killed without fail, but the abomination simply ignored him and maintained its sedate pace.

With sudden, lightning speed belying its utter lack of visible musculature, the nightmare leapt. Briefly there was pain, and then darkness.

o—o—o—o

"Shatter." The aged, expensive, polished, exquisitely-crafted wooden door fell inwards, revealing a familiar dining room.

Lucius Malfoy stared at Milo in utter astonishment for a split second, but quickly schooled his face to calmness.

"So," the elder Malfoy said. "I see you've bested Crabbe and Goyle. No more than I'd expected. I suppose you wonder why we've brought you here?"

"Some," Milo said neutrally. There were twelve other Death Eaters in the room, all anonymous beneath their masks. One of them, at least, was probably a mole; the rest could be anyone. Despite his promise to never jump through a window again, he figured his best way out was the same as last time. This time, however, he could summon Skeletal Trolls — being mindless and Undead, they were immune to all three of the Unforgivable Curses, and, for some reason, Summon Undead III was Conjuration (as opposed to Necromancy, one of Milo's forbidden schools) so he could cast it without problem.

"Well, I think you will find that, if you will but listen for a moment, our aims are much the same," Lucius explained. Despite himself, Milo was intrigued.

"Go on," he said skeptically. If worse came to worst, he could always fight his way out.

"You were brought here quite by accident," Lucius said, "and — I swear this by the Most Noble and Ancient House of Malfoy — we are preparing a ritual that will send you back."

Milo gaped with genuine astonishment. This was completely out of left field.

"You do realize that I'm not naturally predisposed to trust someone wearing a skull mask, right?"

"What, these?" Lucius pulled off his mask, revealing his long, platinum blond hair and politely smiling face.

"And this... this ritual of yours," Milo said, "it won't, by any chance, return me home dead or horribly dismembered?"

"Not to my knowledge, no. So, what say you?"

"I... have to ask. Why?"

"The ritual we... mistakenly used to bring you here cost us something," he said reluctantly, "something which can only be regained if you are returned. It is no concern of yours, however. I'm sure you have your own problems to deal with, where you came from."

Well, there was the matter of resurrecting his almost-certainly-dead teammates...

It was tempting. It was really, really tempting. He could go home, back to a world that ran on sensible, predictable rules, a world where he didn't have to re-invent the wheel every time he wanted to learn a new spell, a world where not every single citizen had access to At-Will No Save Death Spells. He could see his home; Myra, City of Light! City of Magic! more than lived up to its name. He could show Thamior the Unimaginably Horrid who was boss. He could fight Orcs again. Gods, I miss fighting Orcs. And yet...

"Sorry," Milo said finally. "I still have work to do."

"I'm sorry to hear that. Things would go... easier, for both of us, if you were alive for the ritual, but, alas..."

Milo could practically feel the Initiative Die rolling in his head as he unleashed his Readied Action.

o—o—o—o—o—o—o

Also: BONUS OMAKE! (Warning: SPOILERS AHEAD)

Q: What if Milo were transported to Robert Jordan's The Wheel of Time instead of the Harry Potter universe?

A: The Eye of the World would look like this:

The wolf-headed Trolloc reached at him with its horrid, barbed catchpole in an attempt to pull him from his Mount.

"Glitterdust!" Milo shouted, and the surrounded Shadowspawn recoiled, blinded by the sudden light. "Ha!" he said exuberantly, "and that's why you don't send a horde of mooks to catch a caster! Fear my Arcane sparkles, Shadowspawn!"

In an instant — less than a Standard Action, for certain — Milo found himself pulled from his horse and slammed into the hard earth. Lan's curved blade was held against his neck, his foot pressed down Milo's chest. Milo's companions were staring at him in horror.

"Male channeler," he heard somebody whisper, while another added "The Dark One and all the Forsaken are bound in Shayol Ghul, bound by the Creator at the moment of creation," and trailed off. Moirane stared at him, an unreadable expression on her face.

"He is shielded," she said quietly. "But to gentle him, here, would light a beacon for halfmen leagues in every direction." Lan gave her a brief, questioning look. Moirane shook her head, and he withdrew his blade. "The Wheel weaves as the Wheel wills," she murmured. "There was no forseeing this. He is a part of the Pattern, now."

Several Thousand Pages Later:

"Graendel did it," Milo said. "I just used a Limited Wish to Speak With Dead."

Even More Thousands of Pages Later:

The Gholam, immune to the Power and capable of recovering from any injury, charged at Mat and Milo.

"Light!" Mat said, barely avoiding the Gholam's boneless grasp.

"Disintegrate," Milo muttered. The assassin crumbled into dust.

"Blood and bloody ashes, what was that?" Mat asked.

"Dunno," Milo shrugged. "Don't care. Locate Object — Bowl of the Winds. We turn left, now."

Circa The Gathering Storm:

"Widened Fireball," Milo cast, and hordes of Shadowspawn – Trollocs, Draghkar, and Myrdraal alike – fell to his fire. "Cloudkill," he said, and hundreds more died. He only had to hold the line for a few more rounds… the Lord Dragon had promised. Help was coming – right?

Milo felt, rather than heard, the Fade behind him. The Conjurer whirled, ready to send the Halfman back to its master, when its black blade was abruptly sheared in half – as was most of the unfortunate Myrdraal, as well. Rand stepped out of the Gateway, staring at Milo with his steely gaze.

"What you have wrought here was not saidin," he said simply.

"That's what I've been trying to say this whole time," Milo said, wasting a Fist of Trollocs with a Silent Fireball. "But nobody here ever listens to anyone!"

"I have only met one channeler who did not use saidin," Rand continued, oblivious to Milo's words. "Forsaken."

"What? Wai—"

Rand channeled balefire without a second thought.

Chapter 26: Bluff Checks

Author's Notes: last chapter's Wheel of Time joke-section (it's not meant to be taken seriously) was rather a lot of fun, and fairly well received, so I might do more in the future. We'll see how things turn out. Sorry for the long delay, but it should be the last missed weekend for a while—I haven't got any assignments worth mentioning due until mid-November. Updates might become erratic around then. Apologies in advance.

Update Nov 3rd: Hello all you HP:MOR readers! It just came to my attention that Eliezer Yudkowsky/Less Wrong recommended me on his blog on Thursday and a number of new readers have arrived because of that. Which is awesome. Enjoy! Although I think "Rationalist Fanfic" is somewhat of an exaggeration (albeit one that makes me happy) and that "Rationalist-inspired Fanfic" is more accurate because, well, anyone who's met Milo likely won't be immediately struck by how rational he is. Is Irrationalist Fanfic a thing? /ramble.

In other news, there won't be an update tomorrow because of an essay due Monday, but I think with some re-shuffling we can avoid the Great Schedule Slip of October from re-occurring. I tend to leave my homework for weekends, which is also when I do my writing. So. As an experiment, I am going to try switching the update day to Thursdays. That way, if I can't find time in the weekend to write, I won't just give up on the update altogether. Whether there will be one this Thursday is only 50-50, because of Good Reasons I Swear, and Why Are You Looking At Me Like That? Stop! I'm Trying Real Hard And The Next Chapter Will Be Real Soon Now.

Update November 26th: Okay, so here's the deal. I'm starting to think I have the mythical Writer's Block. I know what's going to happen next—it's all been planned out for ages. From the beginning, basically. But, when I'm actually staring at the screen and keyboard, every sentence I write has to be forced out with far more effort than it should take. I'm writing this fic for fun, after all, and every draft of Chapter 27 has been, well, atrocious.

So. I don't know when the next update will be, and I'm so sorry. It will happen at some point, and that's a promise, Mister Frodo. Probably in January between terms, but I can't know for certain. I haven't had to deal with this before, and this is a decidedly inconvenient time for it to strike what with all the new readers coming and all. But. I'm sure most of you know this, but if you hit "subscribe" then you'll be the first to know when my block is gone and I stop rolling 1's on Craft (Epic Fanfic) checks.

To re-iterate: I'm so sorry. I'm doing my best. But the more I worry about the late update, the more the update feels like work, and I worry about it more and want to do it less and vicious cycles suck. So I need to do some other stuff for a while and avoid thinking about my beloved story, then come back with gusto. And when I do, it'll be epic. I have Very Cool Plans.

o—o—o—o—o—o—o

He was being chased. He couldn't see it, or hear it, but he knew. He wasn't sure what it was. The forest was full of nothing but silence, not even the rustle of leaves caused by a bird or squirrel. That was his first clue.

"Professor? Are you... all right?" The villagers—Muggles, all of them—spoke fearfully, when they'd had too much to drink, of... something in the woods. When pressed, they'd laugh it off as silly superstition and change the subject. But a slight hesitation in their laughter, a tightness around their eyes...the fear was real. The...thing might be imaginary, but the fear was real.

He could help them. He'd known it. It had been a chance to prove himself, to get some real field experience. Lessons and books were all very well, but he'd been ready for something more. He'd thought it was vampires, in the woods. After all, what could be more frightening than vampires? It would explain the Muggles' reactions.

"Why is he handcuffed? Alohomora." And now, he was being chased. And it was gaining on him. It wasn't a vampire. He thought...he might know what it was.

"I think he needs help; we should bring him back to the castle."

He'd forgotten. They'd all forgotten, wizards and witches everywhere had buried their memories. Because there was something worse than vampires. Worse than Dementors. They'd tricked themselves into thinking it was gone. That he was gone. But now, Quirrell knew better.

"And how do you reckon we do that? You have a cart hidden under your robes, Hermione?"

Worse, he knew a way to be free. But he couldn't even allow himself to think about it, because it...because he was always listening. Always. So he had to be careful. He would bide his time.

"Professor Quirrell?"

The use of his name jerked him back into the present. He sat up, and his hand immediately went to his head as the world spun. Quirrell opened his eyes and stared at a worried face. A worried, bespectacled face.

A worried, lightning-scarred face.

He recoiled instinctively, a sudden, unreasoning hatred filling him to the core. Quirrell steadied himself with effort; he was used to the mood swings now, had learned to recognize which emotions were his and which came from...him.

"M-mister P-P-Potter," he stammered with his accursed stutter. It had been an act, once, to reduce suspicion. But his act had slipped once too many times, and he had seen to it that it was no longer an act. Quirrell shuddered at the memory. "W-where am I?" That was unusual. The last he had remembered, he'd been planning to take the boy to dispatch some of his tame vampires. He still had several connections in dark places; the filthy creatures in their cave likely still thought he was bringing them the child as blood tribute.

The smirk died on his lips when he realized what must have happened. Suddenly finding himself in an unknown location with no memory of how he got there? There were two possibilities. One, he'd been Memory Charmed. Possible, but unless one of these half-trained children was secretly a Metamorphmagus Auror—or maybe a Polyjuiced Death Eater—he doubted they had the power. The other...he must have taken direct control. There could be no telling what he had done.

"We're...not sure, to be honest, Professor," Potter said. Again, another man's—could he still be called a man?—rage filled him. "We thought you might be able to tell us."

"W-what has h-happened?" Quirrell was, frankly, surprised. Had he taken over, he was sure the first thing he'd have done was finished off his mortal enemy.

The four children all began a disjointed story, each starting at different places and clamouring over each other, but Quirrell managed to piece together what, more or less, they were trying to say regardless.

"S-so you s-say D-Death E-Eaters t-took him?" Quirrell frowned. Death Eaters? That hadn't been part of the plan. Had he changed it, without telling him? There was no way for him to tell, their peculiar bond was very much one-sided.

"But I don't see how," Granger said somewhat petulantly. "You can't Apparate or Disapparate within the Hogwarts wards."

"W-we m-m-must be outside them," Quirrell said. "They d-d-don't q-quite cover the f-far edges of the F-Forest."

"We should tell Dumbledore right away," Granger insisted. "He'll know what to do."

"Good thinking," Potter agreed. "Professor, can you walk?" At the mention of the Headmaster's name, he felt a sudden spike of fear through the bond. It always surprised Quirrell that even one such as he could feel something so human as fear.

"N-no," Quirrell said hurriedly. How was he going to talk his way out of this one? He wondered when the last time he'd said something completely true was. "W-we can't t-tell the H-Headmaster j-just yet. D-Dumbledore, f-for all his v-virtues, is overly trusting. H-he will c-certainly t-tell Snape, and your P-P-Potions M-Master will g-go running to his r-r-real master."

"See?" Weasley said. "I told you he was up to no good." Granger coloured slightly, but said nothing.

"We can't just do nothing!" Potter said. "He's in danger." Abbot nodded fervently in agreement.

"I d-don't p-propose we d-do nothing," Quirrell said. "j-just let m-me handle it. D-don't talk to D-Dumbledore. In f-fact, d-don't let anyone know you w-were out h-here at all." He was feeling increasingly impatient, and it did not do to keep him waiting. "W-well, if we're r-really outside the w-wards, we'd b-best start h-heading back. It c-could q-quite s-some time." Time they certainly didn't have. If the Death Eaters were brazen enough to abduct Milo this close to Dumbledore's seat of power, they really were active again. So Lucius is taking a hand in events again. It had to be him. No-one else had the power and drive to unite his followers who had managed to keep out of Azkaban. Quirrell was somewhat surprised that they had been able to manage even this; he had understood that the best and brightest of his followers lay rotting on the island. Where, he was quick to remind himself, he was certain to go if his true nature was revealed. But...why would they bother? Was it to bring him back? But the boy couldn't even manage that, yet.

Or so he said, anyway.

On the way back to the castle, they passed a large group of dead Acromantulas, of all things. It only took Quirrell a glance to determine what had happened. Something had caused the horrid beasts to turn on each other, but, judging by the pristine corpses lying above the mangled ones, one or more wizards had finished off the lot with the Killing Curse. Must have been Lucius and his cronies.

By the time they reached the castle, it was well past curfew, and after sending the children to their Common Room, Quirrell's footsteps echoed ominously in the hallway alone. He had long since grown out of fearing the dark, but all the same... he couldn't shake the feeling that he was being hunted. Worse, now that he was finally alone—as alone as he could ever be, now—he could speak.

"You lost the boy... were overpowered by an eleven year old..." That was enough to trigger the memories. The Memory Charm that had been placed upon him was a weak one, from someone whose talents clearly lay in other directions.

A dozen excuses came to mind in an instant: that the boy had powerful magic was the reason they were interested in him, that he would have simply told the Death Eaters he was as good as being the Dark Lord before he had prevented him, that there were six of them and only one of him—but he had learned, painfully, that he did not accept excuses. You simply waited, and hoped he would forgive your failures.

"I-I'm sorry, m-my l-lord. Y-you know w-what happened, I h-have n-no excuse."

"No, you don't... but you will have this opportunity to redeem yourself... am I not merciful?"

Quirrell felt a rush of relief that was wholly his own.

"Y-yes, my l-lord." He explained to him his plan as Quirrell hustled to Dumbledore's office, listening carefully. It was a daring move; much could go wrong—and he would be the one to have to modify it on the fly as circumstances changed. No plan lasted much longer than the first contact with the enemy. He could take over his—their—body directly, but only for brief periods of time.

"Sherbet Lemon," he said to the gargoyle statue.

Dumbledore—again, that sudden rush of hate, spiked with fear—sat behind his great wooden desk on a comfortable-looking chintz armchair. As Quirrell entered, a glowing silver doe patronus he had never seen before was leaving, presumably having delivered a message of some sort. He glanced at it briefly, frowning. Quirrell himself had been unable to produce one since... he had arrived. Could it be coincidence, the doe arriving on the same night Lucius made his move? It must be. Surely, someone as powerful as the Headmaster received messages of all sorts at every hour of the day.

"Why, Quirinus," Dumbledore said, sounding genuinely pleased to see him. Quirrell tried to fight down his borrowed emotions with limited success. "What brings you here at this hour?"

It was vital that the Headmaster not discover what Lucius had done, because he was still unsure about the possibly-former Death Eater's loyalties. He might still be useful in the future, but not if he were rotting in Azkaban.

"Milo is g-gone," Quirrell said simply. "V-vampires t-took him."

o—o—o—o

Lucius Malfoy frantically rubbed the blinding particles out of his eyes as he surveyed the carnage that had been wrought in the dining hall of his country manor. Some form of skeletal abomination held Nott by the neck with a single overly long arm, and was closing in on the Carrow siblings with a speed that belied its appearance. Crabbe, Goyle, and Macnair were still nowhere to be found. Gibbon and Avery were trapped in some form of giant web, of all things, which had appeared from thin air near the centre of the room. Lucius had worked too long and too hard to unite those servants who remained free to lose them to this boy. It was time to finish this; the fight had gone on long enough. The situation demanded it—nobody would argue with him on that.

"Avada Kedavra!" The boy, who was flying around in circles dodging curses, whirled around with an expression of genuine fear as the Killing Curse flew towards him. The fear was just as swiftly replaced by a grin as he muttered something under his breath; without any form of show or sign of magic, he was gone. The skeletal nightmare stood—or rather, floated—in his place, and simply dropped out of the air. The foolishly-named "Unforgivable" Curse, impossibly, exploded against its ribcage harmlessly.

How...? No time to think. The monster crashed into Jugson, who crumpled with a scream underneath its bony bulk. The boy re-appeared where the skeleton had earlier stood, with a surprised Nott on one side and Amycus and Alecto Carrow on the other. All three lowered their wands at him.

They would have to handle the boy, Lucius had other concerns. The boy's tame pet defenestrated Jugson's body with, if it had had a face, he was sure would have been contempt—and came loping straight at him. Between the thick webs, the ruins of his centuries-old table, and the writhing trapped Death Eaters, Lucius struggled to get a clear shot. He heard a pair of loud booms, six seconds apart with almost musical precision, from the other side of the room. The skeleton leaped, and Lucius realized he only had time for one last Killing Curse. He would have to give it everything he had if it could so contemptuously ignore the earlier one. He began the practiced motions—despite its power, the Killing Curse required only fairly simple wandwork—but stopped. There was no guarantee a second Unforgivable would have any more effect.

"Petrificus Totalus!" The nightmare struggled vainly as its arms and legs snapped to its sides, and it crashed into his polished mahogany floor, scoring it with deep gouges that would cost a small fortune to repair. He spun around to find the Carrows and Nott in a tight cluster, cowering before Milo's outstretched left hand. Somehow, they'd all managed to lose their wands—no. Nott's was at his feet, but the Carrows' wand hands were bleeding from toothpick-sized-splinters; Lucius was willing to bet galleons to knuts that those were all that remained of their most prized possessions. If we survive this, he decided, we're all going to start carrying two or three spares. Ollivander rarely made two of the same wand, but with the right application of pressure... well, everyone had a limit.

"Give it up," Lucius said. "It's over." He would still try to escape—Milo, from what he had seen, was nothing if not tenacious—and Lucius would kill him in the attempt.

"Is it?" Milo replied, his voice nothing but confidence. Merlin, the boy didn't even look tired! "I could have shattered their heads as easily as their wands. I still can. Drop it, Malfoy, and I'll let you live."

Can he? Lucius wondered. He'd seen the boy do the impossible—he can fly, he thought with amazement—but if he could simply kill them all... why hadn't he? What's more, why hadn't he already destroyed Lucius' eighteen-inch elm wand like he'd done the Carrows'? And Nott. His wand was still fine. It seemed absurd, but if Lucius had to guess, he'd say... well, the boy was out of magic. As if such a thing could happen. The boy was bluffing! Lucius cursed himself inwardly. The situation could still be salvaged, however, as long as nobody else realized. Other masked Death Eaters were moving to surround him, wands drawn. A slightly wild look about the eyes was the only sign that Milo's confidence was cracking.

"The moment you try," Lucius said slowly, "we'll kill you. There are seven of us," No use counting the de-wanded Carrows, "and one of you." Nott, who had grabbed his wand as soon as Milo's back was turned, and the six remaining active, armed, and unimpeded Death Eaters moved to surround him. Most had been hiding around the edges of the room, as if to escape the notice of this child. Cowards. All he had were the dregs; the best—well, all but the very best, of course—had gone to Azkaban. The best, and in many ways, the most foolish. He had little more than contempt for those who confessed to the Wizengamot.

"Yeah, well, there were thirteen of you a moment ago," the boy spat. "And none of you can come back from the dead." He addressed Lucius's followers, now. "How many of you do you think I can kill before I go down? How many of you are wondering what happened to your three guards, in the halls?" The fool's desperate bravado was playing right into his hands.

"Be that as it may," Lucius said, raising his wand. "I think I will be doing the world a favour in k—"

"Stupefy." A red Stunner hit the eleven-year-old's chest, and he crumpled to the floor with an expression of faint surprise frozen on his face. Lucius was aghast. He rounded on the fool who had cast, fighting down fury.

"You idiot!" he shouted. "What were you thinking!" Lucius paused. He'd nearly given away his plan. "He could have killed all of us!"

"If he could have," Snape's oily voice replied from beneath his mask, "he would have." Lucius fought down his anger, the true reason for his rage could never be known. With a cool confidence he did not feel, he gave the necessary orders. There was much work to do to perform the ritual.

o—o—o—o

Quirrell ducked into a side-room to make the necessary preparations, and also to catch his breath. He'd never had much of a talent for Apparition, and the distance from forest outside Hogwarts to Malfoy's manor had pushed his limit. His eyes barely registered the priceless Persian rug or the painted masterpieces hanging from the walls as he began casting. He had been very specific in his instructions when he'd taught him how to perform these spells. The price of failure—or of telling anyone the secrets—would be heavy. Too heavy.

Quirrell glanced at a polished silver mirror hanging on the wall as he began. One spell to turn his eyes red, another to shroud him in darkness. One to change his face—he gasped as his nose turned to slits, like a snake's—another to change his voice, and a third to alter his robes. He suppressed a shudder, looking at the mirror, as he saw a near-perfect replica of the Dark Lord staring back at him. Wonderingly, he touched his now-unfamiliar face.

Somehow, Quirrell knew that these were not the spells the Dark Lord had used to appear like this. He hoped to never learn the truth of the matter. He had given him permission, in this one instance, to pose as his master. It was necessary. The fools who called themselves Death Eaters would fall in line immediately and turn over the boy they captured; Merlin knew why they'd done it.

A pale, bony hand turned the brass doorknob—his hand, for now—as he stepped out into the hallway, wand in hand. Quirrell strode confidently down the hallway, past an unmoving Death Eater's body—dead or unconscious, he neither knew nor particularly cared—and, briefly, past a window. It was then that he heard the unmistakable crack! of a Disapparating wizard. Close to twenty of them, like an erratic staccato beat, followed by, of all things, the hoot of a barn owl. He looked outside and saw uniformed Aurors appearing all around the field, eyes wary for danger and wands held at the ready. But it wasn't the Aurors that caught his eye.

Dumbledore led them, a brilliant phoenix riding his shoulder. A mad rush of terror swept through him, making his knees turn weak and his hand tremble. How did he know to come here? He wondered. He'd been certain the Headmaster had bought his story hook, line, and sinker.

"Dismiss the spells! Hide!" He said. Quirrell did not need to be told twice.

"Finite!" he cast. "Finite! Finite! Finite! Finite Incantatem!" One by one, the spells disguising his appearance ended, and Quirrell wrapped his purple turban back around his head with quick, practiced motions.

o—o—o—o

"It didn't work," Amycus said flatly. Lucius was stunned. After everything he'd gone through to avoid the ritual being performed with a living subject, he'd finally resigned himself to defeat only to be faced with... this. It was unexpected.

"Perhaps," Alecto mused, "she doesn't want to return?" They'd done everything right, he was sure of it. He knew that a single misspoken word could result in disaster, but when they'd completed the ritual the change should have been unmade. Instead...this. Milo stirred feebly on the table.

"I somehow doubt we need their permission," Lucius drawled. "Or we never would have been able to summon him in the first place." He tried to keep the elation out of his tone. Like most in the magical world, he was hardly a religious man, but now more than ever he was certain that if there really were a God out there, he was on Lucius's side. He'd been given another chance to make his plan work. "In fact—" he cut off as he heard the hoot of a barn owl. The elaborate system of wards around his manor had, of course, nothing on Hogwarts—but it did tell him when someone Apparated onto the grounds. "It appears members of the law enforcement community have decided to pay a call. Gibbon, Avery—guard the prisoner and keep your heads down. The rest of you know what to do." With a series of cracks, the other Death Eaters vanished into thin air. This wasn't the first time the DMLE had decided to raid his manor, but they wouldn't find any more than they ever did. Oh, he always left a few minor illicit trinkets and dark objects around, anything else would be suspicious—but in the end, it would amount to nothing more than a slap on the wrist.

Lucius stepped out of the ritual chamber in his basement and tapped the door behind him with his wand. Wooden boards, curled up around the entrance, unfurled with a groan to cover the door. The gap in the wall was seamless; a Malfoy in the distant past had found an apprentice to the master wizard who had hidden Diagon Alley to do the job. Not even Lucius knew what had happened to his body, after he was done. None but his inner circle knew of this hidden chamber, and nobody still living knew the trick to opening it. Lucius transfigured his mask into oil (which he poured into a lamp nearby, he doubted anyone would ever find that when the spell wore off) and went out to greet Amelia Bones like a friend coming over for tea. He felt tremors in the floor along the way, but ignored them.

o—o—o—o

Quirrell knew the plan needed changing. It always came to this; he'd gotten quite good at thinking on his feet. Despite what looked to him like half the Ministry's magical might knocking down the doors, he would settle for no less than complete victory. Quirrell cast a Disillusionment charm and shuddered as the icy feeling came over him. Before meeting him in the forests of Albania, he'd never had a knack for combat magic, but he'd always been good at these. Hiding was something of a specialty for him.

Strolling down the corridors of the richly-appointed house, he quickly found the small service staircase. The house rocked suddenly, but Quirrell had more pressing matters than the inevitable conflict between the Aurors and Death Eaters around. What the purpose of a staircase for servants in a wizard's house was, Quirrell had no idea (House Elves could simply snap their fingers and Apparate). The stairs led him through narrow corridors winding about in plain backrooms and servant's chambers (maybe the house had belonged to Muggles at some point, although it seemed out of Lucius's character to live anywhere that their touch had sullied) until he came to the otherwise unremarkable stretch of wall that he had directed him to. Quirrell tapped the wall with his wand, and was astonished to find a hidden doorway revealed.

"Alohomora." The door behind popped open, and even his usual control broke. "Merlin's beard!"

o—o—o—o

"As you can see," Lucius said to Amelia Bones, the head of the DMLE, while the two strode through the hallways of his mansion near his front entrance, "once again, my home has been attacked by the most brazen thieves I have ever seen. Fortunately, the timely intervention of the Ministry's finest has apparently frightened them off. I am, of course, eternally in your debt." Bones eyed him skeptically. He knew the aged witch had strong suspicions of him, but he also knew that she would never act on them without definite proof. Which was why men—and, of course, women—of principles always lost to those like him, who were free of such... constraints. Dumbledore, who had no official ministry standing, contented himself by waiting outside—for now.

Lucius led her towards his sitting room. "I'll have Dobby bring us some tea while your men search the house for the other thieves," he said, opening the door. "Though I doubt you'll find—" shooting up through the centre of his luxurious room was a great oak tree. The floorboards were bent and buckled around it, as was the ceiling. "Merlin!" he gasped. He couldn't help himself. Even Bones, who was rumoured to chew iron ore and spit nails, widened her eyes. Tangled among the branches were Gibbon and Avery, struggling vainly to escape.

Both were still wearing their masks.

Bones stared at the vista before her, shocked beyond belief. He knew he had to act quickly, or things could quickly become...embarrassing.

Lucius hesitated only seconds.

"Death Eater scum!" he gasped. "Call in your Aurors!"

o—o—o—o

Milo picked himself out from among the leaves and branches and climbed onto the Malfoy manor' tiled roof. Note to self: never again use a Tree Token as an elevator. Being slammed facefirst into four stories of old, hard wood was not his idea of fun. He looked over the edge and sighed.

"At least I'm not jumping through glass this time. Feather Fall."

Chapter 28: Grappling with the Rules

Author's Notes: Another short chapter – but at least I'm on time! This will continue until I get back into the swing of things.

o—o—o—o—o—o—o

The locked door swung open without making a sound. Inside was a familiar, large, dark room.

"Some lights all 'round, yeah?" Milo asked quietly. He'd do it himself, but he had to conserve his magic—even the cantrips—until the final confrontation. With no discernible limit (as far as he could tell) on the number of spells they could cast each day, Milo needed to rely on them to get him to Quirrell.

But that was the proper state of affairs. It felt right to him. All that solo adventuring? That was unnatural. Wizards, while hardly social creatures, do operate best in groups of less-arcane, more-giant-sword-wielding, possessor-of-the-mighty-thews, slayer-of-many-a-fell-beast, meat shields. Or, failing that, friends—Milo still couldn't believe he was using that term and meant it—with magic.

It was like being in a party again. Even if it was a party entirely composed of squishy wizards.

"Lumos," Hermione and Ron muttered, and the tips of their wands began to glow like torches.

"Blimey," Ron said.

"Merlin," Hermione said in a whisper.

"Indeed," Milo agreed, staring into the room. This was most unexpected.

The room was empty.

"Well," Milo said. "That was most unexpected. I suppose they haven't gotten around to replacing the dog, after all. Shall we?" He gestured to the trap door that lay beneath where Fluffy once sat.

"You know," Ron said idly, "I seem to remember this room being, well, bigger last time we were here."

"Now that you mention it," Milo said, "I think you're right. I mean, it is big—"

"—but not that big, you know?" Ron said.

"Yeah. Weird."

"It is not weird," Hermione said. "Honestly, haven't any of you ever read Hogwarts: A History?"

"I have, actually," Milo said. He'd Scholar's Touch'd it a while back, but remembering things read in a flash like that was tricky, much like having a photograph shoved in front of your face, only to be yanked away again a second later. Sure, you saw the picture, but it doesn't quite sink in the same way as if you had carefully perused it.

"Space is somewhat... flexible in the castle, because of the sheer concentrated magic of the place" she explained. "Makes it easy to resize certain rooms with a powerful enough Enlargement Charm. They must have done so to fit the dog in—I mean, there's no earthly reason a school would have a random room big enough to hold a Cerberus, right?"

"Oh, I dunno," Ron said dreamily. "I can think of one or two."

"Let me guess," she asked. "Slytherin disposal chute?"

"Actually, I was thinking, 'know-it-all containment chamber,' but your way works, too." After that, Ron fell silent and stared at the trapdoor. Their unimportant conversation was simply to put off the inevitable, and they all knew it. None of them knew what lay beyond that trap door, but one thing was for certain: there wouldn't be any more freebies like this room had been.

Milo grabbed the heavy wrought-iron ring of the trapdoor and pulled. It opened with an oily squeak which rang through the oversized, silent room. Through the trapdoor lay a deep, dark shaft. Ron reached down with his lit wand, which cast a pale white light on the walls of the shaft.

There was no bottom in sight.

"Light," Milo muttered, fetching a Knut from his pocket. The coin lit up, and with a sigh (Milo hated throwing money away, even other people's money) tossed it into the pit. They all leaned over and watched the bronze coin fall for what seemed like ages, before finally it ceased moving at what looked like miles underground. Of course, it was probably only extremely far down, and not quite as ridiculously far as it appeared, but one never knew when wizards were involved.

A second later the coin went dark.

"Spell doesn't last very long, eh?" Ron asked.

"No," Milo said slowly. "It lasts for hours."

"So, what happened? Some sort of counterspell?" Ron asked, looking meaningfully at Hermione.

"Don't look at me like I know the answer," she huffed indignantly. "If there's one thing we've learned, it's that none of us have any idea what to expect when Milo's magic encounters our own. I don't even know if a counterspell would work."

As she spoke, Milo noticed a brief glimmer of light from the bottom of the pit.

"It's still on down there," he said. "It's just... covered by something."

"Something moving, it would appear," Hermione agreed.

"You don't think... you don't think it might be spiders, do you, mate?" Ron asked shakily.

"Nah," Milo said. "Can't be spiders."

"Well, that's good," Ron said. "But, er, why can't it be?"

"Because we've already fought spiders too many times this campaign. I bet it's scorpions." Milo paused, thinking. He had fifty feet of silk rope (of course), but that hole as far deeper than fifty feet. Maybe, if they all jumped close enough together, he could Feather Fall them before the end? But what if there was something dangerous on the ground? Perhaps if they were Feather Fall-ing, one of them could hammer a piton into the wall near the bottom of the pillar and use it to—

"Right then," Ron said, and jumped in without hesitation.

There was a moment of crystalline silence, where Milo and Hermione stared at each other in absolute shock.

"Well, what are we waiting for?" she asked, her voice sounding somewhat strained. "We have to go after him!"

Milo swallowed, and they jumped in together. They were in complete darkness, save for the light of Hermione's wand and that of Ron's far below them, tumbling down an impressively deep pit. Milo, despite himself, lost track of how many increments of ten feet (and thus, how much damage he'd take upon landing) somewhere distressingly close to terminal velocity. Gritting his teeth, he shook his hands free of his sleeves and readied an action.

"Feather Fall!" he shouted, and the two of them slowed to a gentle drift barely a few feet before touching the ground.

"Ron!" Hermione shouted. "Ron, are you al—all right?" Milo had a sneaking suspicion of what Hermione was going to ask before she caught herself.

"Nah, I'm fine," came his cheerful voice. "There's this soft plant thing I landed on, it's lucky, really." Milo realized embarrassedly that he'd been so distracted thinking about Ron that he hadn't properly taken stock of his surroundings. Ron was lying on the ground nearby on a thick, green carpet of slender vines. The lit Knut was nowhere to be seen. "Dumbledore must have had this thing planted to keep people falling from being hurt. Mind, a mattress would have done, too."

"No..." Milo said, thinking. That seemed wrong to him.

Suddenly, Hermione shrieked. Snaklelike tendrils of vine, moving with deceptive speed, wrapped themselves around her legs to the knee. "It's Devil's Snare!" She shouted.

"Sorry, is that supposed to mean something to me—Merlin's Beard!" Tendrils pounced like a cat, and suddenly Ron was gone.

"Crap, crap crapcrapcrap!" Milo swore, trying to avoid the vines. Despite his efforts, he found his muscles refusing to respond and his feet remained firmly planted (so to speak) to the ground. He fought down a groan. He had no idea what to do or how to move—he'd never understood the Grapple rules. Nobody understood the Grapple rules!

The vines managed to grab hold of Hermione's wand hand, and, while it looked like she was struggling to say something, they were covering her mouth as well. Oddly, they seemed to be largely ignoring Milo, who was still locked up with immobility. He frowned and tried to ignore Hermione and Ron's muffled screams as he focused on what the page(s) describing the rules looked in like in the Rulebook. If he could remember that, maybe he could remember what they said. He remembered a distinct lack of pictures or explanatory illustrations (that would require the initial writers of the Rulebook to understand the Grapple rules, and, of course, they did not). He knew his Grapple bonus was +2, but only because that was on his character sheet. He didn't know how that was calculated or even what it was used for. Maybe if he...

"Ah, screw it. Levitate." He cast the spell, not at himself, but at Hermione. His magic effortlessly pulled her out of the tangled vines (one thing he could remember was that, while grappling, you 'can't move normally,' but being Levitated could hardly be considered normal, now could it?). However, the Snare seemed to have finally taken note of him, and a cluster of twisting tendrils jumped at him. Milo snorted and clubbed one of the approaching vines with his staff. To his surprise, the rest seemed to recoil in what seemed like pain and avoided him — for now. "Hermione!" Milo shouted at his newly liberated friend. "Do something smart—Aaaagh!" The vines jumped him in force, and Milo, for the first time in his life, wished he'd taken the Combat Reflexes feat. He was dimly aware that initiating a Grapple attempt provoked an Attack of Opportunity (AoO) from the defender, which, if it hit, negated the attempt. Evidently, this vine was capable of multiple attacks per round, but Milo could only make one AoO. Still unable to resist (he didn't even know what check to make to begin to do so), the vines effortlessly lifted him from the floor bodily and pinned him up against the wall. Cold, damp darkness coated him, shutting out most of the light.

Somehow, Hermione had managed to maintain a firm grip on her wand while being pinned. Hermione muttered a spell—Milo didn't catch the name of it—and a jet of pale blue fire launched out of her wand in a carefully controlled burst. Milo felt the vines immediately loosen from around him, and with relief he sagged to the ground. They retreated to the sides of the room and remained perfectly still, as if they were a normal, non-animated plant. He heard the ringing clink of a coin dropping, and his lit Knut illuminated the room. Ron was gasping for breath on the floor, but was otherwise all right.

It was only then that Milo got a clear view of the Devil's Snare. Weirdly, the vines were streaked with a sickly, pale yellow and brown. Judging by the thick mat on the ground, they'd been shedding leaves for some time now, and dead tendrils coated the floor.

"Weird," he muttered. Why use a plant-based trap if you weren't going to take proper care of it?

"How did you know?" Hermione asked, looking at him.

"What?"

"That the Devil's Snare is attracted to movement! The harder you struggle, the more it fights. I can't believe I forgot that, I feel like such an idiot."

"Right. Yes, that's exactly why I wasn't moving. The very reason indeed." That must have been why the Devil's Snare only jumped him when he cast a spell—the movement had attracted it. "Why did it run away like that?"

"Fire," Hermione said. "It's scared of fire—we learned that in Herbology, remember? Actually, I'm amazed you forgot that and remembered how it senses prey, because that's far more obscure..."

"Just slipped my mind for a minute," Milo lied. "Let's push ahead, eh? Villain to defeat, hero to save, all that."

Chapter 29: Check Mate, Mate

"Well, crap," Milo muttered. "That right there is a Hell of a lot of keys."

There were thousands of tiny golden, silver, and brass keys fluttering about the chamber, somewhat reminiscent of Golden Snitches—if the semi-sentient sporting equipment were somehow integral to solving the plot and defeating a powerful dark wizard. (Psh).

"So... what," Ron mused, "we have to find the right one? That's like looking for a, well, a key in a stack of keys. Moving keys. Blimey, this will take the rest of our lives."

"Assuming we could even grab them," Hermione added. "They're pretty high up there. Or, you know, I could save the lot of us a lifetime of searching, and just Alohomora the lock."

"Brilliant!" Ron exclaimed.

Hermione raised her wand and aimed it at the door, but stopped abruptly.

"Unless, of course, someone wants to interrupt my spell to vent his or her paranoid delusions about how the door is clearly trapped," she said to no-one in particular. Milo felt his cheeks growing hot. "Or some crackpot, circuitous theory about Dumbledore's real, secret plan."

"Just open the damn door, Hermione," Milo growled. "There's no sensible reason that, if they had a charm or whatever that could stop Alohomora, they'd use it here and not on the first door. Clearly, it slipped the vaunted brain of our brilliant headmaster that Flickwick was handing out magical lockpicks to eleven-year-olds."

"Very well, if you insist. Alohomora!" Nothing happened. Hermione frowned. "Alohomora!"

"Isn't it Alo-ho-more-ah?" Ron teased.

"Oh, shut up, Ron. Anyone have another idea?"

"My Merlin-like powers of deduction suggest we try to find the key," said Ron. "Or, maybe Milo can use some kind of hitherto-unforseen door-opening spell?"

I could always Fly up there, Milo mused, but I wouldn't even know where to begin to find the right key— much less actually catch it. Besides, I need to preserve my magic for the BBEG.

"Stands to reason we should be able to get through without resorting to that," he said. "Quirrell and Harry obviously managed to get through here, right? They only had wanded magic."

"Good name," Hermione said idly. Her forehead was creased with thought, staring up at the keys.

"Thanks. I figured some sort of differentiation was necessary. Ron, take a look around the room and see if you can find anything helpful—a clue, or maybe a piece of equipment."

"Right," he said, and started wandering around the labyrinthine room. Thick, heavy pillars broke up sightlines at irregular intervals, necessitating a manual search of the room.

"Hermione, I need you to make a Knowledge check."

"Pardon?" she asked.

"Just sit and think about the room you're in. Does anything about this ring any bells? Do flying keys appear prominently in any local lore or children's legends?"

Hermione blinked, then frowned, as if trying to remember something said in a conversation from a fortnight prior that only barely registered.

"The Flying Keys were a pair of brothers who were famous pilots decades ago," she said, "but I doubt that has any bearing here." Milo, to whom a pilot was someone who navigated a boat into or out of dangerous harbours in foul weather, was unable to fathom how they earned such a nickname. He chose, however, not to inform Hermione to this particular fact. "Other than that... no. I've got nothing. However, we can probably assume the key was made to match the lock, correct?"

"Hmm. That depends. If the builder wanted to keep us out, the key would have no obvious identifying features whatsoever, and only be determinable by, say, a custom spell. No, scratch that. If he or she really wanted to keep everyone out, there wouldn't be a door. You don't build doors to keep people out—that's what walls are for. The door could be some sort of trick... maybe it's a con. A shell game. None of the keys fit. This room was created to delay intruders until a crack team of Aurors can arrive."

"Can't be," Hermione countered. "Quirrell and Harry got through ahead of us, so there must be some way through. Maybe it's a test?" she suggested. "You can only pass if you can figure out the puzzle?"

"But why?" Milo asked. "I see two possibilities: this dungeon is either some sort of test of worthiness, or it's designed to keep anyone out who doesn't know the trick to entering. In the first case... why bother? If they wanted to give the Stone to someone worthy, Dumbledore and Flamel could just work together and pick someone, avoiding this hassle. In the second case, and it's designed for only a select group of people to enter—say, Dumbledore, Flamel, maybe McGonagall—then why have any clues at all? Everyone in the group knows the trick. Anything and everything observable in the dungeon, therefore, is designed to throw intruders off the trail to it. It's just as likely that none of the keys work, and there's a secret password or lever—or a hidden door."

"My point still stands. Quirrell figured it out, remember?"

"Unless..." Milo used a dramatic pause as cover to reach into his Belt. "Gotcha!" he shouted, flinging a handful of garlic powder directly behind him. "Crap," he sighed.

"Let me guess," the corners of her lips twitched slightly. "You assumed he was hiding under the effects of a Disillusionment Charm, waiting for us to open the door so he, being a dastardly villain, could follow us through?"

"...Maybe. But it was a perfectly reasonable guess, and if you say one word otherwise, please be reminded that I know where you live."

"There's one more thing we haven't considered," Hermione said slowly. "Maybe Quirrell is one of this alleged group, and knows the trick?"

"I... crap." It made sense. Quirrell was the DADA Professor, after all. If they were going to build a big dungeon to keep out dark wizards in their castle, who else would you ask for help? Of course Quirrell knew the way through this room.

"Blimey!" Ron shouted from across the room. "You'll never guess what I've found?"

"A secret door?" Hermione asked.

"Treasure?" Milo said at the same time.

"Neither!" Ron said. "three Comet Two-Sixties!"

"Crap. Crap. Crap." Milo was still unable to get a broomstick to respond to his presence at all, and Hermione was hardly any better. A quick glance at Hermione's face revealed she didn't relish the thought of flight any more than he did.

"And they've been slashed to pieces!" Ron added.

"Oh, thank God," Hermione said explosively, releasing a long-held breath.

"So, what were you two talking about? Figure out what we're supposed to do, yet?" Ron asked.

"Uh..." Milo said. "Sort of. We determined the door is trapped, and that none of the keys fit it... and that it's probably a fake and we have to beat a con man at a shell game, or... something. It got kind of complicated."

"So... I take it we're still clueless."

"Ah, screw it. Kelgore's Fire Bolt." An obsidian-black shard of stone glowing red with heat burst from Milo's opened palm and flew towards the door at just under the speed of sound, arcane energy crackling around it like a comet's tail. As soon as the tip of the stone touched the ancient oak door, it exploded into a searing red ball precisely five feet across, leaving their vision flecked with purple specks. The door splintered, and charred chunks of wood scattered about the room.

"Merlin's left foot!" Ron cursed, rubbing at his eyes.

Hermione stared at the door, her face a mask of abject terror.

"We are going to get in so much trouble," she quailed.

"Whatever. We'll do the paperwork, update our character sheets, and face the consequences of our actions later—maybe. It's the adventurer's way. In the meantime, there's a dungeon to crawl."

Ron cautiously poked a large chunk of ex-door with the remains of a Comet-Two Sixty. The solid-looking wood crumbled into ash at the gentle contact, scattering in the gentle draft created by the fluttering wings above.

"Blimey," he said almost reverently.

"Evocation is generally underpowered," Milo said, "but, on occasion, it can have its uses."

The next chamber was lit only by the glow of the room before entering through the smoldering doorway. Milo could barely make out large, towering armoured figures with a vaguely humanoid shape standing in front of him, lined up like a phalanx. He took a hesitant step forward, and the instant that his foot touched the ground in the new room, his vision flooded white. His eyes took a few seconds to adjust to the vision in front of him.

What Milo had taken to be armoured soldiers were, instead, giant black chessmen (although, as an experienced adventurer, he refused to rule out the possibility that they were Animated). They were carved to resemble armoured soldiers, weapons and all – except for their faces. Some of the pieces wore helmets, but the rest had blank, expressionless smooth surfaces in their place. As someone who had never seen a mannequin before, he found the sight distinctly unnerving.

"I'm an idiot," Ron said quietly.

"Sorry, what?" Milo asked. He was missing something.

"You'll see. I'd bet my magic that we have to play our way across."

"Before jumping to any conclusions," Hermione suggested, "how about we test that? Wingardium Leviosa." She levitated a large chunk of door across the oversized chessboard. The black players seemed to ignore it, but as it reached the white line, a pale pawn leapt forwards at a diagonal and ran it through with his spear. Milo winced. He knew that stone weaponry took a -2 penalty to attack and damage, but, looking at the razor-sharp edges of the nearby black soldiers' gear, he doubted that applied here. The white pawn stepped back into his original position, looking no different than before save for a light dusting of ash. "Okay," Hermione admitted. "we have to play our way across."

"Fortunately," Ron said with a slightly shaky grin, "I have something of an advantage here."

"Why's that?" Milo asked, "because you happened to put maximum ranks in Profession (Chess Player)? And here I thought those were wasted."

"Just watch. Milo, do me a favour and take the place of the left bishop? That's the one with the pointy hat and mace. Hermione, take the third pawn from the right."

"But—" Milo protested.

"Just trust me."

"He is the best chess player in the school, remember?" Hermione pointed out lightly. "We had that tournament and everything. Still..." she stepped into the place of the designated pawn. "This does seem awfully specific."

It suddenly struck Milo that he'd completely forgotten that 'chess' was on the Plot. Cursing himself, he reluctantly took the place of the bishop, who mutely stepped off the board to make way for him. Of course chess would come up here, at the end. The sheer number of times it had been mentioned would be mind-bogglingly pointless had there not been some sort of chess-related puzzle.

"What about you?" Hermione asked Ron.

"I'm the king, of course. Just do what I say, and we'll be fine. I promise."

Reluctantly, Milo and Hermione agreed.

After they had taken their places, a white pawn slid forward towards their side. Ron ordered one of his pawns forward, looking not quite as confident as he sounded. Milo noticed a somewhat wild look to his eyes, but, after seeing the white side's response (another pawn), he let out a deep breath and smiled, as if the white side had fallen for some sort of trap. After that, Ron began to below orders at a shocking pace. He barely waited for each piece to finish moving before moving his next one. The white pieces, driven by silent orders, responded immediately to each move.

Milo was surprised, to say the least. He knew Ron was good, but this... it was as if Ron were reading off of a script, knowing in advance what he would say each turn well before he spoke. The sheer amount of information he must be processing to give commands that quickly... either Ron had been holding out on a Headband of Intellect +10, or he had no idea what he was doing and simply giving orders at random.

Milo swallowed nervously as it came time to act. Despite Ron's confidence, they were losing pieces. A lot of pieces. There were only two pawns, aside from Hermione, still standing on their side. They'd lost their other bishop early on to what had to have been a sheer blunder — though Ron's confident, almost bored, expression never changed.

Still, Ron was a better player than he had ever been. Milo walked diagonally across the board, standing uncomfortably close to a white knight. The knight completely ignored his presence, sitting atop his pale horse, long white blade in hand. While he was fully aware that the knight could only move in a weird, L-shape (suddenly, the Cleric spell Knight's Move made a lot more sense to him), and that he was perfectly safe where he was standing, the sword still sent shivers down Milo's spine.

The rules of chess were clear: when a piece took another piece, the taken piece didn't have a hope of fighting back, even a mighty queen against a lowly pawn. So Milo wondered what would happen if he was hit by that sword and survived. Would the knight simply repeatedly stab him until satisfied? Or would the game carry on, ignoring his presence completely, as he bled out on the floor?

Hermione, meanwhile, was tapping her foot impatiently. She'd been almost completely ignored by Ron, only moving up to allow another piece to pass early on.

A black castle stepped up and smashed the white knight off of his horse with a heavy, flanged mace. The knight's horse dragged its rider off the board, and then there was silence.

"Check..." Ron said quietly. Then he drew a deep breath, letting it out explosively. "Mate."

The remaining white pieces (the ones that could still stand, anyway) walked to the edges of the board and bowed slightly.

"How did you do that?" Hermione asked, throwing her arms around him in a hug. "That was incredible!"

Milo was beginning to have suspicions at that point.

Ron simply shrugged, looking a little embarrassed at Hermione's outcry. "I'd played the same game before."

"You... what?" Hermione asked, stepping back from him. Several pieces clicked in Milo's head so loudly he was surprised nobody noticed.

"When I played against Quirrell, I was really playing the castle."

"He used his little tournament to find which of us were good at chess," Milo said with realization. "The wily bastard."

"I knew chess had nothing to do with Defence!" Hermione exclaimed.

"Right. So every time I made a move, he'd go down here and make the same move against the castle, then use its move against me. Quirrell's likely rubbish at chess."

"But the white side's just a spell," Milo murmured. "It doesn't have any creativity of its own, just an elaborate set of premade responses. So when you made the exact same moves against it..."

"...It made the same moves against me," Ron finished. "It was the hardest game I'd ever played—but I'd already done it and knew how it ended."

"You put all that together just by seeing the chess game down here?" Hermione asked. Her eyes were a little wide. Milo was having to make some revisions in his mind, as well. There might be more to Ron than he had previously thought.

o—o—o—o—o—o—o

Author's Notes: When I came up with the chess trick Quirrell played on the party, I was so proud of myself. I went around congratulating myself all day for my own cleverness and ingenuity. Within five minutes of posting the chess chapter, however, a reader PM'd me, guessing exactly what had happened. I suppose some metagamers out there flagged any mention of 'chess' as suspicious, considering the dungeon crawl at the end.

Now I'm curious. Was Quirrell's trick really brilliant, or was it transparent? Leave a review saying if you'd called it in advance or were caught by surprise.

Chapter 30: Troll Wanted: Dead or Alive

Milo opened the door a crack and peeked through. The room was pitch dark, but his sense of smell confirmed his suspicions.

Crap.

He, ever so quietly, closed the door and looked back at his companions.

"Right," he whispered. "So, there's a Troll on the other side of this door."

His companions stared at him blankly for a few seconds, then cursed sulfurously.

"The same one as before?" Ron asked after venting for a moment. "If we're lucky, it'll be so scared of Hermione here that it'll lie down and play dead when we enter."

"Could be," Milo said, "But I wouldn't count our lives on that. Frankly... I'm not sure we can take him." The last encounter he had had with a Troll had proved definitely, dreadfully, defenestratively disastrous. He looked at his comrades, whose faces were ashen. They'd thrown everything they'd had at it, and it had still gotten away. Hermione and he had been seriously injured.

"Wait!" Ron said, his face brightening suddenly. "Milo can just blast it like he did that door!"

"Yeah..." Milo said, "about that. That was kind of a one-off. Sorry, guys. What else have we got?" Maybe they should have tried to solve the last puzzle after all—the fickle being that ran the universe appeared to be punishing him for his brute force approach.

"If we had a large quantity of dust, I suppose I could use Ventus again," Hermione mused. "But even that didn't finish off the last one."

"How about a Hippogriff?" Ron suggested. "Like back at the Duelling Club. That Hufflepuff was in the hospital wing for three days—mind, I reckon he was just trying to skive classes."

"Didn't prepare Summon Monster," Milo admitted, "but I have something that's almost as good for this. I only give it even odds of winning, though, so I suggest we run past it while it's distracted. Sound good?"

"Not particularly," Hermione confessed, "But I don't see that we have any other option."

"Great. This spell takes six seconds to cast, so open the door for me at the count of five, okay?" Ron nodded, and moved to stand by the heavy, iron-studded wooden door. Milo rolled up his sleeves, adjusted his Arcanist's Gloves slightly, and began casting. Ron swallowed nervously, his hand on the doorknob.

"Summon Skeletal Troll!" The door flew open, and a towering nightmare of a figure appeared before them. Without pausing to look closer, Milo and the others bolted through the door, an almost-physical wall of putrid stench assaulting their noses. In the darkness, he heard someone gag, but kept running until he hit the far wall. Undead had Darkvision out to 60 feet, so Milo wasn't worried about his summoned monster. If anything, the undead Troll likely had the advantage over the living one in this lighting. Milo felt around at the wall that he was touching, searching for an exit.

Then he encountered a problem.

"Where in the Infinite Layers of the Abyss is the thrice-damned door?" he hissed quietly. It was so dark that he could barely see the blue-and-gold of his own gloves.

"Lumos," Ron cast, and his wand glowed, clearly illuminating the door—and them.

"No!" Hermione shrieked, staring at the lit wand. She covered her mouth in horror, looking around nervously for the Troll. Milo prepared to launch a salvo of magic at the Troll that he was sure was about to fall on them like a landslide.

Nevertheless, nothing happened.

"I thought you said there was a Troll," Hermione whispered accusingly.

"I smelled a Troll," Milo said. "I just assumed there was one, too. I mean, it makes sense, right? This dungeon was probably made by the top Hogwarts teachers, each one making a single room—Professor Sprout did the Devil's Snare, probably—and Quirrell has this whole Troll thing going on, so I figured—"

"Found him," Ron said, the light of his wand revealing the unmistakable cadaver of an ex-Troll. "Big ol' bugger's dead already. Ruddy convenient, that is."

"Perhaps Quirrell killed him on the way in?" Hermione suggested. Milo shrugged, dismissing his skeleton with a casual wave.

"Looks like."

The next room simply had a large table with seven mismatched bottles arranged on a thick tablecloth. As soon as they entered the room, purple flames appeared behind them, blocking their escape. Black flames guarded the door on the other side of the room.

"Bugger," Ron muttered. "This has 'Snape' written all over it. We should have brought shampoo; any fire made by that git would probably bugger off in fright after one whiff of it."

"Look!" Hermione pointed at a small roll of parchment on the table. "Wingardium Leviosa." The roll floated over to her.

"Why not just pick it up?" Milo asked.

"All this talks of traps must be making me paranoid," Hermione confessed. "I felt I couldn't be too careful—especially if Professor Snape" (she shot a look at Ron) "had anything to do with it."

"You're learning, young grasshopper," Milo said sagely.

"I'm actually older than you are," Hermione pointed out. "I'm twelve, after all. You're only eleven."

"Ish," Milo corrected. "Eleven-ish. Birth date still unknown. Anyways, what's on the paper?"

"It's a puzzle!" she said, a smile growing on her face. "One of the potions will let us through, I just need to figure out which. It's brilliant—a lot of wizards haven't got an ounce of logic, they'd be stuck in here forever."

"You don't say?" Milo asked. So wanded magic wasn't Intelligence-based after all. Interesting. Very interesting.

"The only catch is, three of the bottles are poison—the rest are wine, except for one that lets the drinker go back, of course—so it's important I figure out which is which. Now just give me a second. Let's see..." Hermione looked at each bottle closely, and re-read the parchment several times. "I've got it!"

"We drink from the little one," Ron said.

"—we drink the smallest one!" Hermione finished. "Oh. How did you figure?"

"Quirrell must have drunk one when he went through earlier," Ron said. "Harry too, for that matter. The small one is clean and the others have all got dust on."

"...I see."

"But don't worry about it—a lot of the greatest wizards couldn't notice what's right under their noses, either," Ron said teasingly.

Interesting. It's not Wisdom-based, either. Could it be... (Milo shuddered at the thought) ...Charisma? It would explain why Grabbe and Coyle were failing most of their courses, and why Voldemort was simultaneously the greatest dark wizard alive (or possibly undead, Milo thought, fingering a wooden stake in his belt) and had an impressive cult following. Dumbledore, too, for that matter (except for the 'dark' part). Fortunately, PCs were explicitly immune to the effects of high-powered Diplomancy.

"We... have a slight problem," Hermione said in a small voice.

"Oh?"

"There's only enough for one of us," she said. "Hardly even that." She was right—the bottle was tiny.

Tiny... but full.

"The potion must replenish itself," Milo pointed out. "Assuming Quirrell and Harry came through here—and everything we've seen suggests that they have—they both had to have drunk from that bottle, which is nevertheless full to the cork. So all we have to do is go through one at a time. The only question is..."

"Which order do we go in?" Hermione asked.

"I was going to say, 'how long does it take to refill,' but yours is valid. The only two questions are: which order do we go in, and how long does it take to refill?"

"That, and 'what's on the other side, and does it want to eat our faces,'" Ron added.

"Right. Our three questions are: which order do we go in, how long does it take to refill, and what's on the other side, and does it want to eat our faces? Oh, and, how about, 'did Hermione pick the right bottle, or will the first drinker turn blue and die?' So our four questions are: which order, how long, what's on the other side—"

"—and does it want to eat our faces off—" cut in Ron.

"—Right, and does it want to eat our faces off, and did Hermione pick the right bottle."

"Wait," Hermione said. "Didn't you say your robes made you fire proof? You had me set you on fire and everything."

"Fire resistant," Milo corrected in a pained voice. "And it's only rated against regular fire. Against fancy black fire? It depends: how much does the DM hate me? The answer? Probably a lot." Milo could still remember the disastrous 'Use Spontaneous Divination to get Cleric Spells' fiasco.

"DM?" Ron asked in a puzzled voice.

"Disgruntled Mechanics. If you push the rules... sometimes, the rules push back."

"O-kay. Let's pretend I never asked, and I'll pretend you're not completely daft."

"Fair enough. How about you two play Fighter, Rogue, Wide-Mouth-Spiked-Pit-Trap to determine which of you goes first, and I'll chance the fire. The other one waits for the potion to refill and charges in to save us from whatever horrific fate we've found ourselves in. I'm thinking the giant squid that lives in the lake will figure in here somehow."

"I hesitate to ask, but... Fighter, Rogue, Wide-Mouth-Spiked-Pit-Trap?" Hermione asked.

"Sure. The Fighter Power Attacks the Rogue for quintuple the Rogue's HP, the Rogue uses Trap Sense and discovers and disarms the Wide-Mouth-Spiked-Pit-Trap, the Fighter has no skill ranks or good abilities other than Strength and Constitution and falls into the Wide-Mouth-Spiked-Pit-Trap. It's abstract, I know—for example, it assumes the theoretically possible but, in practice, impossible event of a Fighter engaging a competent Rogue in a fair combat—but really, when it comes down to it, it's just common sense."

"Oh, so just like Rock, Paper, Scissors, then," Hermione said.

"What is this Rock, Paper, Scissors of which you speak?"

"Well, rock bends the scissors, the scissors cut the paper, and the paper... well, I guess it wraps around the rock," Ron explained.

"I'd always assumed the paper was too flexible to be beaten by the rock," Hermione said. "Which is why it 'wins.'"

"Psht," Milo muttered. "The paper is probably a scroll of Rock to Mud. It's the only explanation that makes any sense."

"Regardless," Hermione cut in, "let's play, shall we? Milo, count us off."

"Three... Two... One..."

"Paper!" Hermione said, at the same time that Ron said "Wide-Mouth-Spiked-Pit-Trap!"

"Hooboy..." Milo muttered.

Eventually, Ron won out with rock ("I assumed you'd think I was the sort of person who always chose rock, so while I was going to trick you by choosing scissors, I realized, you might have guessed that I'd use my cunning ploy and that what I should really be using is paper, but then I remembered your scores in History of Magic so, taking into account the fact that you were a brainiac, I one-upped you again, which put me right back to rock. Bloody brilliant, I say.") against Hermione's scissors ("I assigned each move a number—paper was one, rock was two, scissors was three—and divided the third line of Snape's riddle by three, because three there are three of us (if it came out to four, it would wrap around and would count as 'paper,' of course, and five would be rock) to simulate a random move, which would thus be impossible to guess.")

"Ha!" Ron exclaimed. "I win! Who's clever now?"

"You were lucky," Hermione stressed. "There's a difference. Just because you were right doesn't mean it was the smart decision."

"Right," Milo said. "Drink up, and let's go rescue Harry."

Ron's grin vanished immediately.

"Ah, bugger. I forgot the prize was 'almost-certain grievous injury, with a side of dismemberment.' I should have lost."

"Who's clever now," Hermione muttered under her breath. Milo didn't think that he was supposed to hear it.

Milo walked over to the flickering black fire, feeling the heat rolling off of it. This was, oddly, reassuring—it was a weak implication that the fire did, well, Fire damage as opposed to something eviller, like Cold or Negative Energy. Or (Milo shuddered at the possibility) Level Drain. All things being equal, death was generally preferable to level loss. At least it was only a temporary inconvenience.

Beside him, Ron chugged the tiny bottle and shivered.

"It's like drinking ice water," he said, and passed the empty bottle to Hermione.

"I'll follow as soon as it refills," she promised. "Be careful, will you? If your theory is right, and each of the Heads of Houses and Quirrell made a room... well, this was the last one. Good luck." She looked like she wanted to say more, but decided against it and stepped back.

"Best take it at a run, you think?" Ron suggested.

"Agreed. Ready?" Milo asked, backing up a bit so he could Run through the fire.

"Ready."

o—o—o—o—o—o—o

Author's Notes: When organizing a D&D game, make sure to tell everyone to be there half an hour early. That way, you can get the obligatory incessant Monty Python quoting out of the way and still pick the lock on the ten-by-ten room containing an orc guarding a chest without running overtime. At least half an hour. Maybe an hour. A good hour.

The way I picture it, in Milo's universe, this behaviour results in PCs reflexively referencing Monty Python (and the Princess Bride, Lord of the Rings, etc.) without really understanding why. Milo is cut off from his Player, but the behaviour is deeply ingrained in him nonetheless.

Chapter 31: The Man With Two Faces

Author's Notes: For added realism, I rolled every die for this chapter.

o—o—o—o

"T-try harder! L-l-look at the M-Mirror and th-think about the g-g-good and h-h-healing you c-c-could do with it! Your f-f-friend is c-counting on y-you!"

"I'm trying, Professor! I can see myself using the Stone to cure Milo, but nothing else is happening! Are you sure this is how it works?"

Milo landed with a roll on the far side of the fire, feeling his hit points drop by one. Just his luck that the fire—which turned out to be rather ordinary, after all—rolled a six for damage. Smooth darkwood in his left hand, right hand ready for casting, Milo quickly took stock of the room in the way that only an Adventurer could. Fine details were simultaneously ignored and calculated for gold piece value, plot-relevant details were filed away for future reference, and threats were evaluated immediately.

The sum value of all unattended items in the stark room was a paltry 37gp, 4sp, and 7cp—not counting a rather familiar mirror that he deliberately avoided looking straight at. Standing in front of the Mirror of Erised was a surprised looking Harry, who was staring at the newcomers in astonishment.

In a flash, Quirrell had his wand out and was standing directly behind the still-amazed Harry.

Not good, Milo thought. Quirrell could kill all three of them before Milo could get a single spell off, most likely. Best get him talking. Every villain worth his black robes and skull necklace likes to monologue.

"So, you've been trying to get at the Stone this whole time, have you?" Milo asked. "I asked around. You've been teaching Muggle Studies at Hogwarts for four years before you got the Defence job. Were you just waiting, gaining the trust of everyone around you?" The specific words were unimportant to his plan — all that mattered was that he got Quirrell talking.

"Y-you fool!" Good start. When they start calling people fools, it generally means they're working their way up to a magnificent rant. "You th-think you have any inkling of m-my plan?"

"Well..." It was all Milo could do not to smile. "Since you're going to kill us anyways... could you at least tell me what the deal was with the Acromantula in the Forbidden Forest back in the fall?" Milo had been dying to figure out what that was all about. Harry stood with his hands up, Quirrell's wand pointed at his temples.

"You were s-s-supposed to die!" Quirrell said. "You knew t-too much! You even t-t-told me—said it was obvious to anyone with a brain—that you, your f-f-friends, and D-D-Dumbledore had f-f-figured it out! So kind of you t-to b-bring them h-here, b-by the way. Everyone except that G-G-Granger g-girl, anyway." Milo blinked. Figured what out? He could barely remember that conversation having taken place, much less the subject matter. "S-so I l-l-let that h-halfbreed oaf f-find out I w-was k-k-killing the unicorns in the f-f-forest to g-get you out in the f-f-forest alone. It w-was p-p-perfect... the spider would k-kill you and m-make it l-l-look like an accident. V-very t-tragic, I'd s-say... what a p-promising student you were..."

Quirrell was killing the unicorns? And now he's trying to get the Stone... What was it Milo had said? That there were likely followers of Voldemort out there, each competing to bring their master back? So... Quirrell wasn't just trying to get the Stone for himself. He was a Death Eater as well.

"...But you didn't count on me to kill it?" Milo asked. Except he hadn't killed it. Investigation had shown that the injuries he'd dealt it weren't nearly severe enough to finish the monster off. Everything pointed to a Killing Curse.

"You think you k-k-killed it? Fool! It was m-me!" Quirrell hesitated for a second. "I'd s-sworn n-n-never to mention this again, b-but... s-seeing as how I'm g-g-going to k-kill you anyways..." Milo couldn't help himself; he leaned in a little closer. "I t-tripped." Quirrell paused, and Milo heard Ron fighting down a laugh. "I w-was watching, under the c-cloak of a Disillusionment s-spell, w-when I s-slipped. The g-g-ground was unnaturally s-slippery" Milo grinned, despite himself. He'd cast a Grease spell, but hadn't imagined that he'd managed to get the end boss with it. "And the A-Acromantula h-heard me. I h-had n-no choice b-but to abort the p-plan, k-kill the spider, and Obliviate y-you."

"But you had plenty of opportunities to try again," Milo pointed out. "Why didn't... Oh. I see. After I told you how my magic works, you realized that I could be used to revive Volde— "

"D-don't s-speak his n-name!" Quirrell shouted.

"You-Know-Who, then. So, you changed gears... the Duelling Club. The Vampires. They weren't to kill me, they were to get me XP." That was so backwards, it almost hurt Milo's head. "You wanted me to level up, to turn me into a Philosopher's Stone!"

"It w-was one p-plan of m-many," Quirrell shrugged, though Milo noticed his wand remained pointed directly at Harry's head. "It n-never h-hurts to m-make... backups."

"So..." Milo could practically hear the gears whirring inside his head. It was like a scaled-down Mechanus in there. "You're also the one who possessed Hannah and me, I take it?" He asked in a deceptively cool voice.

"I—"

"For a Death Eater, you seem awfully afraid of your own master. You flinch every time anyone says Voldemort."

"You think I am a D-Death Eater?" Quirrell said incredulously. "You h-haven't realized anything yet!"

"One follower of Voldy is much like another," Milo shrugged. "I don't know, and, frankly, don't care if you have some sort of internal naming scheme or hierarchy. You're all just XP waiting to be collected, when it comes down to it." While Milo was speaking, Quirrell reached up with his off-hand and began unwrapping his turban. Milo was unconcerned—it wasn't until the Professor's wand hand began moving that he had anything to worry about. At worst, he was trying to activate some sort of magic item, and from what Milo had seen, the local magic items were mainly to aid in household activities. At worst, all potatoes in a sixty-foot radius would magically peel themselves.

"I am s-so much m-more than a m-mere D-Death Eater," Quirrell sneered, the turban falling to the floor. Harry cried out in pain suddenly, his hand going to his forehead. It came away bloody. "I am the a-avatar of the D-Dark L-Lord h-himself!"

A horrible, hissing voice that seemed to come from Quirrell—though his mouth never moved—spoke suddenly.

"Kill the newcomers... we only need the boy..."

Quirrell's wand came up, but Milo was faster.

"Nerveskitter," Milo said in harmony with himself as time bended around him, speeding his reflexes up slightly. Though a minor difference, all things considered, it was enough. "So, you're Lord Voldemort, eh?" Milo's raised his right hand, palm outspread and ready to cast. "They say you once murdered an entire family of Muggles. The entire family—cousins, cousins-in-law, grandparents, nieces, nephews. Everyone bearing the same surname. They say you did it just because a twenty-year-old and his new wife had a witch—a mudblood—for a daughter. They say you're more demon than man, that you sold your soul for dark powers. Some say you never had a soul to begin with. They say that merely saying your name aloud is enough to call your attention." Milo stared at the man standing in front of him, the man he had once trusted. Maybe he really was part demon, but templates came at the cost of all-important caster levels. "But, you know? People say a lot of foolish things. Once, I heard a Bard reason that, since wearing heavy armour reduced his Hide bonus, going absolutely naked would render him invisible." To an outside observer, it would seem remarkable that Voldemort would wait for Milo to continue before completing his spell. However, said outside observer was likely unaware that talking is a Free Action, and Milo could have recited The Raven in its entirety before allowing anyone else to act. "Really, when it comes down to it, your vaunted 'Dark Magic' is about as useful as a Fallen Paladin without your wand," Milo said. "It would be a shame if it were to, unexpectedly, say... Shatter."

A noise like an elder wyrm roaring echoed through the room, and Quirrell's alder wand exploded into splinters. Harry, taking advantage of the confusion, dashed away from the Mirror to join Ron and Milo.

"W-w-well," Quirrell stammered. Something felt wrong. Very wrong. "It w-would appear that I h-have b-been beaten..."

Milo blinked, then realized what it was: he hadn't got any XP. Quirrell wasn't defeated.

Then he remembered what happened after the first time he'd seen the Mirror of Erised...

Twelve sapient creatures. Quirrell counts as two, leaving ten unaccounted for.

"Glitterdust!" Milo cast the spell, not at Quirrell, but directly to his right. Milo's primary usage of the spell was generally to blind everyone in the area, but this time, he wanted it for its other purpose: revealing invisible creatures. Sparkly arcane doom rained down, revealing five small, heavily armed creatures that Milo was all-too familiar with...

...Redcaps.

Invisible Redcaps.

Crap.

The golden particles outlined the invisible creatures, each carrying a heavy sword like the one in the Forbidden Forest had. Milo guessed—though he doubted he could push Quirrell into another rant to confirm it—that that one had been sent by the Professor—no, by Voldemort—as part of his 'Level-Grind the PC plan.'

"The outlined ones will only be visible for 42 seconds!" Milo shouted to Ron and Harry. "Stun as many as you can—I'll deal with the other five!"

"Right!" Ron said. "Stun them with what, exactly?"

"I don't know! Stupefy or something!"

"But that's fourth-year—"

"JUST FIGURE SOMETHING OUT!" Three of the five glowing Redcaps had been blinded by the golden light, but the other two were advancing rapidly towards them. Milo could only guess what the other five were up to, but, fortunately, this was the fight he was made for. Enough of that one-on-one insanity. Battlefield control was a Conjurer's specialty.

"Web!" Thick, sticky webs appeared in the area that Milo guessed the still-invisible Redcaps were standing. The beauty of the Web spell is that even if the targets manage to make their Reflex saves, it doesn't really help them all that much. They still get a host of penalties, and requires an extremely difficult Strength check to move at all—and even then, extremely slowly. That, and at Milo's level, it lasts for over an hour. It is generally considered the pinnacle of the Conjuration school—and on top of all of that it's only a Second Level spell.

Milo could hear screams of frustration from the trapped Redcaps—but that was no guarantee that he'd caught all five.

"Can you smell any others?" Milo asked his familiar. Rats have a keen sense of smell, which is one of the reasons that he had picked Mordy as his companion. Mordy sniffed the air for a second, then nodded.

"Eleven o'clock, 20 feet. One straggler."

"Grease." The thud and metal-on-stone clatter confirmed the hit. Grease would only delay the Redcap, not trap it entirely like Web had. Milo glanced around to see how his companions were faring.

"Expelliarmus!" Harry shouted, and one of the Redcaps' sword went flying behind him.

"Wingardium Leviosa!" Ron cast immediately afterwards, catching the sword in midair and lifting it up over another's head, dropping (hilt-first) from five feet up. The Redcap moved to dodge, but was too slow and went down like a Sorcerer hit by a Greatclub. With one Redcap disarmed, another unconscious, and the other three still blind, there didn't seem to be any immediate threats, but Milo doubted that would last.

"Mirror Image," he cast, and six doppelgangers appeared around him. The unarmed Redcap didn't seem to know when it was beaten, and lunged at Ron, his golden hands clenching around the redheaded boy's throat.

"Crap!" Milo was out of attack spells except for Acid Splash, and he didn't even want to know what kinds of penalties could be incurred by shooting into a Grapple. He started running through a list of Divinations he could cast spontaneously that might be helpful, but Harry was faster.

"Expelliarmus!" Ron went flying out of the Redcap's hands. Brilliant, Milo thought. Expelliarmus knocks away whatever the target his holding, not just wands. Harry was already starting to think like a Munchkin; Milo would never admit it, but he felt somewhat proud of his party member. Glitterdust didn't provide enough detail for Milo to be sure, but he imagined a look of dumbfounded astonishment on the ugly Fey's face.

It was then that Milo had an Idea.

"Hey ugly!" Milo shouted at the unarmed Redcap. "Worried about your lack of weapon? A real Redcap doesn't need one—after all, I killed your buddy unarmed back in the Forbidden Forest." Milo couldn't tell if the Fey understood a word he said, but it lunged at him nevertheless. The darkwood staff whirled, and smashed into the creature's temple with as much force as Milo could manage (so, not a lot, when it comes down to it). The creature recovered, and attempted futilely to punch Milo through the protection of his Robe of Arcane Might. The bony fist slid off of the magically-augmented uniform and Milo attacked again.

Milo's bet paid off. He'd gambled that the Redcap hadn't taken the Improved Unarmed Strike feat—Hells, nobody takes Improved Unarmed Strike—and, therefore, would give Milo a free attack every time he tried to do the same. Despite Milo's slender build and lousy BAB, with a pair of attacks for every punch from the Redcap—combined with his high AC and miss chance from Mirror Image—the Fey didn't stand a chance.

As the Redcap fell to Milo's sixth blow, Mordy spoke again.

"Alert! Enemy approaching at six o'clock!"

Gods damnit! Milo thought, whirling around. It must be the one that I Greased. He'd completely forgotten about it when he'd gone in to play Big Stupid Fighter with the other one.

One of Milo's doubles flickered and vanished as, presumably, the invisible Redcap slashed at it with his wickedly curved sword. Ron and Harry each cast a Disarming Charm, but, without knowing exactly where the Redcap stood, they went wide. This was becoming far too hairy for a Wizard as squishy as he. For a second, Milo considered using Fly to reach the safety of the ceiling, but realized that that would leave Harry and Ron—who lacked his (by this world's standards) preternatural healing abilities and resilience—vulnerable. Instead, Milo decided that he'd be better to leave the battle in the hands of a specialist.

"Summon Skele—" halfway through the spell, the Redcap swung again, this time guessing the correct target. Milo tried to dodge, but only succeeded in mitigating the attack somewhat. The sword penetrated the spell-enhanced robes and drew a thick red line along Milo's chest, inflicting a hefty ten damage. He screamed in pain, and, falling to his knees, his concentration shattered.

The spell failed.

Milo spat blood and looked around the room hazily. Harry and Ron were still futilely shooting Disarming Charms around the room, trying to catch the invisible Redcap. Quirrell was standing by the Mirror counting silently, of all things. Milo narrowed his eyes, and realized what was happening.

Thirty-Nine... Forty... Forty-One...

"Forty-Two," Milo breathed, terror rising. The magic sustaining the golden particles surrounding the five Redcaps vanished, and they vanished. Two were unconscious, but the other three...

Normally, Milo would simply spontaneously cast See Invisibility and Fly, then proceed to rain blows upon the Redcaps' heads from above. However, despite having only two hit points left, he was still the best-defended of his group. Further, from what Milo had noticed, the Disillusionment Charm didn't make the wearer technically invisible, merely extremely well-concealed. As such, See Invisibility would be useless.

It was then that Milo noticed a glimmer of movement near the black fire of the doorway. This was unusual, as the Redcaps were all invisible, and both Ron and Harry were nowhere nearby...

"Incendio," he heard a feminine whisper. A barely-noticeable jet of bluebell fire, the same hue as what had been used against the Devil's Snare, hit a distant corner of Milo's Web.

Of course. Hermione. She was creeping along the side of the room near the door, with the Web spell between her and most of the Redcaps—and Quirrell—blocking vision.

"Duck!" Milo shouted. Harry and Ron, too surprised to do anything but comply, hit the ground immediately. The webs began to burn quickly—magical webs, unlike mundane webs, are highly inflammable. As the violet-blue flames spread throughout the faux-spidersilk, Milo heard Hermione's voice again.

"VENTUS!" A colossal gust of searing-hot air slammed into Milo bodily, knocking him onto his back. This was shortly followed by a raging-hot bluebell inferno as strands of inexplicably-inflammable webs were sucked up by the whirlwind and, suddenly oxygenated, exploded into fire. "Ventus! Ventus! Ventus!" Hermione, through clever use of controlled bursts of air, managed to direct the flame to a certain extent, causing it to avoid Harry and Ron. Milo's magic robes protected him (and Mordy, with Improved Evasion, had little to worry about), but the Redcaps had no such luck. As the fires began to die out, Hermione threw both glass bottles of wine from the potions riddle into the middle of it, the alcohol spilling out as the containers shattered. Redcaps screamed in agony as their clothes and hair burned in the suddenly refuelled inferno.

"Merlin's beard," Ron breathed as the fires died down. Invisible burning figures were sprinting around the room, trying to put out themselves out. One by one they began to drop.

Milo did some rapid counting.

"She only got five!" he shouted. "There's three more still conscious!"

Ron whirled as he heard the sudden cracking of broken glass behind him caused by the heavy bronze-studded boots the Redcaps favoured crushing the remains of a bottle.

"Expelli—Argh!" Ron went down as the Fey clubbed him over the head with, fortunately, the hilt of his invisible sword.

"You fools thought y-you c-could d-defeat us?" Quirrell laughed. There was something in his voice—Milo cursed his low Sense Motive bonus yet again—that seemed a little... off. Like he wasn't quite sincere, maybe. "We are—"

Frankly, Milo didn't give a damn what Quirrell was going to say. "Fly," he muttered, ripping the Amulet of Protection from Evil from around his neck. Behind him, he saw Hermione spin in surprise and start casting something, but the wand was knocked from her hand by an unseen attacker. She started to back up, but was pushed to the ground, struggling.

"WAAAAAAAGH!" Milo roared and flew towards Quirrell, knocking the Professor from his feet into the Mirror of Erised, which was made of sterner stuff than it looked. The man-sized mirror fell to the ground with a crash, and Milo and Quirrell came tumbling down on top of it. As they struggled, Milo noticed with revulsion that there was another face on Quirrell's head, normally hidden by his turban. A face with snakelike eyes and slits for a nose...

Mind on the task, he reminded himself, trying to pin Quirrell to the ground. This next task would take all of his mental ability and concentration: Grappling. First an Attack of Opportunity—which Quirrell was denied, being caught Flat-Footed by Milo's sudden attack (though Milo was fairly sure that the local wizards hadn't ever heard of AoO's, anyways). Then... what was it? A touch attack? Milo clumsily grabbed the downed wizard, an easy task—Quirrell was unarmoured and not particularly agile, while Milo had his (again, by the low standards of his competition) superior melee talents, augmented by the +2 bonus for charging. Then (Milo wracked his brain to try to remember the ridiculously complicated rules) there was, what, an opposed Grapple check? He struggled to wrap the Amulet around Quirrell's neck as the fully-grown man resisted with vastly superior strength and size, albeit inferior skill.

"Ha!" Milo gasped. "I got a 16!" His fingers struggled to work the clasp on the steel chain (the clasp which was specifically designed to be difficult to do and undo) and almost felt it click into place when Quirrell threw him off. Milo landed in a heap, astonished, as Quirrell calmly climbed to his feet.

Quirrell was holding his wand. Milo blinked, trying to process the image in front of him.

Quirrell—no, Voldemort— was holding his wand. Thirteen inches, chestnut wood, dragon heartstring core...

"...Good for curses," Quirrell murmured to himself, testing the wand.

"Pelor above and Nerull below," Milo cursed. Trying to use the amulet to cut Voldemort's influence on Quirrell was Milo's last plan...

Well, his second-last plan.

"True Strike," he muttered reaching into his extra-dimensional belt for his knife. He'd avoided this—horrific memories of his last use of the dagger flooded into his mind—but now, he had no choice. Milo threw the masterwork, cold iron dagger in an overhand arc, aimed right for Quirrell's throat.

The image of Hannah's crumpled body entered his mind's eye, but he dismissed it. It had been Voldemort's fault that Hannah had been possessed, Voldemort's fault that Milo had almost killed her with this very dagger, and Voldemort's fault that Milo was in this position once again. Dice rolled in Milo's head as he channelled all of his rage and anguish into this final, desperate throw. Twenty. Milo marvelled; even the DM seemed to be with him for once. Quirrell, and therefore Voldemort, suffered from the same weakness that Hannah had: a remarkably frail physical body. He wouldn't stand a chance.

The dagger spun gracefully in the air once, twice, thrice, guided by the unseen force of the famed True Strike spell.

Quirrell's wand arm shot upwards without even looking.

"No," the horrible face on the back of Quirrell's head murmured, and the dagger stopped in midair halfway between Milo and his target. It hovered there for a moment, then crumpled and fell.

"No..." Milo whispered weakly, his voice barely carrying to his own ears. "That's not fair... I call shenanigans..." Still, he wasn't done yet. He still had two hit points, an active Fly spell, and a belt full of tricks. Quaal, don't fail me now. All Milo had to do was fly over to Quirrell, drop the feather, and watch as the purple-clad Professor was crushed between the ceiling and a rapidly growing oak tree. He grabbed the feather-shaped token in his gloved hand and launched himself into the air, aiming for the space over the Defence Professor's head.

"Petrificus Totalus," Quirrell muttered.

Milo fell like a stone, landing painfully next to Harry, who, like Hermione, had been pinned by invisible hands.

Quirrell turned to face them—that is, he looked directly away from Harry, Milo, and Hermione, treating them with a full view of the horror on the back of his head—and began casting with game-breaking speed, Milo's amulet still clutched in his left hand.

"Petrificus Totalus, Petrificus Totalus," Harry and Hermione suddenly stopped fighting against their invisible attackers. "Finite Incantatem," all ten Redcaps—five of them critically injured from burns, two unconscious, two grappling Hermione and one grappling Harry—suddenly became visible. They looked around in surprise, clearly not counting on this unexpected turn of events. Then they began to die.

"Avada Kedavra, Avada Kedavra, Avada Kedavra..." One by one, Quirrell—Voldemort—methodically shot and killed the Fey, all the while his expression remaining neutral, almost bored. "Horrible creatures," the voice said in a strained, snakelike hiss. "Still, not quite as useless as some of the... servants... I have had to... deal with... recently..." Milo was unsure if the weird pauses in his dialogue were a dramatic affectation, or a result of his unnatural half-life. "Disappointingly, I have... guessed incorrectly... about the nature of this Mirror..." Voldemort waved his wand lazily, and the Mirror of Erised turned to dust, scattering about the room. "It being a puzzle created by that... sentimental fool... I assumed one such as him," Quirrell glanced at Harry, and for once the glimmer of emotion was visible in his snakelike eyes. In all, Milo was happier before knowing what the Dark Lord looked like when filled with barely controllable rage. "would be able to crack it... some sort of frame of mind, perhaps benevolence... or a desire to do good... Alas... but fortune... favours me again..." Voldemort paused to gasp for air. Milo wondered, briefly, how the internals, so to speak, of Quirrell and Voldemort's setup worked—where the esophagus went, and such—before deciding he didn't want to know. "It... seems that my... so-called downfall... has been delivered directly into my hands..." The tips of Voldemort's mouth bent upwards into a horrific semblance of a grin, and Milo decided that he preferred wrath to pleasure on that horrific face. "Blood of the enemy..." he murmured, though Milo wasn't sure what he meant by that. "Oh, and... Crucio." Harry screamed, straining against the bonds of his Full-Body-Bind curse. His scar started bleeding as his body was wracked with the worst pain magic could produce. Milo had once been the target of a Power Word: Pain spell, but this looked significantly worse.

"And now... young Milo... I no longer have need... of your... specialized abilities... Avada Keda—"

Click. As soon as Voldemort started casting with his right hand, Quirrell's left hand reached around his neck and snapped the Amulet of Protection from Evil into place. There was a brief moment of silence, and then Voldemort—or Quirrel—collapsed to the ground. The magical bonds trapping Milo and the others vanished.

"Did..." Harry said. "Did Voldemort just finish himself off?" Hermione, meanwhile, rushed over to check on Ron, who was blearily regaining consciousness.

"Bit anticlimactic, if you ask me," Milo said. "Still, could be some sort of trick..."

"Yeah," Harry said, climbing to his feet shakily. "Trick us into thinking that he's tricking us into thinking he's dead by offing himself. Brilliant, that is. Well, we saw through his cunning ploy. Go team."

"Mage Hand." Milo floated his wand away from Quirrell, then quickly drew his 11-foot pole (sometimes, you just need that extra foot) and prodded the body gently. There was no response. "Huh. Well, looks like we got him. Time to loot the corpses." His companions looked at him, a mix of shock and revulsion on his faces, as he patted down the Redcaps for loose change. Not finding any, he settled for pocketing their swords in his Belt of Hidden Pouches, and proceeded to the real prize: the boss.

"I think this went rather well," Milo said happily, walking over to Quirrell. "We stopped the Philosopher's Stone from being stolen, defeated the Dark Lord Voldemort once and for all—sort of? Maybe?—rescued the princess," (Milo nodded at Harry, ignoring his 'Hey!') "and we don't even need to shell out for a single True Resurrection. Not bad, all things considered. All that remains is to divvy up the loot—Holycraphe'sbreathing!"

Quirrell, it appeared, was merely unconscious—but of the face on the back of his head, there was no sign, merely a normal (but shaved) scalp. Milo reached for the amulet around Quirrell's neck, but decided against it. For all he knew, it was the only thing keeping Voldemort at bay. Still, he patted down Quirrell's pockets nevertheless. Not much, really, when it came down to it—just a few sickles, some garlic, a holy symbol... and a tattered old book.

"Hello!" Milo exclaimed, turning over the shabby, leather-bound diary. There was a faded date on the cover (Milo did some arithmetic and figured it was just over fifty years old). "What have we here? Book of evil plans? Tome of Clear Thought? Book of spells? Let's find out... Scholar's Touch." Milo paused for a second while the spell read the book in its entirety. "...Huh. It's empty. That's... unexpected. As far as treasure goes, this kind of sucks." Behind him, Ron blearily stood up.

"Maybe it really is just an old book?" Hermione suggested. "We can ask Quirrell when he wakes up. No, just wait, Ron—you really shouldn't be moving around yet."

"Can I see it?" Ron asked groggily.

"Sure," Milo said, and tossed it over to him.

Ron flipped through a few pages. "Anyone know who "T. M. Riddle is?" Seeing them all shaking their heads, Ron pocketed the book. "What?" he asked defensively. "Ginny will be starting school next year; she'll need a notebook." Ron was always very self-conscious of his family's wealth (or lack thereof) and parchment was kind of expensive (by non-PC standards, anyway), so Milo let the issue drop.

"We should probably grab the Professor and work our way backwards through the challenges," Harry suggested. "We should really tell Dumbledore about all this."

Hermione paled. "We are in so much trouble," she said. "We broke into the expressly-forbidden third-floor corridor!" she paused for a second. "And then nearly killed the Defence Against the Dark Arts professor!"

"We have an even bigger problem than that," Milo said. "How in the Nine Hells do we get out?" The black fire was still guarding the door.

They all looked at him. Milo sighed. "Fine." He proceeded to wade through the flames, grab the little black bottle, carry it out, have someone drink it and walk back, wait for it to replenish, then wade through fire again. Rinse and repeat for his three companions and Quirrell, who was still unconscious (they had to pour the bottle down his throat and hope for the best, though, to be honest, none of them much cared if he was trapped down there or not). Then again for the purple flames. The whole process took more than an hour, but, blessedly, was timeskipped.

Milo was far too distracted thinking up what to do with his new level.

o—o—o—o—o—o—o

Author's Notes: And so, the Epic Boss Fight of Climacticity +5 comes to an end. As I mentioned above, I rolled all the attack, damage, saving throw, initiative, etc. dice for this battle (using modified Redcap stats from the MMIII and Super Secret stats for Quirrellmort). I must say, I cackled somewhat at Milo's Crit, and the feeble attempts of the unarmed Redcap trying to defeat Milo's multi-layered defences.

See you next chapter for the dénouement! (Fear not, true believers—Book 2 is already in the works)

Chapter 33: Epilogue One, Rebuilding

Author's Notes: Sorry for the lateness (as usual). Term ends tomorrow, and then there's exams, but after that I'll have a lot more time to make sure updates are regular-ish, like last Spring/Summer.

In other news, my fic so far (including the two omakes, but not the author's notes) clocks in at 265 pages, font-size 11, single-spaced. It's roughly double the length of Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone.

In other other news, the first chapter of Harry Potter and the Confirmed Critical will likely be ready in two weeks. Maybe three. I want to plan ahead a little bit more in advance this time.

In other other other news, Less Wrong gave an extremely favourable review of Harry Potter and the Natural 20 on his website ( /notes/progress-13-04-01/), which I am strongly considering framing.

Milo does some fairly obscure and convoluted, but not particularly plot-relevant munchkinry in this chapter. I glossed over it in the prose, but, if you're interested, the details can be seen at the end of the epilogue.

o—o—o—o—o—o—o

"Honestly, Milo, you should be revising for History of Magic," Hermione chided as Milo stumbled into the Great Hall for breakfast. The exam was less than a fortnight away, but he'd hardly even glanced at his notes. The Hall was full of students, with the usual comforting white noise of hundreds of conversations going on in the background. For a time, the only topic of conversation was Professor Quirrell's sudden absence, which continued well after Dumbledore's announcement that he had suffered a nervous breakdown and was recuperating at St. Mungo's—which, as far as Milo could tell, was true. Dumbledore had been as close-mouthed and mysterious about it as he was about everything, however. Eventually, the Hogwarts students had found other topics to amuse themselves—Quidditch (Gryffindor had surprised everyone as the clear leader, with Ravenclaw and Slytherin competing neck-to-neck for second), the upcoming exams, Fred and George's latest hijinks (Hogwarts had awoken to find one of the legs of every chair in every classroom was shortened by a quarter of an inch; nobody could figure out how they'd done it), various Ministry scandals, the illustrious deeds of Gilderoy Lockhart, and, most recently, the death of some Death Eater bigshot at Azkaban. In short, as far as Milo was concerned, nothing of relevance.

"No time," Milo said sleepily. "It's almost done." He'd barely slept for weeks. There was too much to do: spell research, item crafting, and—most recently—a major feat of munchkinry. He'd discovered that there simply wasn't enough time in a day to do everything that had to be done, and that the only way for him to carry on without keeling over dead was with some magical assistance by way of a Dedicated Wright. These creatures, a form of Homunculus, were cat-sized magical automata created by spellcasters to help them craft items, both magical and mundane. Milo still had to provide the spells, and raw materials worth half the value of the finished product, but the Wright would do the actual crafting. This would free up eight hours a day from Milo's packed schedule for frivolous luxuries, such as sleep and adventuring. However, Milo lacked some of the prerequisites for creating the Wright, and so had to, through convoluted means, retrain a number of his class levels to Artificer from Wizard, then back again. While he was at it, he made a few modifications to his current build. Many of his abilities had been chosen under duress and with very specific needs in mind—needs that no longer existed—and he was in dire need of some streamlining.

"What is?" Neville asked, pouring an (un)healthy amount of salt onto his dinner. He seemed distracted, even by his usual standards.

"Careful with that!" Milo said. "Do you have any idea what that's worth?"

Neville stared at him blankly, utter incomprehension evident on his round face.

"Uh... sorry? What what's worth?"

"The salt! It's worth its weight in silver!" Milo was aghast that anyone would just pour it onto their food like some sort of condiment.

"I'm pretty sure you're wrong about that," Neville said, giving him a look that Hogwarts students reserved for Milo when he exclaimed 'Natural Twenty!' after a Chaser made a particularly impressive goal. "Salt's just... well, it's salt. You can get it anywhere, it's on everything, they give it out for free in tiny paper packages at restaurants. It's salt."

"Wait, you're serious?" Milo asked. "They just give it away?"

"'Course. It's just salt."

Milo blinked. Crafting magic items required a specific value of unspecified materials, so, really, anything valuable could work as long as Milo 'used it up' in the production of his gear. However, this price was measured as a gold piece value, not a galleon or Muggle currency value. Salt had a fixed price of five gold pieces per pound as far as his magic was concerned, but if the local conditions meant that he could get it for a small fraction of that...

"Ha...ha...MWAHAHAHAHAHAHAHAHAHAHAHA!"

o—o—o—o—o—o—o

Epilogue Two: Charms Final

"Abbot, Hannah!" Flitwick called from the front of the room. Hannah shot Milo, Harry, Ron, and Hermione a nervous look and walked to the front of the room, wand clenched with white knuckles. Harry and Ron, on Milo's left, looked somewhat pale and shaky, while Hermione, on his right, was rocking back and forth in her chair, her mouth moving soundlessly at a tremendous speed.

Of them, only Milo was unconcerned. Pretty much the only spell that they'd actually learned in Charms was the Hover Charm, which was, fortunately, one of the few spells that he could actually mimic. More or less. More pressing was the debate of which, if any, prestige classes Milo should adopt.

Up at the front of the room, Hannah stuttered slightly but managed, in the end, to lift the heavy textbook from the desk and hover it in the air for a few seconds before lowering it to the table. Flitwick, at the front, looked pleased, and Hannah scurried off through one of the side doors. Milo hardly noticed.

Paragnostic Apostle has dead easy requirements, Milo mused, but the benefits are so-so.

"Amastacia-Liadon, Milo!"

I'd have to be a member of the 'Paragnostic Assembly,' which doesn't exist here—or back in Azel, for that matter—but, when it comes down to it, I could probably just paint a sign on the door of my dorm that says 'WELCOME TO THE PARAGNOSTIC ASSEMBLY, NEW MEMBERS WELCOME' and ordain Mordy as the 'Exalted Philosopher of Paragnostic Truths'... fluff requirements are so irritating...

"Er... Milo?"

Master Specialist isn't bad, but the benefits don't really help me all that much. Besides, it takes Spell Focus (Conjuration). Milo had been planning to swap that out. The locals almost never failed to fail a save as it stood—it was almost as if they didn't even have Will save bonuses!

Flitwick coughed expectantly.

"Oh, right!" Milo said absentmindedly, and tried to walk out of the aisle of students.

I might just stay as a full Wizard, then, Milo decided. Mordy would chew me out if I dipped into a PrC that didn't advance Familiars, anyway. He could swap some of his bonus feats for the Domain Granted Power ability.

"Just hover the textbook," Flitwick urged gently.

"Sure, yeah, whatever." Milo lazily drew his wand and waved it around more-or-less at random. Not that the feats wouldn't come in handy, what with all the item crafting I've been doing. He still couldn't believe that he was willingly sacrificing his experience points for anything. "Wing Guardian Levitate-iosa," he said.

With all the close-quarters combat that's been happening, maybe I should take some levels of Eldritch Knight...

Milo fought down a chuckle. Theoretically, Eldritch Knight only held back spellcasting by one level—not including the level in a martial class needed to meet the prerequisites. However, this remained strictly in the hypothetical, as nobody had yet taken two levels in Eldritch Knight and lived to talk about it. The last adventurer who came close was slain by a kitten in a fair fight.

"That," Flitwick said sternly, "was the worst Hover Charm I have ever seen. Your wandwork—and footwork!—was sloppy in the extreme. Your incantation was thoroughly botched, and...and...put me down this instant!"

On the other hand... there really has been a lot of fighting. He'd have to see if there were any magic items he could make, or spells to research, to increase his combat skills without sacrificing magic.

"Right, sorry," Milo said, and dismissed Levitate. Professor Flitwick, who Milo had inadvertently lifted eight feet off the ground, fell with a crash. The textbook remained on the table, completely unmoved.

"In all my years teaching at Hogwarts, I've only twice seen such... such..." Milo winced as Flitwick drew himself up to his full (but still tiny) height, brushing dust off of his shoulders. "such an audacious display of magic from a first year student at Hogwarts!" Flitwick stretched up to Milo's ear and whispered in a conspiratorial manner, "I shouldn't be surprised, if I were you, to find that you'd received an Outstanding mark, if you catch my drift."

o—o—o—o—o—o—o

For those interested, here's how Milo made the Dedicated Wright (ECS 285):

The Dedicated Wright requires five things to create: the Craft Construct feat, Arcane Eye, Fabricate, a DC 14 Craft (Pottery) check, and a body composed of "clay, glazed with a mixture of arcane unguents and the creator's blood, and fired in a kiln."

The Craft (Pottery) check was easy, seeing as how it was DC 14 and Milo already possesses a +6 modifier to Craft from Intelligence (not even including a bonus from tools and the various spells he could have used)

The materials for the body are easy: much of anything found at Hogwarts and Diagon Alley can count as "arcane unguents." Milo used powdered mistletoe berry, belladonna, and garlic, with the reasoning that there was no reason why his Homunculus shouldn't be a remedy for Lycanthropy, a Divine Spell Focus for Druids, and immune to vampires. To make up the 100 gp cost requirement, he used Craft (Engraving) to carve a the homunculus into a work of art, resembling tiny little dwarf with the eye of Boccob on his forehead (incidentally making the Homunculus into a holy symbol—just in case). The Wright is, obviously, riddled in invisible Arcane Marks.

The tricky bit comes from the Craft Construct feat and Fabricate. The only way to get around this is retraining. Using the Philosopher's Stone dungeon as his Rebuild quest (see PHBII, 197-199), Milo swaps out his 7 of his 8 Wizard levels for Artificer. However, each dungeon run only allows him to swap 1/5 of his levels, so he simply goes back to Fluffy's room and does it again three times. He needs one level of Wizard—I'm not sure what would happen to Mordenkainen if Milo ceased being a Wizard altogether, and neither is Milo. Nothing good, to be sure. Completing the dungeon run again is no problem, as he knows which potion to drink, knows the weakness of the Devil's Snare, and can use the same set of moves as Ron did to beat the chess game every time.

As an Artificer, Milo can craft magic items without knowing the requisite spells. Fabricate is a mere third-level spell for the Trapsmith class (from Dungeonscape), so it can be easily copied. Arcane Eye, likewise.

Milo can likewise retrain one of his feats for Craft Construct

After the Wright is finished, Milo can rebuild his character back to Wizard. This all has to be finished in a short timeframe, as the Philosopher's Stone run will presumably be dismantled and lose its dungeon-status after the Stone is moved.